<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<events xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="whq-events-schema.xsd">
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-a-dead-ard-weapon" name="A Dead 'Ard Weapon">
    <flavor>These dirty but well-fashioned weapons were scavenged from who knows where. Some have crude runes or sigils cut into them, and they all look lethal.</flavor>
    <rules>Roll 1D6 to see what has been found: 1 A halberd (BE) 2 A warhammer (BDE) 3 An axe (BD) 4 A flail (BD) 5 A mace (BD 6 A sword (BDEW) Which... Croll 1D6): 1 Causes +1 Wound per Battle-level. 2 Ignores 1D6 points of Armour. 3 Gives the wielder +1 To Hit. 4 Gives the wielder +1 Attack. 5 Gives the wielder the Parry 6+ ability. 6 Causes +1D6 Wounds on a To Hit roll of 6. Now roll again. If the roll is higher than the first score to see what the weapon does, the weapon has the second ability as well and so on. Each ability adds 200 gold to the weapon's value. ROLEPLAYING GAME ONLY PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-abandoned-backpack" name="Abandoned Backpack">
    <flavor>This scruffy-looking backpack is of the kind often used by adventurers.</flavor>
    <rules>In the backpack there are 1D3 items of Dungeon Room Treasure. The Warrior who gets this card can Keep all 1D3 items for themselves, and they only count as one item for the purposes of divvying out Treasure. USE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>-</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-amulet-of-anurandel" name="Amulet of Anurandel">
    <flavor>Anurandel was a Wood Elf Sorceress, renowned for her peaceful demeanour, sunny disposition and hatred of battle. She fashioned many items to aid her followers should they be assailed by dark forces.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior invokes the power of this amulet, Monsters only hit the wearer on a natural To Hit roll of 6. After the first successful hit, the amulet's power wanes and Monsters will hit as normal. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-amulet-of-charadris" name="Amulet of Charadris">
    <flavor>Charadris was a Priest of Sigmar who abhorred magic in all its forms, believing that his faith in Sigmar was the greatest power of all.</flavor>
    <rules>Any Undead Monsters with the Regenerate ability adjacent to the Warrior wearing this amulet may only regenerate half the number of Wounds they normally would (rounded down). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-amulet-of-fury" name="Amulet of Fury">
    <rules>At the heart of this crystal amulet a magical fire rages. This amulet allows a Warrior who is not a Wizard to cast a spell. Take one of the Wizard's Starting Spell Cards at random. The Warrior may try to cast the spell once per Turn, rolling equal to or over its Casting Number on 1D6 to do so. After successful use, the amulet disintegrates. DISCARD AFTER SUCCESSFUL USE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-amulet-of-power" name="Amulet of Power">
    <flavor>This ornate amulet throbs dully, and a thick, black liquid appears to flow within its core.</flavor>
    <rules>At the start of each Warriors' Phase the bearer may roll 1D6. If the score is a 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, they get +2 Strength for the rest of the Turn. If the score is a 1, the amulet explodes causing 1D6 Wounds to the bearer, with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. LASTS UNTIL EXPLODES</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-amulet-of-vindication" name="Amulet of Vindication">
    <flavor>This antiquated porcelain amulet is covered in a layer of cracked and peeling black leather.</flavor>
    <rules>This amulet allows the Warrior to counter hostile magic. Each time a spell is cast against the bearer of the amulet, roll 1D6. On a score 6 the spell has no effect on them (RPG: A Warrior wearing this amulet gains the Magic Resistance 6+ ability). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ancient-manuscript" name="Ancient Manuscript">
    <flavor>These ancient documents are faded and somewhat fragile.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who reads these documents must roll 1D6 to see what they reveal: 1 A recipe for Halfling pie. 2 A very old letter from a noble, worth 10 gold. 3 A musical masterpiece from a famous bard, worth 25 gold. 4 Battleplans from ages past, worth 50 gold. 5 A religious text, worth 100 gold. 6 A Treasure Map that leads to 500 gold! (RPG: The Warrior must add two extra weeks of travel to a Settlement after which they uncover the gold.) DISCARD AFTER SALE OR USE</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ancient-vase-of-lustria" name="Ancient Vase of Lustria">
    <flavor>Lustria is a land of the unknown, the undiscovered continent, a realm of Giants and Daemons and powers beyond all telling.</flavor>
    <rules>This vase is of strange design, unsuitable for use by Humans, Elves or Dwarfs. Its purpose can only be guessed at, as can its age, but its beauty and value is beyond question. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>175G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-arkal-s-powder" name="Arkal's Powder">
    <flavor>This silver dust swirls in its casket as if shifted by an unseen finger.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who consumes this powder has their movement increased. They may immediately move another 3D6 squares, and automatically Escape from Pinning. Arkal's Powder may be consumed at any time. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-armour-of-fortune" name="Armour of Fortune">
    <flavor>This armour gleams in a rainbow of never-ending array of carnage and war.</flavor>
    <rules>This armour can absorb Wounds inflicted on the Warrior. Once donned, the armour cannot be removed. It can absorb a total of 30 Wounds, then explodes, taking the wearer to zero Wounds (and death if no healing is possible). LASTS UNTIL EXPLODES</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-arrow-of-slaying" name="Arrow of Slaying">
    <flavor>A thick black liquid drips ominously from the end of this arrow. The magical venom on this arrow can fell even the toughest monster.</flavor>
    <rules>If this arrow hits a Monster, roll 1D6. On a score of 1, 2 or 3 the arrow causes normal Damage. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the Monster is immediately slain. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-arrows-of-death" name="Arrows of Death">
    <flavor>The shafts of these jet-black arrows are encrusted with golden runes and their tips glow with a pale green light.</flavor>
    <rules>These enchanted arrows are magically sharpened and cause +3 Wounds when they hit. There are 1D6 Arrows of Death. Each arrow can only be used once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>100G each</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-arrows-of-piercing" name="Arrows of Piercing">
    <flavor>These magically sharpened white arrows are able to pierce the toughest armour at a thousand paces.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using these arrows must roll 1D6 after each successful hit. On a score of 5 or 6 (6 if the Armour is magical) the arrow ignores the target's Armour when determining Damage. There are enough arrows to last one Adventure. LASTS FOR ONE ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-arrows-of-sure-flight" name="Arrows of Sure Flight">
    <flavor>These arrows were skillfully crafted by the Wood Elves of Athel</flavor>
    <rules>Loren. Arrows of Sure Flight may only be used to their full effect by an Elf. When used by any other Warrior treat them as normal arrows. An Elf using these arrows gets +1 To Hit. There are 2D6 arrows. Each arrow can only be used once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>100G each</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-axe-of-damnation" name="Axe of Damnation">
    <flavor>This axe retains a drop of blood from every foe the wielder has defeated.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this axe gets +1 Attack. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-axe-of-retribution" name="Axe of Retribution">
    <flavor>This axe of Dwarf origin was created to punish foes for crimes they have committed.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this axe gets +1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>175G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-axe-of-slaughter" name="Axe of Slaughter">
    <flavor>This axe was forged by the Dwarf Runesmith Garvan</flavor>
    <rules>Surehammer, who honed its blade to an impossible sharpness. This axe causes +1D6 Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-backpack" name="Backpack">
    <flavor>This rugged backpack is of the kind favoured by those who venture into dangerous places.</flavor>
    <rules>The Backpack contains 1D6 sets of Provisions. Each set of Provisions restores 2 Wounds. (RPG: At the end of each Adventure, any remaining provisions in the Backpack are lost. However, at the start of the next Adventure, the Backpack will have magically replenished itself, and will contain 1D6 Provisions again!) 1D6 PROVISIONS PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bag-of-gold" name="Bag of Gold">
    <flavor>This decaying bag is tied with a leather thong. Inside of it is a number of gold pieces.</flavor>
    <rules>The bag contains 1D6x25 gold. RECORD THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x25G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-band-of-magic" name="Band of Magic">
    <flavor>This slender gold band glitters with a clear light.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior finds this ring, randomly select two Attack Spells (RPG: randomly select two Attack spells with Casting Numbers that are equivalent to the Warrior's Battle-level). These two spells are stored in the magic band. Each Spell may be cast once, automatically, whenever the wearer wishes. When both spells have been cast, the magic power of the band has been used up and it crumbles to dust. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bandages" name="Bandages">
    <flavor>Simple battlefield bandages used by dungeon adventurers.</flavor>
    <rules>Each bandage restores 3 Wounds. Use once then discard.</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bane-scroll-of-the-undead" name="Bane Scroll of the Undead">
    <flavor>This tattered old scroll bears the seal of a renowned Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Lord. Reading aloud the words on this scroll will kill any single Undead creature worth up to 400 gold on a dice roll of 4, 5 or 6. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bauble-of-anurandel" name="Bauble of Anurandel">
    <flavor>Anurandel was a Wood Elf Sorceress of Loren, renowned for her soft voice, peaceful demeanour and hatred of battle.</flavor>
    <rules>This innocuous looking bauble is in fact an item of great power. This bauble flashes with energy and its bearer may add +1 to all dice rolls to Escape from Pinning. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-beasthelm" name="Beasthelm">
    <flavor>Smoke incessantly curls from the hollows of this helm.</flavor>
    <rules>The Beasthelm protects the wearer from only the most powerful blows. Any Damage Dice that scores a natural 6 against the wearer of the helm causes only half the Damage G.e. 3 Wounds instead of 6). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-belt-of-valour" name="Belt of Valour">
    <flavor>This belt is adorned with the ferocious face of a lion, flanked by glowing runes of power.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who dons this belt must roll 1D6 at the beginning of each Turn to see what the belt confers: 1 -1 Strength and -1 Toughness. 2-3 +1 Strength 45 +1 Toughness 6 +1 Strength and +1 Toughness The belt cannot be removed for the rest of the Turn. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-belt-of-the-beastmaster" name="Belt of the Beastmaster">
    <flavor>The head of a vicious wolf glows on the front of this belt.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time a group of Monsters who all attack a single Warrior (RPG: Monsters who have the Gang Up ability) appear on the same Board Section as the wearer of this belt, roll 1D6. If the score is a 3, 4 or 5, the beasts attack the Warriors using the rule of One-On-One instead. If the score is a 6, the beasts attack each other in the first round of Combat instead, after which they attack the Warriors using the Rule of One-On-One. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-berserker-sword" name="Berserker Sword">
    <flavor>This brutal weapon appears to be crudely fashioned from a dull iron-like metal, and has sinister-looking runes engraved upon its hilt.</flavor>
    <rules>When used by the Barbarian, this sword adds +1 to the dice roll to see if he becomes Berserk. When used by other Warriors, this sword has no magical effect. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-berserkers-brew" name="Berserkers Brew">
    <flavor>The liquid in this bottle burns the Warrior's throat, and they experience an uncontrollable desire to kill their enemies.</flavor>
    <rules>When drunk, this potion lasts for an entire Combat. Each Turn, before they fight, the Warrior must roll 1D6, adding +1 to the score for every slain Monster on their Adventure Record Sheet. If the total score is 6 or more, the Warrior goes Berserk until the Combat is over. While Berserk, they get +1 Attack. If they roll a 1, however, the Warrior is so wild that all they do this Turn is slash about, causing 1 Wound to every adjacent Warrior. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-biting-blade" name="Biting Blade">
    <flavor>This sword has been magically sharpened to a razor-fine edge and is capable of biting through steel as if it were paper.</flavor>
    <rules>This sword ignores all non-magical Armour (and up to 2 points of Magical Armour) when rolling for Damage. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bitter-wind-crossbow" name="Bitter Wind Crossbow">
    <rules>Any bolt placed into this crossbows turns freezing cold. This crossbow is Strength 4 and any quarrel fired from it is considered magical. When using this crossbow a Warrior gets +1 To Hit and ignores up to 2 points of non-magical Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>DW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-black-desert-amulet" name="Black Desert Amulet">
    <flavor>This artefact was used by an Arabyan Knight in the 1000 year long 'War of Death'. The power of the amulet can be invoked against one Monster each Turn.</flavor>
    <rules>That Monster suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. The power of the amulet will regenerate after one use when there are no Monsters on the Board. If used twice without having regenerated, however, the amulet disintegrates after the second use and must be discarded. LASTS UNTIL DISINTEGRATES</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-couronne" name="Blade of Couronne">
    <flavor>This is the blade that the master swordsmiths of Bretonnia forged to defeat an undead Liche-king many centuries past.</flavor>
    <rules>Each Undead Monster in a square adjacent to a Warrior wielding this sword automatically suffers 1 Wound at the end of each Turn, after any Regeneration, with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-leaping-copper" name="Blade of Leaping Copper">
    <flavor>This sword seems to have a life of its own, striking in a blurred arc of slicing metal.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this sword gets +1 Attack. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-sea-gold" name="Blade of Sea Gold">
    <flavor>Forged from gold taken from the depths of the sea when the world was young, this blade is covered in runes so ancient and worn that they can no longer be read.</flavor>
    <rules>This sword ignores 1 point Armour when determining Damage. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-slicing" name="Blade of Slicing">
    <flavor>This sword moans softly as it is drawn from its scabbard, in eager anticipation of the blood it is about to spill.</flavor>
    <rules>This sword causes +2 Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bladed-boots" name="Bladed Boots">
    <flavor>These unusual boots have stiletto blades concealed in the toes.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is wearing these boots, they gain a special Kick Attack which suffers -1 To Hit but is resolved at +1 Strength. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blessed-gem" name="Blessed Gem">
    <flavor>This huge ruby has been empowered with warding spells engraved into it by the wizards of the Empire.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Turn, the Blessed Gem can be used to dispel a Necromantic spell. When the spell is cast, roll 1D6. On a roll of 4, 5 or 6 the spell has no effect. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blessed-sword" name="Blessed Sword">
    <flavor>Cooled in the water of the Temple of Ulric, this sword is a powerful weapon of purity.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this sword, they only miss their opponent if their To Hit roll is a 1 or 2. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blessed-water" name="Blessed Water">
    <flavor>The Blessed Water can be used to heal, exorcise evil spirits and banish Undead.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks some Blessed Water has 1D6 Wounds restored. If the result is a 1, however, it means that the Blessed Water has run out; discard it. The water can also be thrown as a missile weapon. Any Daemonic or Undead creatures hit suffer 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. If a Warrior throws the Blessed Water, it must be discarded. DISCARD ON A ROLL OF 1</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bloodblade-scroll" name="Bloodblade Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior's sword glows as a thick red liquid coagulates on the blade.</flavor>
    <rules>Roll 1D6 for each Monster adjacent to the Warrior bearing the scroll. On a score of 5 or 6 that Monster suffers 1 Wound with no modifiers for anything. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bloodletting-sword" name="Bloodletting Sword">
    <flavor>This dark blade glows with an internal pulse.</flavor>
    <rules>The sword drinks the blood of its victims, causing +1D6 Wounds every time it hits. However, if the wielder rolls a 1 To Hit, the blade takes the energy it needs from the Warrior instead causing 1D3 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bloodpulse-scroll" name="Bloodpulse Scroll">
    <flavor>A dull throbbing fills the room as it becomes suffused with a red glow.</flavor>
    <rules>The Warrior bearing the scroll immediately has 1D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-blur-scroll" name="Blur Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior's outline shimmers and becomes an indistinct, hazy blur that is continually changing.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Warrior on the Board. All Attacks made against the chosen Warrior suffer -1 To Hit for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bograt-s-krown" name="Bograt's Krown">
    <flavor>Faded runes are inscribed upon the pitted surface of this grubby looking circlet of rusted iron.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this crown gets +1 Toughness. Bograt's Krown can be worn at the same time as a helmet. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bone-blade" name="Bone Blade">
    <flavor>This magical blade is made from a bleached white substance that looks like bone, but is as sharp as steel.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use this sword once per Adventure. If their Attack hits, the sword causes + 1D6 Wounds. (RPG: For one Turn per Adventure, the Warrior may trade in all their normal Attacks and use this sword to make a single Attack that causes normal Damage + (1D6 per Battle-level) extra Wounds.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bone-of-turgit" name="Bone of Turgit">
    <flavor>Turgit was as seemingly unstoppable Chaos Lord finally defeated by a group of Empire Battle Wizards who simultaneously cast their spells on him. The result was so powerful that the magic became fused into his bones.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use this bone by rolling 1D6. If the score is a 6, every Chaos creature adjacent to the Warrior suffers 1 Wound (RPG: per Battle-level) with no modifiers for anything. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-book-of-magic-distortion" name="Book of Magic Distortion">
    <flavor>This book contains powerful incantations that manipulate the</flavor>
    <rules>Winds of Magic. The Wizard may use this book just after the Power Phase has been rolled in an attempt to change the amount of Power that is available to him this Turn. Roll 1D6. The result is now the amount of Power that he has for the Turn. Note that this does not change the Power Phase. If the Power Phase roll was a 1, an Uneventful Event still occurs (RPG: and the Wizard may not add his Battle-level to the result). USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-book-of-prowess" name="Book of Prowess">
    <flavor>The pages of this book are initially blinding to the eyes. Eventually the light dims and the book can be read.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who reads this book may add +1 to their Weapon Skill Characteristic permanently. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-anurandel" name="Boots of Anurandel">
    <flavor>Anurandel was a Wood Elf Sorceress, renowned for her peaceful demeanour, sunny disposition and hatred of battle.</flavor>
    <rules>She fashioned many items to aid her followers should they be assailed by dark forces. These boots give the wearer the ability to dodge missile fire. Whenever a Warrior wearing these boots is attacked with a missile weapon, roll 1D6. On a score of 6 the attack misses. (RPG: The boots give the Warrior the Dodge 6+ ability against missile fire.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-barging" name="Boots of Barging">
    <flavor>The steel toes of these leather boots are emblazoned with a Magic rune in the shape of a key.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing these boots may attempt to kick open any closed door by rolling 1D6. If the result is a 5 or 6 66 if the door is magically locked), the door opens. Only one attempt may be made per door and any traps on the door are set off as normal. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-battle" name="Boots of Battle">
    <flavor>These sturdy iron-shod boots are magically made to be an exact fit for whoever wears them.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing these boots gets +1 Weapon Skill and +1 Ballistic Skill. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-leaping" name="Boots of Leaping">
    <flavor>These boots are fashioned from the tough leather of a Wyvern's wings.</flavor>
    <rules>These boots allow the Warrior to leap 1 square in any direction as part of their Movement, landing in the square beyond. Any obstacle in the square being leaped is ignored, though it still counts as 1 square of Movement. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-quargskin" name="Boots of Quargskin">
    <flavor>These boots are made of a strange, soft leather.</flavor>
    <rules>One per Adventure the Warrior wearing these boots gets +2 Movement for one Turn. (RPG: If the Warrior tries to sell these boots, no self-respecting trader will take them seriously and as such they cannot be sold.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>0G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-swiftness" name="Boots of Swiftness">
    <flavor>These dusty boots are made of a strange material. When worn, the world seems to blur and slow down.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing the Boots of Swiftness a Warrior gets +1 Movement. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-tzchak" name="Boots of Tzchak">
    <flavor>This long dead sorcerer Baalga the All-Seeing created these boots to enable his long suffering henchman Tzchak to walk long distances carrying immensely heavy loads.</flavor>
    <rules>These boots allow the wearer to ignore any Armour-based Movement penalties. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bow-of-tiranoc" name="Bow of Tiranoc">
    <flavor>This mighty bow was crafted by the Elves of Tiranoc from a single Starwood branch.</flavor>
    <rules>When the land of Tiranoc was engulfed by the sea, the bow was carried to the Old World, a fabled treasure of a fallen kingdom. This bow is Strength 2 and causes +3 Wounds. It may be fired twice per Turn. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bow-of-tor-alessi" name="Bow of Tor Alessi">
    <flavor>This white bow was captured by the Dwarfs at the fall of the</flavor>
    <rules>Elf city of Tor Alessi. Its accuracy is beyond compare, and it was considered a prize worthy of the bloodshed and slaughter that won it. This bow is Strength 4 and, rather than having to move then attack as usual, the wielder may fire it before, during or after their Movement instead. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bracelet-of-ashain" name="Bracelet of Ashain">
    <flavor>This slim golden band fits comfortably around the wearer's forearm, even on top of armour.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this bracelet gets +3 Starting Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bracelet-of-transformation" name="Bracelet of Transformation">
    <flavor>This plain bronze bracelet has a single rune embossed on its surface.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who dons this bracelet may take on the appearance (and only the appearance) of any creature. While transformed, the Warrior will not be attacked and may automatically Escape from Pinning as long as they do not initiate combat. As soon as the Warrior attacks a target in any way the bracelet's effects wear off. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bronze-sigil-sword" name="Bronze Sigil Sword">
    <flavor>The runes on this blade shimmer in the light. It is exceptionally light and well-balanced in the hand.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this sword gets +2 Initiative. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bugman-s-xxxxxx" name="Bugman's XXXXXX">
    <flavor>This sturdy wooden barrel bears the mark of the great Dwarf</flavor>
    <rules>Master Brewer Josef Bugman. This is a barrel of the fabled Bugman's XXXXXX beer! There is enough beer for four drinks. If a Warrior takes a drink of the beer, they have 1D6 Wounds restored, but they suffer - 3 To Hit for the next 1D3 Turns. Every drink still left in the barrel is worth 50 gold. DISCARD WHEN ALL DRUNK</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-bull-horn" name="Bull Horn">
    <flavor>This horn was removed from a ferocious Minotaur and then fashioned into an instrument. Imbued with a strange magic, the horn seems to invigorate those who hear it.</flavor>
    <rules>When this horn is blown, each Warrior on the Board gets +1D3 Strength. The effect lasts until a 1 or 2 is rolled in the Power Phase. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-candle-of-lost-souls" name="Candle of Lost Souls">
    <flavor>Smoke rises from the bottom of this candle like spirits searching for something they cannot seem to find.</flavor>
    <rules>Once lit, this candle will illuminate the Board Section the bearer is on, just like the leader with the Lantern. It is not bright enough to be used to Explore through a Doorway. If the bearer of the candle flees the Dungeon, they do not need to roll on the Escaping the Dungeon Table. LASTS FOR ONE ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-captain-s-cutlass" name="Captain's Cutlass">
    <flavor>The point of this curved blade gleams with a viciousness that only a dirty, rotten sea scoundrel could appreciate.</flavor>
    <rules>A cutlass is more effective when used with finesse rather than brute strength. A Warrior wielding this sword adds their Weapon Skill to the Damage rather than their Strength. In addition, this magical cutlass causes +1D6 Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-carnival-of-death-scroll" name="Carnival of Death Scroll">
    <flavor>Overcome by an unreasoning madness, the Monsters leap towards each other in a berserk killing frenzy, completely ignoring the Warriors.</flavor>
    <rules>Roll 1D6 for every Monster on the same Board Section as the bearer of the scroll. On a score of 5 or 6 that Monster moves towards the nearest Monster and attacks it this Turn instead of the Warriors. If there is any confusion about which Monsters are attacked, the bearer of the scroll decides. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-casket-of-sorcery" name="Casket of Sorcery">
    <flavor>This golden casket emits a soft hum which continuously raises and lowers in pitch.</flavor>
    <rules>If they do nothing else this Turn, the Warrior bearing this casket may attempt to use it to capture a single spell of their choice from an adjacent enemy spellcaster. Roll 1D6. If the score is a 4, 5 or 6, the casket absorbs the spell and prevents the spellcaster from casting it again. (RPG: If the destroyed spell is rolled on a Monster's Spell Table when determining which spell it casts, roll again.) The Warrior may automatically cast the captured spell once during Combat. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cataclysm-scroll" name="Cataclysm Scroll">
    <flavor>Moaning in anguish, the Warrior spreads their arms as an area of blackness takes shape around their foes.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any 2 square by 2 square area on the same Board Section as the bearer of the scroll. Every Monster in the chosen area suffers 1D6 Wounds, with no modifiers for anything. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-chalice-of-fate" name="Chalice of Fate">
    <flavor>The Chalice of Fate has the power to warp time, to change fate, and to alter reality.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use the Chalice of Fate to re-roll the Power Phase roll. They may only re-roll once, and must accept the result of the second roll even if the score is worse. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-chalice-of-vigour" name="Chalice of Vigour">
    <flavor>This chalice is one of the legendary artefacts created by the</flavor>
    <rules>Priest King Alcadizzar. Much sought after by Witch Hunters, the chalice is filled with a golden liquid, which never dims or dries up. During Combat the Warriors may inhale the pungent vapours that rise from the bubbling golden liquid. For the duration of the Combat, on a roll of 6 To Hit, the Warriors will cause +1D3 Wounds. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-chalk" name="Chalk">
    <flavor>Inside a small pouch is a modest amount of chalk, the kind that adventurers take into maze-like dungeons.</flavor>
    <rules>This chalk allows a Warrior to mark an escape route out of the Dungeon. The Warrior does not need to roll on the Escaping the Dungeon Table should they wish to leave the Dungeon. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>0G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-chaos-bane" name="Chaos Bane">
    <flavor>This innocuous gourd is filled with a foul-smelling paste.</flavor>
    <rules>A weapon that has been smeared with this paste causes +1 Wound (RPG: +1 Wound per Battle-level) against Chaos creatures it hits. There is enough of the bane to coat one weapon for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-charm-of-learning" name="Charm of Learning">
    <flavor>Donning this charm brings everything into sudden clarity.</flavor>
    <rules>This beautiful charm is worth 100 gold. (RPG: This charm allows a Warrior to assimilate the knowledge required for training very quickly indeed. It costs them 300 less gold (per Battle-level) than usual to train to the next Battle- level.) USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-charm-of-prosperity" name="Charm of Prosperity">
    <rules>The bearer of this charm becomes very lucky indeed! Anytime the bearer of this charm finds gold whilst adventuring in the Dungeon, they discover an extra 1D6x10 gold hidden in the area. (RPG: In addition, whenever the bearer of this charm participates in gambling or other games of chance, they may add +1 to their score.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-chest-of-gold" name="Chest of Gold">
    <flavor>A chest filled with sparkling gold coins is a welcome sight to any</flavor>
    <rules>Warrior. The chest contains 1D6x100 gold. RECORD THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-circlet-of-repanse" name="Circlet of Repanse">
    <flavor>Repanse de Lyonesse was a Bretonnian Paladin famous for her assault on an invading Chaos army.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this crown gets +1 Strength The Circlet of Repanse cannot be worn with a helmet. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-circlet-of-wrath" name="Circlet of Wrath">
    <flavor>This band of silvered, luminescent metal, worn around the forehead, glistens and gleams with an unnatural light. This circlet allows the wearer to enter a destructive blood rage.</flavor>
    <rules>Upon entering this state the Warrior doubles their regular Attack Characteristic for one Turn and must roll 1D6. On a score of 1 the enraged Warrior must move towards the nearest Warrior and attack them instead. While in this state the Warrior may automatically Escape from Pinning. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-anadon" name="Cloak of Anadon">
    <flavor>This cloak is made from a fabric that seems impossible to tear.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears this cloak gets +1 Toughness. However, if any Damage Dice from an opponent scores a natural 6, the cloak ceases to provide any more benefit (RPG: until the beginning of the next Adventure). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-deception" name="Cloak of Deception">
    <flavor>This cloak swirls around the Warrior as they move, deceiving the eye as to their precise location, and causing their opponents to become ensnared in its all enveloping folds.</flavor>
    <rules>All Attacks against the Warrior wearing this cloak suffer -1 To Hit. If an attacker scores a 6 To Hit, however, the power of the cloak is exhausted (RPG: until the next Adventure). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-invisibility" name="Cloak of Invisibility">
    <flavor>This cloak catches the light in a very strange manner, becoming transparent in places as if it were full of holes.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this cloak the Warrior becomes invisible and therefore cannot be attacked. They may fight as normal. The cloak contains enough power to keep the Warrior invisible for one Turn per Adventure. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-loren" name="Cloak of Loren">
    <flavor>This cloak is made of a fine, silk-like material that, although extremely light, is very, very strong.</flavor>
    <rules>Every time a Warrior is hit while wearing this cloak, they can ignore the first Wound caused by the blow. However, each time the cloak absorbs Damage like this, roll 1D6. On a score of 1 the cloak rips and is useless. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-stealth" name="Cloak of Stealth">
    <flavor>This cloak is made of an odd material that is slippery to the touch.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is wearing this cloak they may automatically Escape from Pinning once per Adventure. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-the-woods" name="Cloak of the Woods">
    <flavor>This magical cloak is woven with leaves, animal hide and bird feathers.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears the cloak to jump up into the air for one Turn before slowly settling back to the ground. While in the air, the Warrior may not engage in hand-to-hand Combat but any missile Attacks they make get +1 To hit, while any missile attacks against them suffer -1 To Hit. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-confuse-scroll" name="Confuse Scroll">
    <flavor>The scroll bears the words for the Confuse spell. The arcane words create confusing images around the Monster's head, and it stumbles around befuddled.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Monster on the same Board Section as the Warrior bearing the scroll. That Monster suffers -1 Attack this Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-coughing-spell-jewel" name="Coughing Spell Jewel">
    <flavor>This jewel contains the power of the Coughing spell. When used, the Warrior's opponent suddenly bursts out in a hacking cough of such violence that they look as if they may drop their weapon.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Monster on the same Board Section as the Warrior with the jewel and roll 1D6. On a score of 6 the target succumbs to a coughing spasm and suffers -1 To Hit for the rest of the Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-create-bridge-scroll" name="Create Bridge Scroll">
    <flavor>Solid rock leaps from the Warrior's outstretched fingertips, building a bridge across the room.</flavor>
    <rules>When cast, this spell allows the bearer to create a magical bridge 1 square wide across any pit, hole or chasm. The bridge remains in place until a 1 is rolled in the Power Phase, at which point it suddenly disappears. Any models on the bridge at that time plummet into whatever the bridge was crossing. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-crown-of-madness" name="Crown of Madness">
    <flavor>This crown pitches the wearer into a world of insane lunacy.</flavor>
    <rules>This valuable gold crown is worth 250 gold. (RPG: Cackling and giggling to themselves at their own macabre jokes, the Warrior wearing the crown finds the death and carnage in the Dungeon most amusing. They now get +1 to all psychology based tests such as Fear and Terror.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-crown-of-night" name="Crown of Night">
    <flavor>This jet black crown is fashioned from bands of iron and engraved with powerful runes that crackle and spit with an incandescent blue light.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time a spell is cast against the Warrior wearing this crown, roll 1D6. On a score of 6 the spell has no effect on them (RPG: the crown gives the wearer the Magic Resistance 6+ ability.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-crown-of-rebellion" name="Crown of Rebellion">
    <flavor>This crown was worn by Rhag Hellroar who became a great</flavor>
    <rules>Norse Chieftain. The wearer of this enchanted crown gets +1 Attack and +1 To Hit. If any of their To Hit rolls score a natural 1, however, the wearer may not make any offensive actions during the next Turn, and gets +2 Toughness instead. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-crown-of-winter" name="Crown of Winter">
    <flavor>This magical crown was created long ago by an Ice Witch of Kislev and is said to contain some of her magical power.</flavor>
    <rules>When the wearer invokes the power of the crown, for one Turn all Attacks made by the wearer cause +3 Wounds and the weapon they are using is treated as magical. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-cure-small-wounds-scroll" name="Cure Small Wounds Scroll">
    <flavor>This scroll bears the words for the Cure Light Wounds spell.</flavor>
    <rules>When the Warrior uses the scroll, pick any Warrior on the Board and roll 1D6. On a score of 6 the spell restores 1 of their Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>15G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-daemon-statuette" name="Daemon Statuette">
    <flavor>The life-like features on this small figurine are _ quite disconcerting.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may toss this magical figurine into the air during Combat, where it will grow in size and hover above the Monsters. In the next Monster's Phase every Monster on the Board will attack the figurine instead of the Warriors. The figure can absorb a total of 20 Wounds before it is destroyed and the Monsters' attention turns back to the Warriors. If it survives the Combat, it may be used, but note how many Wounds it has left to absorb. LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dagger-of-treachery" name="Dagger of Treachery">
    <flavor>This dagger imbeds itself in the target, refusing to be removed.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may attempt to plunge this dagger into any adjacent Monster at any time by rolling 1D6: 1 The Warrior accidentally stabs an adjacent Warrior (determined at random) who suffers 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. 2-5 The Monster suffers 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. 6 The Monster suffers 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. At the start of each Turn thereafter the Monster suffers 1D3 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. The dagger may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. USE ONCE PER COMBAT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dart-of-suffering" name="Dart of Suffering">
    <flavor>Tucked within a velvet sheath, this small dart is more than it seems... In addition to any other attacks they may have, a Warrior may throw this dart as a missile weapon with a Range of 6 squares. The Warrior suffers -1 To Hit if the target is 4 squares away, -2 if the target is 5 squares away, and -3 If the target is 6 squares away.</flavor>
    <rules>If it hits, the dart causes 1D6 Damage with no modifiers for anything. The dart painfully embeds itself into the Monster and the creature suffers -1 To Hit for the rest of the Combat. The dart may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. USE ONCE PER COMBAT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-darting-steel-daggers" name="Darting Steel Daggers">
    <flavor>These two daggers of purest steel were forged in the time of the High Elves. Ancient sigils bind powerful spells of destruction to their blades.</flavor>
    <rules>While using the Darting Steel Daggers a Warrior gets +1 Attack and each Attack made with the daggers automatically hits. However, each hit will only cause 1D6 Wounds, with no modifiers for Strength. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dazzle-scroll" name="Dazzle Scroll">
    <flavor>A blurring screen of energy shoots towards the target, engulfing it in a maze of glittering colours.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the bearer of the scroll may pick any Monster on the board. For this Turn, all hand-to-hand Attacks made against the Monster only miss on a natural To Hit roll of 1. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-deathstone" name="Deathstone">
    <flavor>The Deathstone is a small black crystal that seems to soak up the light from the lantern, converting it into raw power.</flavor>
    <rules>The Deathstone acts as a source of Power for the Wizard. When casting a spell, he may use the Deathstone to increase his chance of success. Roll 1D6. On a 3, 4, 5 or 6, the spell may be cast at a cost of zero Power instead of its normal cost. On a 1 or 2, the spell fails and all the Wizard's Power for the Turn is lost. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-deathsword" name="Deathsword">
    <flavor>This sword's power is such that it cannot really be controlled and would soon overwhelm whoever carried it.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this sword may increase their Strength to 10 for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-destroy-magic-scroll" name="Destroy Magic Scroll">
    <flavor>This piece of crisp white parchment rustles and crackles, silver lettering shifting across the page.</flavor>
    <rules>This scroll allows the bearer to automatically dispel any one spell cast against them or their companions. That spell has no effect. (RPG: The spell is also destroyed, preventing the caster from ever casting it again. If a destroyed spell is rolled on a Monster's Spell Table when determining which spell it casts, roll again.) USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dispel-magic-scroll" name="Dispel Magic Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior bearing the scroll raises their hand and shouts the words of warding, diffusing their opponent's magic.</flavor>
    <rules>The Dispel Magic scroll may be used to attempt to dispel another spell that has just been cast. Roll 1D6. If the score is 4, 5 or 6 that spell has no effect. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dome-of-power-scroll" name="Dome of Power Scroll">
    <flavor>White power streams from the eyes of the Warrior bearing the scroll, forming a protective dome around the Warriors.</flavor>
    <rules>This scroll allows the bearer to protect up to 4 squares of the Board with an impenetrable magic shield for one Turn. The squares must be linked together, but the dome can be of any shape. Models inside the dome may not move, take offensive action or cast any other magic, but are immune to all forms of attack. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-doomsday-flail" name="Doomsday Flail">
    <flavor>A heavy stone, carved in the shape of a ferocious beast, rests at the end of this flail.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this flail, they get +2 Strength. If the wielder's To Hit roll is a natural 6, the flail causes Double Damage. If the wielder has a Weapon Skill less than 5 (including items, special abilities, etc.) and rolls a 1 To Hit, they hit themselves causing normal Damage. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-door-spikes" name="Door Spikes">
    <flavor>These durable iron spikes are the kind used to wedge doors shut. A spike keeps a door closed for one Turn. To use a spike, a Warrior must be adjacent to a door. Once spiked, a door cannot be opened unless it is broken down. For someone to break down a door, they must be adjacent to it.</flavor>
    <rules>Roll 1D6 and add their Strength. If the total is 9 or more, the door is broken down. There are 1D6 spikes. Each spike can be used once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>10G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dragon-shield" name="Dragon Shield">
    <flavor>This shield is fashioned from the deep-red, sulphurous scales of a Great Fire Dragon.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior bearing this shield gets +1 Toughness. Once per Adventure they may use the shield to ignore all of the effects from any one attack, whatever its origin. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dragonflame-rod" name="Dragonflame Rod">
    <flavor>A fire suddenly erupts from the end of this rod, scorching all who come in contact with it. The rod may be used at any time against one Monster adjacent to the bearer. It causes 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. (RPG: If used against a Mummy, the creature is also set alight.</flavor>
    <rules>AT the start of each Monsters' Phase thereafter the Mummy suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. If the roll is a 1 when determining Damage, the fire goes out and the Mummy suffers no more fire Damage. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dragonhelm" name="Dragonhelm">
    <flavor>This ancient Elven helm is inscribed with a glowing rune of fire.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is wearing this helmet they get +1 Toughness (RPG: or +2 Toughness against any fire-based attacks). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-drop-scroll" name="Drop Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior mutters the words on the scroll and gestures towards the ground, causing the target's grip on its weapon to fail.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Monster on the same Board Section as the bearer of the scroll. The target drops any one object they are holding. The Monster may do nothing for one Turn as they retrieve it. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dungeon-map" name="Dungeon Map">
    <flavor>This tightly sealed wooden tube protects a valuable parchment. The tube contains an ancient map of a Dungeon. From looking at the map, the Warriors can see that there is a secret door leading out of one of the rooms.</flavor>
    <rules>On the next new Board Section that the Warriors enter, place an extra Doorway on one of the free walls. Through the Doorway is a single Dungeon Room. When the Warriors enter the room, take 2 Event Cards. Once the Events are completed, the Warriors gain two items of Dungeon Room Treasure in addition to any they gain for completing the Eents. USE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>10G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dwarf-pick" name="Dwarf Pick">
    <flavor>This old but serviceable pick looks like the ones used by Dwarf miners.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use the pick to dig their way through a cave-in. It takes 1D6 Turns to clear a way through the rubble. After each successful use, roll 1D6. On a roll of 1 the pick breaks and must be discarded. LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>125G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-dwarf-warhammer" name="Dwarf Warhammer">
    <flavor>This Dwarf warhammer glows with a pale blue light.</flavor>
    <rules>This magical Warhammer causes +1 Wound. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-elf-waybread" name="Elf Waybread">
    <flavor>This nutritious, delicious, cake-like food is what Elves take with them on long journeys. There are 1D6 pieces of Elf Waybread. Each cake restores 1 Wound to the Warrior who eats it.</flavor>
    <rules>At the end of each Adventure, roll 1D6 for each piece of Waybread. If the score is a 1, that piece has spoiled and must be discarded. DISCARD WHEN ALL EATEN</rules>
    <goldValue>5G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-eltharion-s-bow" name="Eltharion's Bow">
    <flavor>This bow is enchanted with Elf magic that makes it much more accurate.</flavor>
    <rules>This bow is Strength 4. While a Warrior is using this bow, they get +1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-emperor-s-noose" name="Emperor's Noose">
    <flavor>This enchanted rope was commissioned by a long-dead Emperor from far-off Nippon to assassinate his foes. It was also the instrument of his death...</flavor>
    <rules>The bearer may direct this rope to strangle any Monster on the Board. Roll 1D6. If the score is 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, the Monster suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. If the score is a 1, the rope attacks the Warrior instead! At the beginning of each Turn thereafter, roll 1D6. If the total is equal to or greater than the victim's Strength, they suffer another 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. If the total is less than the target's Strength, they manage to free themselves. USE ONCE PER COMBAT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-enchanted-garlic" name="Enchanted Garlic">
    <flavor>The Fay Enchantress of Bretonnia placed a spell upon this bulb of garlic to help a Bretonnian Knight in his battle against a monstrous Vampire.</flavor>
    <rules>Any Vampire attacking a Warrior bearing this garlic suffers -1 To Hit. (RPG: At the end of each Adventure, roll 1D6. If the score is a 1, then the enchantment has worn off and the garlic must be discarded.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-enchanted-shield" name="Enchanted Shield">
    <flavor>This magic shield expands and swells whenever the bearer is being assaulted.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior bearing this shield gets +1 Toughness. Each time the bearer is hit they may use it to try and absorb the blow. Roll 1D6. On a5 or 6, the shield absorbs all the Damage. On a roll of 1, the shield explodes and the Warrior takes 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. LASTS UNTIL EXPLODES</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-energy-jewel" name="Energy Jewel">
    <flavor>This glowing jewel, set in a silver clasp, stores powerful magic.</flavor>
    <rules>This jewel contains 6 points of Power that the Wizard can use in the same way as his Power Tokens. Place a D6 on top of this card to show the jewel's current Power. Once all the points are used up it is useless and worthless. It cannot be recharged. The jewel is worth 50 ogld per unused point of Power. DISCARD WHEN DRAINED</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ensorcelled-blade" name="Ensorcelled Blade">
    <flavor>This blade of pure iron was tempered to the sound of arcane incantations in ages past. This weapon's magic guides the wielder's hand, making it easier to strike foes.</flavor>
    <rules>While using the Ensorcelled Blade, a Warrior gets +1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-exotic-foods-of-tilea" name="Exotic Foods of Tilea">
    <flavor>These exquisite sweetmeats from Tilea are preserved in tightly sealed stone containers.</flavor>
    <rules>These foodstuffs are a rare delicacy, and are worth 50 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-extra-spikey-shoulder-pad" name="Extra Spikey Shoulder Pad">
    <flavor>This shoulder pad once belonged to the late, great Blood Bowl</flavor>
    <rules>Star Player Bozark 'The Boz' Bile-Belly. This piece of Blood Bowl memorabilia is worth 300 gold. If worn by an Ex-Blood Bowl Player, it causes +2 Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fanged-death-helm" name="Fanged Death Helm">
    <flavor>This helm is fashioned into the likeness of the gaping maw of a ravenous beast.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this helm gets +1 Toughness. In addition, they may nominate one of their Attacks each Turn. If that Attack hits, then the Warrior gains an extra bite attack from the helm which hits the same target automatically, doing 1D6 Damage with no modifiers for anything. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-feathers-of-ind" name="Feathers of Ind">
    <flavor>In the Kingdoms of Ind, strange land of fabulous temples, dwell some of the most exotic beasts in the world.</flavor>
    <rules>These are the feathers of mystical birds from Ind, the Land of a Thousand Gods. There are 1D3 sets of feathers and each set is worth 1D6x10 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x10G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-festival-treats" name="Festival Treats">
    <flavor>This drawstring bag is filled with colourful treats.</flavor>
    <rules>Festival Treats can be eaten at any time but they are very hard and durable so each time a Warrior (except a Dwarf) tries to eat one, they must roll 1D6. If the score is 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, the Warrior has 1 Wound restored. If the score is a 1, the Warrior painfully breaks a tooth on the treats and suffers 1 Wound instead. There are 2D6 treats and each is worth 10 gold. DISCARD WHEN ALL EATEN</rules>
    <goldValue>10G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fine-clothes" name="Fine Clothes">
    <flavor>These well preserved clothes would not look out of place in the wardrobe of a royal household.</flavor>
    <rules>Having been carefully stored, these fine clothes are made of silk and inlaid with gold and jewels. There are 1D6 items, and each is worth 1D6x25 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x25G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fine-elf-wine" name="Fine Elf Wine">
    <flavor>Connoisseurs throughout the Old World speak with reverence of the exquisite wines made by Elves. There are 1D6 bottles of wine, and each is worth 100 gold.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior drinks a bottle of wine, they have 1D3 Wounds restored but suffer -1 To Hit for the next 1D3 Turns. DISCARD AFTER USE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-finger-of-doom-scroll" name="Finger of Doom Scroll">
    <flavor>This dusty scroll contains magical sigils that are traced in a spidery scrawl. It is the Finger of Doom spell - ancient and powerful magic.</flavor>
    <rules>While he has this scroll, the Wizard may take the Finger of Doom Spell Card and use it just like any of his other spells. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-finger-of-life-scroll" name="Finger of Life Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior points at one of their companions and a thin stream of blue energy pours from their fingertips, revitalising them.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Warrior on the Board and roll 1D6. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the chosen Warrior has that many Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fire-arrows" name="Fire Arrows">
    <flavor>These regular arrows have been doused in oil and can be easily lit before firing.</flavor>
    <rules>If these arrows hit, roll 1D6. If the score is a 4, 5 or 6, the target is set alight and suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. The Damage continues each Turn until the Damage roll comes up a natural 1 or 2 and the fire goes out, causing no more Wounds in subsequent Turns. There are 1D6+3 Fire Arrows. Each arrow can only be used once. DISCARD AFTER ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>5G each</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fire-brew" name="Fire Brew">
    <flavor>This vial contains a pale red liquid that sparkles as it catches the light. It is the harsh and fiery liquid used by Orcs to heal their wounds. This is supposed to be a healing potion and holds enough liquid for four doses. Each unused dose is worth 100 gold. Whenever a Warrior takes a drink of the potion roll 1D6: 1 The potion tastes awful, and does no good at all other than induce a fit of vomiting!</flavor>
    <rules>2-4 The potion tastes pretty bad, searing the gullet, but quickly restores 1D6 Wounds. 5-6 The burning brew restores 1D6+1 Wounds (RPG: +1 Wound per Battle-level). DISCARD WHEN ALL DRUNK</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-firebomb" name="Firebomb">
    <flavor>From the rune inscribed on it, the fuse jutting out of the top, and its pungent smell, this large, spiked ball can only be a firebomb.</flavor>
    <rules>The Firebomb may be thrown at any time and affects an area 2 squares by 2 squares. Any model in the area suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-firebombs" name="Firebombs">
    <flavor>Prising the skull-marked lid off a wooden box, the Warriors uncover a stash of firebombs!</flavor>
    <rules>A Firebomb may be thrown at any time, and affects an area 2 squares by 2 squares. Any model in the area suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. There are 1D6 Firebombs and each Firebomb can only be used once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>75G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fist-of-iron-scroll" name="Fist of Iron Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior conjures up a huge iron-mailed fist and sends it hurtling towards their opponent.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Monster up to 6 squares away from the bearer of the scroll and roll 1D6. If the score is equal to or greater than the range of the target, it suffers 1D6+1 (RPG: 1D6+Battle-level Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>175G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flail-of-skulls" name="Flail of Skulls">
    <rules>At the end of each chain on this flail is a gnashing, biting, chattering skull! A Warrior using this flail gets +1 To Hit. Once per Adventure one of the Warrior's Attacks causes Triple Damage. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flail-of-the-chimera" name="Flail of the Chimera">
    <flavor>This flail was used by a Bretonnian Knight in his battle against an army of Chaos.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this Flail gets +1 Strength. In addition, the Warrior may nominate one of their regular Attacks each Turn. If that Attack hits with a natural 6, treat it as 1D3 separate hits. Roll the Damage for each hit separately. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flash-powder" name="Flash Powder">
    <flavor>This small, sturdy bag contains some notoriously volatile flash powder.</flavor>
    <rules>The Flash Powder may be set off at any time to confuse the Warriors' enemies. After it has exploded, any Warriors who have not yet fought this Turn get +1 Attack. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flask-of-inferno" name="Flask of Inferno">
    <flavor>A volatile, magical fire rages inside of this thick flask. This flask may be thrown into any square, where it explodes into a ball of fire. Roll 1D3. The score indicates how many D6 Damage are inflicted on the model in the square, with no modifiers for Armour. The score is also the number of squares in every direction that the ball of fire expands to. The fire dissipates outward, with each square away from the centre taking a D6 less Damage than the previous, with no modifiers for Armour.</flavor>
    <rules>See diagrams below: Aad IP 186/100) D205 208 108 Sieur Deas.. mle oe ae 'Pe! pa aegis 2D6 36 ees xs fe (D6, 1D6\&lt;)) BS. 2D6 2D6/1DG} a pete &quot;a wes a pet 3 1D6 Damage 2D6 Damage 3D6 Damage 1 square 2 squares 3 squares USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flask-of-poison" name="Flask of Poison">
    <flavor>The label on this red-tinted bottle is unreadable and the liquid within swirls mysteriously.</flavor>
    <rules>Any arrows or bladed weapons coated in this poison cause +2 Wounds on the next successful hit. There is enough poison for 1D6 applications, each of which last 1 Turn. Each unused application is worth 50 gold. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fleet-of-foot-scroll" name="Fleet of Foot Scroll">
    <flavor>This scroll bears the words for the Fleet of Foot spell. When cast, the bearer of this scroll feels light and swift</flavor>
    <rules>Upon using this scroll the Warrior gets +1 Movement for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>25G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flesh-worm-scroll" name="Flesh Worm Scroll">
    <flavor>The scroll bears the words for a Flesh Worm spell. When cast, a small glowing worm appears, hurls itself at a Monster and burrows into its flesh.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick a Monster on the same Board Section as the Warrior with the scroll. The Monster is attacked by a Flesh Worm and suffers 1 Wound with no modifiers for anything. At the start of every Turn thereafter, roll 1D6. On a score of 1, 2, 3 or 4 the Flesh Worm dies. On a score of 5 or 6 it continues to feed and the victim suffers another 1 Wound. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flute-of-fate" name="Flute of Fate">
    <flavor>This enchanted white flute was carved from a branch of the rare white oaks of Loren.</flavor>
    <rules>When blown, the flute allows all of the Warriors on the same Board Section to re-roll one of their dice rolls this Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>EW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-flying-trousers" name="Flying Trousers">
    <flavor>These yellow-stripped trousers are decorated with magical glowing runes.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears these trousers can fly for one Turn. While airborne, they can fly over all obstacles and automatically Escape from Pinning. Anyone who attacks them suffer -1 To Hit. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-freeze-scroll" name="Freeze Scroll">
    <flavor>A freezing wind swirls through the room, chilling the Monsters to the bone yet leaving the Warriors unharmed.</flavor>
    <rules>Roll 1D6. The number shows two things: 1 The number of Monsters who may be affected by this spell. 2 The amount of Wounds each Monster affected suffers, with no modifiers for anything. The targets of this spell must be on the same Board Section as the bearer of the scroll. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-freezing-death-spell-jewel" name="Freezing Death Spell Jewel">
    <flavor>This jewel is carved of ice that never melts and is freezing to the touch.</flavor>
    <rules>When its power is invoked, it releases a lethal blast of icy shards at the Warrior's foes. This jewel may be used to cast the Freezing Death spell. The bearer makes an attack roll as if using a missile weapon. On a successful hit roll 1D6 to work out the jewel's Damage. If the score is a 1, the jewel causes 1D6 Wounds. If the score is a 2, the jewel causes 2D6 Wounds, on so on. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fungus-brew" name="Fungus Brew">
    <flavor>The slimy green potion in this flask turns Night Goblins into gibbering Fanatics.</flavor>
    <rules>There is enough liquid in the flask for four doses. A Warrior can take a drink at any time during Combat. Roll 1D6 to see what happens: 1-2 The brew makes the Warrior hallucinate! They immediately make an attack against every model adjacent to them. 3-4 The brew restores 1D6 Wounds. 5-6 The brew restores 1D6 Wounds and the Warrior may ignore the Damage from the next blow they take. The brew is worth 200 gold if none of it has been drunk, or 100 gold if some of it (but not all of it!) has been consumed. DISCARD WHEN ALL DRUNK</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-fur-cloak" name="Fur Cloak">
    <flavor>Rolled up and placed over one arm, this thick fur cloak offers some protection in place of shield.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior uses this cloak instead of a Shield, they get +1 Toughness. Each time the Warrior wearing the cloak is hit, roll 1D6. If the roll is a 4, 5 or 6 it remains effective and can be used again. If the roll is a 1, 2 or 3 it is ruined and must be discarded. LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-gavel-of-judgment" name="Gavel of Judgment">
    <flavor>Carried long ago by the Witch Hunter Hernando Hellman, this magic item was used to subdue evil-doers so that they could be brought back to stand trial for their crimes.</flavor>
    <rules>This gavel may be thrown as a missile weapon but the Warrior throwing suffers -1 To Hit. Anything struck by the gavel is rendered unconscious for the next 1D3 Turns. If the To Hit roll is a natural 1, however, the gavel mysteriously vanishes (discard it). Further attacks against an unconscious target only miss ona To Hit roll of 1. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-gem-of-passage" name="Gem of Passage">
    <flavor>The Gem of Passage was wrought many centuries ago by the Dwarfs. It aided them in building their underground empire and can be used to control the very rocks that make up the ceiling and floor of the dungeon.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior invokes its power, the Gem of Passage opens up a hole in one of the walls. Place another Doorway on the Board Section the Warrior occupies. Beyond this Doorway will be 1D6+3 more Dungeon Cards which the Warriors can explore as normal. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-gem-of-selection" name="Gem of Selection">
    <flavor>This gem was crafted by a clever Halfling who always seemed to avoid being selected for perilous errands outside the Moot.</flavor>
    <rules>If the rules require a Warrior to be randomly determined for any reason, the bearer of this gem may decide which Warrior is selected instead. The first time the gem is used, turn this card upside-down; when it Is used a second time, flip this card over. USE TWICE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ghost-powder" name="Ghost Powder">
    <flavor>Every component in this powder was blessed by a priest of Sigmar and then enchanted by a wizard.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use this powder to coat one of their weapons. In the first Turn when it is applied, the weapon causes +2D6 Wounds against any Undead. During the second Turn, it causes +1D6 Wounds. In the third Turn it causes +1D3 Wounds, after which the effects wear off. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-giant-slayer" name="Giant Slayer">
    <flavor>This massive sword may only be wielded with both hands and even then it takes a mighty Warrior to use it effectively.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this two-handed sword they get +3 Strength. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-glittering-robe-scroll" name="Glittering Robe Scroll">
    <flavor>The scroll bears the words for the Glittering Robe spell. The</flavor>
    <rules>Warrior bearing the scroll creates a robe of magical energy that shimmers and glitters about them as they move. This spell creates a cloak of magical energy around the bearer, which absorbs the next 1D6 Wounds they would suffer, after which it fades away. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-globe-of-detection" name="Globe of Detection">
    <flavor>The Globe of Detection allows the Warrior's vision to pierce the solid rock of the dungeon walls.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior with this globe can easily find hidden passages. When the Warrior rolls on the Hidden Passages Table, they mad add +1 to their roll. However, if the Warrior rolls a 1, then that result stands and the Warrior will suffer the 'Collapse!' result. USE ONCE PER TURN GLORY! SCROLL (DEW) The Warrior bearing the scroll sends out tendrils of force that pierce the hearts of the Warriors, filling them with great valour and courage beyond measure. All of the Warriors are suddenly enthused with great bravery and each gets +1 Attack this Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-glory-scroll" name="Glory! Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior bearing the scroll sends out tendrils of force that pierce the hearts of the Warriors, filling them with great valour and courage beyond measure.</flavor>
    <rules>All of the Warriors are suddenly enthused with great bravery and each gets +1 Attack this Turn. Use once then discard.</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-glowstone" name="Glowstone">
    <flavor>This small crystal orb holds the light of the dawn, giving off the same light as the Lantern.</flavor>
    <rules>Once activated, the orb glows brightly and the bearer can explore in the same manner as the leader with the Lantern. How long the Glowstone will last is unknown, however, and if the Power Phase roll is a 1, roll a further 1D6. On a score of 1, 2 or 3 the glow dies and the Glowstone is useless and worthless. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-goblet-of-vitality" name="Goblet of Vitality">
    <flavor>This goblet is suffused in a brilliant golden aura which expands to fill the area, flooding it with bright light.</flavor>
    <rules>When the power of this cup is used, each Warrior on the Board Section has 3 Wounds restored. &lt;&lt; USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-grey-armour-of-eshkalon" name="Grey Armour of Eshkalon">
    <flavor>This dull grey armour is made of a flaky, stone-like substance and is extremely resilient.</flavor>
    <rules>Whenever a Warrior wearing this armour is hit by an Attack, roll 1D6. On a score of 1 the armour shatters and is useless and worthless. On a 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6 the armour absorbs that many Wounds. LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-grim-mace" name="Grim Mace">
    <flavor>This mace seeks the death of those around it.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this mace they get +1 Strength. Once per Adventure, if a Warrior forgoes all of the regular Attacks this Turn, every adjacent model (friend or foe) suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-grimstone" name="Grimstone">
    <flavor>The age-pitted surface of this ancient stone hides the power to drain the life energy of others and transfer it to its wearer.</flavor>
    <rules>Upon invoking the Grimstone choose any other Warrior in the party. The bearer now has the same number of Wounds as the Warrior, while they now have the number of Wounds the bearer had. In effect, their Wounds are swapped. The Grimstone may never be used to take a Warrior above their Starting Wounds, which remain as they were. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-grudgehammer" name="Grudgehammer">
    <flavor>This magical hammer was constructed to help settle grievous offences against Dwarfs.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this weapon, they may re-roll the first Attack that misses each Turn. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-grulmak-s-axe" name="Grulmak's Axe">
    <flavor>This black-bladed axe exudes a poisonous, corrosive slime. It is rumoured to be the axe stolen from Chaos Warlord Grulmak Deathmonger by the - notorious' Hobgoblin Scragface Throatslasher.</flavor>
    <rules>This axe ignores 3 points of Armour, and spatters acid everywhere. At the end of the Warriors' Phase, every model adjacent to the wielder suffers 1 Wound with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. However, every time the wielder rolls a 1 To Hit, they are struck by the acid themselves and suffer 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-halo-of-vengeance-scroll" name="Halo of Vengeance Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior bearing the scroll casts a glowing halo around themselves.</flavor>
    <rules>This spell surrounds the Warrior with a protective shield. At the start of each Turn roll 1D6. The result is the number of Attacks that can be absorbed by the halo this Turn. Ignore all of the Damage from those attacks. The halo remains until the bearer moves or a 1 is rolled on the dice to see how many Attacks are absorbed. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hammer-of-deliverance" name="Hammer of Deliverance">
    <flavor>This magical hammer was forged by a devoted follower of Morr, the God of the Dead.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this hammer causes Double Damage if their To Hit roll is a natural 6. In addition, both the wielder, and any Monster hit by the hammer (even if it causes no Damage), can only restore half the number of Wounds from any healing that they receive this Turn. (RPG: nor can they use the Regenerate ability if they have it this Turn.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hammer-of-hargon" name="Hammer of Hargon">
    <flavor>This sturdy Dwarf warhammer has an ornate icon carved on its head. Any Dwarf in the party recognises this as the lost Hammer of Hargon.</flavor>
    <rules>When using this hammer a Warrior may roll as many dice for Damage as they like. Add up the total, then add the Warrior's Strength to the final score. However, if any of the dice come up with a 1 or 2, the hammer causes no Damage at all. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hammer-of-scorching" name="Hammer of Scorching">
    <flavor>The face of this hammer is so hot, that it heats up any surface it touches. This hammer causes +1D6 Wounds.</flavor>
    <rules>If the target is wearing non-magical Armour, however, the hammer causes +2D6 Wounds instead. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-harbinger-staff" name="Harbinger Staff">
    <flavor>This staff calls out warnings during combat, alerting the wielder to incoming attacks.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this staff gets +3 Toughness. (RPG: The staff is cumbersome in combat, however, and the Warrior suffers -1 Attack to a minimum of 1. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-healing-hands-jewel" name="Healing Hands Jewel">
    <flavor>This jewel contains the power for the Healing Hands spell. When used, the Warriors feel a soothing calmness descend upon them.</flavor>
    <rules>When the power of this jewel is used, every Warrior on the Board has 1 Wound restored. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-healing-potion" name="Healing Potion">
    <flavor>Inside this tightly sealed glass jar is a small quantity of a liquid that can only be a healing potion.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion has 1D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-healing-salve" name="Healing Salve">
    <flavor>Although ominous in appearance, the thick, yellow paste contained within this black bottle is a salve of healing.</flavor>
    <rules>The healing salve can restore 2D6 Wounds to any single Warrior, or 1D6 Wounds to each of 2 different Warriors. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-heartbeat-scroll" name="Heartbeat Scroll">
    <flavor>As the Warrior utters the words on this scroll, power surges through the target's body and their heart beats with renewed Vigour.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Warrior on the Board. That Warrior has 2D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-heartseeker" name="Heartseeker">
    <flavor>This sword has the ability to warp time, guiding its own destiny to the benefit of whoever wields it in battle.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Turn, while a Warrior is using this sword, they may re- roll any one of their Attacks that misses. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hell-mace" name="Hell Mace">
    <flavor>Sparks fly from the iron-shod head of this mace as it is wielded, bathing the area in light.</flavor>
    <rules>While using the Hell Mace a Warrior gets +2 Attacks. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hellbeast-scroll" name="Hellbeast Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior assumes the aspect of a daemonic creature.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the Warrior bearing this scroll gets 1 Attack, +1 To Hit, causes +2 Wounds and cannot use a weapon. (APG: In addition, they are immune to all psychological effects such as Fear or Terror, for one Turn). USE ONCE THEN DSICARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-helm-of-absorption" name="Helm of Absorption">
    <flavor>This helm protects the wearer against the arcane arts.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears this helm gets +1 Toughness. In addition, they may attempt to absorb any spell cast on them by rolling 1D6. If the score is a 2+, the helm absorbs the spell and the Warrior suffers no effects. If successful, the next time the Warrior uses the helm to absorb a spell they need a 3+ and so on. This continues up to 6+, after which the cycle starts all over again. If the score is ever a 1, the helm explodes and the Warrior suffers 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hidden-alcove" name="Hidden Alcove">
    <flavor>After a thorough search, one of the Warriors finds a secret panel which opens, revealing a hidden alcove. To see what the alcove contains, the Warrior may roll as many dice as they like. If any score a 1 they have found nothing, and managed to make a lot of noise - take an Event card immediately. If any come up with a 2, 3, 4, or 5, the Warrior gains gold equal to the total of those dice multiplied by 10. For each dice that scores a 6, they receive an item of Dungeon Room Treasure.</flavor>
    <rules>USE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-holy-artefact" name="Holy Artefact">
    <flavor>This ornate artefact obviously belongs to one of the temples of the Empire.</flavor>
    <rules>At the end of the Adventure roll 1D6 to see whether you find a temple. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 you find a temple and sell the artefact for 1D6x100 gold. (RPG: You may find a temple in any Settlement. If you roll a 1 when seeing how much gold you receive, then you actually get nothing - it is not an artefact they recognise. You will have to try again in the next Settlement you come to.) DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-holy-water" name="Holy Water">
    <flavor>A glass phial of glowing water like this is an ideal tool in the arsenal of many Witch Hunters.</flavor>
    <rules>This phial can be thrown as a missile weapon. It causes 1D6 Wounds to any Daemonic, Undead or Chaotic creatures hit. It also causes 1D3 Wounds to any such creatures adjacent to the target, with no modifiers for anything. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-horn-of-animosity" name="Horn of Animosity">
    <flavor>Blowing this horn produces an aggressive, guttural sound.</flavor>
    <rules>When blown, roll 1D6 for each group of Monsters on the Board (a group being defined as all those Monsters of the same type e.g. Orcs or Skaven). On a score of 4, 5 or 6 that group of Monsters attacks another group of Monsters this Turn (determine randomly) rather than the Warriors. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-horn-of-dominion" name="Horn of Dominion">
    <flavor>This Norse horn produces a highly unnerving chord.</flavor>
    <rules>When blown, all of the Warrior on the Board get +1 Strength for one Turn. (RPG: In addition, all of the Monsters on the same Board Section who are carrying a Rider become disorientated and suffer -1 Attack for one Turn. This does not affect the Rider, however, who may attack as normal.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-horn-of-panic" name="Horn of Panic">
    <flavor>This jewel-encrusted silver horn has ancient runes engraved upon it.</flavor>
    <rules>When the horn is blown, roll 1D6 for every group of Monsters on the Board (a group being defined as all those Monsters of the same type e.g. Orcs or Skaven). On a score of 6, that particular group flees the battle. The Warriors do not receive any gold for Monsters that flee. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-horn-of-resilience" name="Horn of Resilience">
    <flavor>This brass horn is said to originate in the Kingdoms of Ind.</flavor>
    <rules>When blown, the magical power of this horn allows any Warrior on the Board to enter a hypnotic trance and heal themselves if they choose. The horn may only be used if there are no Monsters on the Board. Entering the trance takes one full Turn, during which the Warrior may do nothing else. At the end of the Turn each Warrior who entered the trance has 1D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-horn-of-shielding" name="Horn of Shielding">
    <flavor>This large rusty warhorn shows signs of having been carried in many a battle.</flavor>
    <rules>When blown, the mystical power of the horn places a magical shield around each Warrior, cloaking them in a _ near impenetrable cowl of raw magic. The Warriors can only be hit by Monsters scoring a natural 6 To Hit. The effects of the horn last for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-hounds-of-grimnair-icon" name="Hounds of Grimnair Icon">
    <flavor>The air is filled with an eerie howling and incorporeal shadows hurl themselves at the Warrior's foes.</flavor>
    <rules>The stone allows a Warrior to summon 1D3 Hounds of Grimnair. The Warrior may choose which Monster each Hound attacks and it doesn't matter if there are any open squares next to target as the Hounds are immaterial beasts. A Hound attacks its target each Turn. It hits on a D6 roll of 6 and causes 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. If a 1 or 2 is rolled for the Hound's Attack or its target is killed, the Hound vanishes. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ice-shield-of-jana" name="Ice Shield of Jana">
    <flavor>This magical shield was carried by Norse Barbarian Jana the Unforgiving and helped protect her tribe from a rampaging Fire Dragon. Icy crystals protrude from the surface of this shield generating a soft mist around it.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this shield they get +1 Toughness (RPG: or they get +2 Toughness against fire-based Attacks). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ice-tomb-scroll" name="Ice Tomb Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior's chill breath fills the room, coalescing around a single Monster and encasing it in a solid tomb of ice. Pick any Monster within the bearer's Line of Sight and roll 1D6.</flavor>
    <rules>If the score exceeds the target's Toughness, it is encased ina sarcophagus of ice and may not move or fight. While entombed, target cannot be attacked. Roll 1D6 at the beginning of each Monsters' Phase. If the score is less than or equal to the target's Toughness, it frees itself. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-icon-of-agility" name="Icon of Agility">
    <flavor>This sturdy jewelled icon twists and turns in the hand of its bearer.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, this icon allows the Warrior to add +1 to their roll to Escape from Pinning. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-icon-of-combat" name="Icon of Combat">
    <flavor>This redstone icon is chillingly cold to the touch.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the icon allows the bearer to shove a Monster out of their way. Roll 1D6 and add the Warrior's Strength. If the total is greater than the Monster's Strength it is pushed back into any one of the three squares behind it that is unoccupied. Having pushed their foe back, the Warrior moves into the square that was occupied by the Monster and may now make their normal Attacks. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-icon-of-determination" name="Icon of Determination">
    <flavor>This small jewelled icon gleams with a cold light. This small icon may be placed upon a shield, melding itself permanently with the surface.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Adventure, this icon allows the Warrior to ignore the Damage from a single blow. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-icon-of-direction" name="Icon of Direction">
    <flavor>This icon gives the Warrior an impressive sense of direction even in the depths of the darkest dungeon.</flavor>
    <rules>If the Warrior bearing this icon flees the Dungeon, they may make two rolls on the Escaping the Dungeon Table and choose the best result. In addition, if the bearer is the leader with Lantern and an Event (RPG: or Travelling Hazard) indicates they are lost, roll 1D6. If the score is a 3, 4, 5 or 6, they may ignore it. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-icon-of-obliteration" name="Icon of Obliteration">
    <flavor>This jeweled icon radiates great destructive energy.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use this icon once per Turn to attempt to destroy one item carried by an adjacent Monster. Roll 1D6. If the score is a 5 or 6, the item is destroyed. The icon lasts until used successfully or until the Warrior rolls a 1 when attemping to use it, both of which render the icon useless and worthless. LASTS UNTIL USED SUCCESSFULLY OR UNTIL A 1 IS ROLLED</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-incense-of-healing" name="Incense of Healing">
    <flavor>This small, decorative urn is covered with magical symbols and runes.</flavor>
    <rules>When opened, the urn discharges a fragrant cloud of vapour that acts as a healing potion. Every Warrior on the same Board Section as the urn has 2D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-invisibility-scroll" name="Invisibility Scroll">
    <flavor>With a shimmer of light, the Warrior's outline slowly fades until they are completely invisible.</flavor>
    <rules>This spell allows the Warrior bearing the scroll to become invisible for one Turn. While invisible the Warrior may automatically Escape from Pinning and carry out any action except attack an opponent: moving, healing, etc. are therefore valid actions, while firing a bow, pushing a Monster into a pit, casting offensive spells, etc. are not. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-iron-skin-scroll" name="Iron Skin Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior bearing the scroll is protected by a magical second skin created by the Iron Skin spell.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the Warrior with the scroll gets +2 Toughness for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-javelin" name="Javelin">
    <flavor>Bearing magical sigils this slender silver javelin glitters in the darkness.</flavor>
    <rules>This javelin may be thrown as a Strength 4 missile weapon. If the target is successfully hit, and is standing directly in front of, and adjacent to, a wall, roll an extra 1D6 after rolling for Damage. On a score of 5 or 6 the javelin causes normal Damage and pins the target to the wall. A pinned creature may do nothing for the rest of the Turn as it struggles to free itself. The javelin can be retrieved at the end of the Combat. USE ONCE PER COMBAT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-jong-s-magic-cards" name="Jong's Magic Cards">
    <flavor>Huayi Jong was a sorcerer from Cathay often sought out for his arcane abilities. He invented these cards for his amusement, often demanding that an employer draw one as part the contract for his services.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who finds these cards feels compelled to draw one immediately (RPG: and at the beginning of each Adventure). Roll 1D6 to see what effect the magic card has on the Warrior: 1 -1D3 Starting Wounds 2 -1 Strength 3 +1 Weapon Skill 4 +1 Strength 5 +1 Toughness 6 +1 Attack The effect lasts until the end of the Adventure. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-jugglers-clubs" name="Jugglers Clubs">
    <flavor>These surprisingly heavy juggling clubs hide a potent secret. There are 1D6 juggling clubs filled with explosive black powder.</flavor>
    <rules>Each club can be thrown at any time at an enemy within the Warrior's Line of Sight where it may explode upon impact. Once thrown, roll 1D6 for the Monster and if the score is a 5 or 6, the club remains intact and the Monster immediately throws it back at the Warrior! In that case, roll 1D6 for the Warrior with the same rules listed above. This process continues until either the Warrior or the Monster rolls a 1, 2, 3 or 4, whereupon the club explodes causing 2D6 Wounds. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>50G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-kill-krazy-total-brew" name="Kill Krazy Total Brew">
    <flavor>Steam rises from the frothy surface of this foul-smelling liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>Any Dwarf will recognise it with grudging respect as the product of the Orc Kill Krazy Brew Boyz. No sane Warrior would contemplate drinking the brew, but if they did... There is enough brew for four drinks and each unused drink is worth 125 gold. If a Warrior drinks, roll 1D6: 1 Dead! The Warrior's head explodes in a colourful and noisy fashion. 2 Mindless! The Warrior falls to the floor, fluid leaking from their ears. They ignore all Damage from blows they take for 1D6 Turns, but may do nothing at all. 3 Zonked! The Warrior staggers around in an uncontrolled fashion. Until a 4, 5 or 6 is rolled in the Power Phase, the Warrior may do nothing except wander along blearily behind the others. If attacked, they are at Weapon Skill 1. 4-5 Fortified! The coarse liquor fires up the Warrior's blood, invigorating them whilst stripping the skin off the roof of their mouth. They have 2D6 Wounds restored, but may not talk for the next 1D6 Turns. 6 The Warrior gurgles mindlessly for a moment as the brew reorganizes their internal organs, then a feeling of new-found strength washes over them. They have 1D6 Wounds restored, their Weapon Skill is permanently reduced by -1, but they cause an extra dice of Damage every time they hit. DISCARD WHEN ALL DRUNK</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-kingshield-of-tilea" name="Kingshield of Tilea">
    <flavor>King Esteban of Estalia won a famous battle against the Undead of Lahmia, and attributed his legendary invulnerability to the shield he bore. Its past is shrouded in mystery, but the kings of Tilea have always carried it into battle.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior bearing this shield gets +1 Toughness. In addition, the bearer may ignore all the effects from any one Attack made against them, whatever its origin. PERMANENT/USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lava-boots" name="Lava Boots">
    <flavor>These unconventional boots glow like molten lava.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is wearing these boots, they gain a special Fire Stomp Attack which causes Wounds as normal with no modifiers for Armour. However, the boots are cumbersome and so the wearer suffers -1 Movement. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lesser-antidote" name="Lesser Antidote">
    <flavor>The liquid in this small bottle is thin like water and has a floral aroma.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion has 1D3 Wounds restored. (RPG: In addition, a Warrior who drink this antidote has 1 point restored to any one Characteristic that had previously been reduced for any reason. This potion cannot restore Wounds that have been permanently reduced.) USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-levitate-scroll" name="Levitate Scroll">
    <flavor>A crackling sound fills the room as the Warrior raises themselves aloft on a column of coruscating power.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior uses this scroll, pick any Warrior on the Board. For one Turn the target levitates. A levitating Warrior can only be attacked with missile weapons or spells. They cannot move, however, and may not fight in hand-to-hand Combat. Their square remains impassable, just as if they were standing in it normally. They may levitate out of a pit. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lifebringer-scroll" name="Lifebringer Scroll">
    <flavor>Blazing fire leaps from the Warrior's eyes, striking the Warriors and bathing them in a corona of energy that closes their wounds. Pick any number of Warriors on the Board, including the Warrior bearing the scroll. Roll 1D6 for each Warrior chosen. Each Warrior has that number of wounds restored.</flavor>
    <rules>If any two or more of the dice rolled come up with the same number, the spell fails and none of the Warriors have any Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lifestealer-talisman" name="Lifestealer Talisman">
    <flavor>This skull-headed talisman is imbued with the properties of the dreaded Lifestealer spell. The Warrior with the talisman can steal Wounds from a nearby Monster to heal themselves.</flavor>
    <rules>The bearer may choose one adjacent Monster who immediately suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. The bearer then has the same number of Wounds restored. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lifestone" name="Lifestone">
    <flavor>The Lifestone has the power to drain the life energy of others and transfer it to its wearer.</flavor>
    <rules>Upon invoking the Lifestone choose any other Warrior on the Board. The bearer now has the same number of Wounds as that Warrior, while they now have the number of Wounds the bearer had. In effect, their Wounds are swapped. The Lifestone may never be used to take a Warrior above their Starting Wounds, which remain as they were. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-light-of-courage" name="Light of Courage">
    <flavor>This phial is filled with a glowing white liquid which lights the way in the darkness just as the Lantern does.</flavor>
    <rules>Once this phial is opened, the bearer can use it to explore just as if they carried the Lantern. The power of the phial will be exhausted after one Adventure, or if the Warrior carrying the phial is reduced to zero Wounds. LASTS FOR ONE ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lightning-bolt-scroll" name="Lightning Bolt Scroll">
    <flavor>Raw power arcs across the Warrior's fingertips and a bolt of white energy streaks from their eyes toward their opponent.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior uses this scroll, any single Monster in the bearer's Line of Sight immediately suffers 2D6 Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lightning-fire-ring" name="Lightning Fire Ring">
    <flavor>As soon as this ring is slipped over a finger, it shrinks slightly to fit, and a lightning rune starts to glow coldly on its upper surface.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing the Lightning Fire Ring can fire a bolt of lightning at any Monster within their Line of Sight. The bolt hits automatically and causes 5D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lock-tools" name="Lock Tools">
    <flavor>This set of tools is designed for unlocking things that were meant to stay secured. Lock tools allow the user to open any lock as long as it is not magical or the rules of the lock specifically state otherwise. To see if the user can open a lock, roll 1D6. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the lock opens. On a score of 2 or 3 the lock refuses to open at the moment, though the user may try again next Turn.</flavor>
    <rules>On a score of 1, the lock tools are snapped off in the lock and are now useless. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-luckstone-of-anurandel" name="Luckstone of Anurandel">
    <flavor>Anurandel was a Wood Elf Sorceress, renowned for her peaceful demeanour, sunny disposition and hatred of battle.</flavor>
    <rules>She fashioned many items to aid her followers should they be assailed by dark forces. This plain, smooth stone bears an Elf rune. It allows the bearer to re-roll any one dice roll once per Adventure. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-lucky-talisman" name="Lucky Talisman">
    <flavor>Hanging from a fine chain, this palm-sized talisman is said to bring good luck.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use the Lucky Talisman at any time. Any Attack made while using the Lucky Talisman will automatically hit. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-mace-of-no-mercy" name="Mace of No Mercy">
    <flavor>The edges of this mace have been expertly sharpened so that it inflicts more damage upon impact This mace causes +1D3 Wounds if the To Hit roll is a natural 6.</flavor>
    <rules>PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-mace-of-thrashing" name="Mace of Thrashing">
    <rules>A Warrior feels extra aggressive with this mace in their hand. While using this mace, if the Warrior's final regular Attack in a Turn hits and causes at least one Wound (after all deductions), they may make an extra Attack on the Monster again. The Warrior may Keep making an extra Attack against the Monster until they miss or fail to cause a Wound. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-magic-arrers" name="Magic Arrers">
    <flavor>These arrows are carved with strange Goblin runes. The arrows are enchanted, but are somewhat unpredictable.</flavor>
    <rules>When fired, roll 1D6 below instead of rolling To Hit: 1 The arrow automatically hits one of the Warriors (determined randomly) for 1D6+3 Wounds. 2-5 The arrow automatically hits the Monster and causes 1D6+3 Wounds. 6 The arrow automatically hits the Monster causing 2D6+3 Wounds. There are 6 arrows. Each arrow can only be used once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>40G each</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-magic-beans" name="Magic Beans">
    <flavor>Glowing and vibrating in their hand, the Warrior can see that these are no ordinary beans!</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may eat a Magic Bean at any time. Roll 1D6 to see what effect the bean has on them for one Turn: 1 +1 To Hit. 2 +1 Movement. 3 +1 Strength. 4 +1 Toughness. 5 +1 Attack. 6 +1D6 Wounds when determining Damage. There are 1D6 beans and each one is worth 50 gold. DISCARD WHEN ALL EATEN</rules>
    <goldValue>50G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-magic-potion" name="Magic Potion">
    <flavor>This small glass bottle bears strange inscriptions in some long- forgotten magical language.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior drinks the Magic Potion, roll 1D6 to determine what it is: 1 Poison: suffer 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. 2 Poison: suffer 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. 3 Rainbow Potion: the Warrior's flesh becomes rainbow striped! 4 Healing Potion: restores 1D6 of the Warrior's Wounds. 5 Healing Potion: restores 2D6 of the Warrior's Wounds. 6 Healing Potion: restores the Warrior to full Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>60G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-magic-sword" name="Magic Sword">
    <flavor>This blade glows with a yellow light and is slightly warm to the touch.</flavor>
    <rules>This fine sword is worth 25 gold. (RPG: This weapon is magical.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>25G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-magical-quiver" name="Magical Quiver">
    <flavor>This quiver is made from soft leather and has magical runes branded into its surface.</flavor>
    <rules>This fine quiver is worth 25 gold. (RPG: Any arrows or crossbow bolts placed in this quiver immediately become enchanted so they can affect Monsters that can only be hit with magical weapons.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>25G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-mangler-helm" name="Mangler Helm">
    <flavor>Spikes protrude from the top of this helm, making it as dangerous as it is protective.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this helm, a Warrior gets +1 Toughness. In addition, if all of the Warrior's regular Attacks hit this Turn, they receive a special Helm Attack. Roll To Hit as normal. If the helm Attack hits, it causes normal Damage. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-map-of-finding" name="Map of Finding">
    <flavor>This parchment glows with a pale light but appears blank.</flavor>
    <rules>However, it may be of value to someone who understands how its magic works. This parchment is worth 50 gold. (RPG: A Warrior may use this map if they wish to find a Special Location in a Settlement without having to roll the dice. They only need to say the name f the place and, if the Settlement would normally include it, the map reveals exactly where it is. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-marsh-lights-scroll" name="Marsh Lights Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior sends a sparkling, dancing light down the corridor, drawing their opponents away.</flavor>
    <rules>This spell may be cast when Monsters are about to be placed on the Board. Roll 1D6 for each Monster that appears. On a score of 6 that Monster follows the marsh lights away from the Warrior and isn't placed on the Board at all. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-mask-of-horror" name="Mask of Horror">
    <flavor>This bizarre mask depicts the wicked face of a daemon.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears this mask takes on the appearance of a daemonic creature. Any Chaos or Daemonic Monster attacking the Warrior suffers -2 To Hit. If another Warrior is adjacent to the mask wearer and rolls a 1 To Hit, however, they have mistakenly hit the mask wearer instead, who suffers Damage as normal! This mask cannot be worn at the same time as a helmet. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-midnight-armour" name="Midnight Armour">
    <flavor>A dark cloud begins to swirl around the wearer of this black leather armour.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this armour a Warrior gets +1 Toughness. Once per Aventure, the armour can produce a black cloud that shrouds the Warrior in darkness. For one Turn Monsters only hit the wearer on a natural To Hit roll of 6. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-moradrels-boots" name="Moradrels Boots">
    <flavor>Moradrel was a skilled Elf Mage who created many powerful magic items, most of which have been lost or destroyed down the long years.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing these boots a Warrior's Movement Characteristic is 1D6+1 Roll each Turn to see how far the Warrior can move. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-morning-star-of-fracasse" name="Morning Star of Fracasse">
    <flavor>This flail seems to have a will of its own, trying to entangle nearby weapons.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior using this weapon rolls a natural 6 To Hit, the flail entwines itself around one object the creature struck is holding, yanking it from their grasp. The Monster may do nothing for one Turn as they retrieve it. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-mushroom-medley" name="Mushroom Medley">
    <flavor>One who holds these brightly coloured mushrooms in their hands feels a strange tingling sensation in their fingers. There are 1D3+1 Mushrooms and a Warrior may eat only one each Turn.</flavor>
    <rules>If they do, roll 1D6 to see what happens: 1-2 Hallucinogen. Confused, the Warrior attacks one random adjacent model this Turn. 3-4 Panacea. A sense of calm comes over the Warrior and they have 1D6 Wounds restored. 5-6 Stimulant. The Warrior's muscles begin to bulge and they get +3 Strength for the rest of the Turn. DISCARD WHEN ALL EATEN</rules>
    <goldValue>25G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-nightmare-shield" name="Nightmare Shield">
    <rules>Any foe whose eyes fall upon this shield sees the haunting vision of their own death. A Warrior carrying this shield gets +1 Toughness. In addition, the bearer may force a Monster to re-roll one of its Attacks against them, but they must accept the outcome of the second roll. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-norse-talisman" name="Norse Talisman">
    <flavor>Carved into this talisman is the image of a warrior at the heart of a ferocious storm.</flavor>
    <rules>When the power of this talisman is invoked, it allows the Barbarian to go Berserk automatically. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-obsidian-blade" name="Obsidian Blade">
    <flavor>This sword is made from the solidified blackness of the void, explaining its ability to destroy any armour it touches.</flavor>
    <rules>After a Warrior has made a successful Attack using this sword which actually wounded their opponent, roll 1D6. On a score of 5 or 6 the sword destroys the target's Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ogre-slayer" name="Ogre Slayer">
    <flavor>This brutal, broad-bladed axe is a powerful weapon and is almost certainly of Dwarf origin.</flavor>
    <rules>While using this two-handed axe a Warrior gets +2 Strength (+3 if they are a Dwarf). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ogre-strength-scroll" name="Ogre Strength Scroll">
    <flavor>Calling on the forces of magic, the Warrior bearing the scroll uses the power to increase the target's strength tremendously.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Warrior on the Board. That Warrior gets +2 Strength for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-old-rope" name="Old Rope">
    <flavor>This rope is old, worn and has begun to fray.</flavor>
    <rules>The rope can be used to escape from a pit. After each use, roll 1D6. On a score of 1, 2, 3 or 4 the rope breaks and must be discarded. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>3G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-orb-of-might" name="Orb of Might">
    <flavor>This black orb glistens dully and is far heavier than it looks. This orb contains 1D6 points of Power that the Wizard can use in the same way as his Power Tokens. Place a D6 on top of this card to show the orb's current Power.</flavor>
    <rules>Once all of the points are used up it is useless and worthless. It cannot be recharged. The orb is worth 50 gold per unused point of Power. DISCARD WHEN DRAINED</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-orb-of-obstruction" name="Orb of Obstruction">
    <flavor>This orb is affixed to a claw-like stand that grips the hand of whoever holds it.</flavor>
    <rules>When the power of the orb is invoked, no model on the same Board Section as the bearer may use any ability, magic or item that allows them to fly for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-orb-of-power" name="Orb of Power">
    <flavor>The surface of this glittering silver orb, constantly swirls as if in motion and exudes a distinctive magical aura.</flavor>
    <rules>This orb contains 1D6 points of Power that the Wizard can use the same way as his Power Tokens. Once all the points are used up it is useless and worthless. (RPG: The Wizard can recharge the Orb at the Font of Power, just like the Wizard's Staff.) USE ONCE THEN RECHARGE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-orb-of-sigmar" name="Orb of Sigmar">
    <flavor>The Grand Theogonist Wilhelm used this sparkling orb in his battle against the Vampire Count Vlad von Carstein.</flavor>
    <rules>When the power of the Orb is invoked, no Necromantic Magic may be used by any model on the same Board Section as the bearer for the next 1D6 Turns. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-parrying-blade" name="Parrying Blade">
    <flavor>This sword darts forward of its own volition to meet the weapon of an attacker, stopping the blow from hitting home.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Turn a Warrior using this sword may attempt to parry one hand-to-hand Attack that would otherwise hit them. Roll 1D6. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the attack is magically turned away and has no effect. (RPG: The sword gives the Warrior the Parry 4+ ability.) USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-pearl-necklace" name="Pearl Necklace">
    <flavor>This long pear! necklace is exquisite and will fetch a fair price when sold.</flavor>
    <rules>The necklace is worth 1D6x10 gold. (RPG: The Warrior may try and sell the Pearl Necklace to the General Store. Roll 1D6 and multiply the result by 10 to see how much the trader will offer you for it. However, if you roll a 1, the necklace is fake, and the trader refuses to buy it. You will have to try and sell it at another Settlement.) DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x10G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-phantasm-sword" name="Phantasm Sword">
    <flavor>The magic sigils on this sword glow brightly whenever an evil spirit draws near.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this two-handed sword they get +2 Strength. In addition, when used against Monsters with the Ethereal ability, the wielder gets +1 To Hit and causes Double Damage. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-pipes-of-doom" name="Pipes of Doom">
    <flavor>Playing these pipes produces a hauntingly beautiful chord.</flavor>
    <rules>When played, the sound from these pipes echo for one Turn. During that time every Warrior on the same Board Section as the player only miss with their regular Attacks if their To Hit roll isa 1. If a Warrior rolls a natural 1 To Hit, however, they blunder their Attack so badly that they hit themselves instead and suffer normal Damage. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-pit-of-despair-scroll" name="Pit of Despair Scroll">
    <flavor>Roaring words of power the bearer of the scroll stamps their foot into the ground, cracking the floor with a loud boom.</flavor>
    <rules>Place the Pit of Despair marker on any 2 square by 2 square area on the Board. Roll 1D6 for each model standing in the pit area. On a 1 or 2 it falls into the pit and is killed. On a 3, 4, 5 or 6 it scrambles out of the way - put it in an empty square on this or any adjacent Board Section. If there are no empty squares available, the model falls into the pit anyway. Once the pit is in place, no model may enter the squares it covers. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-plergits-stabba" name="Plergits Stabba">
    <flavor>This wickedly sharp and very thin bladed dagger is designed for slipping between armour joints.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use this dagger to make an extra attack by rolling 1D6: 1 The attack misses. 2-4 The attack hits causing 2D6+Strength Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. 5-6 The attacks hits causing 3D6 + Strength Wounds, with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-alchemy" name="Potion of Alchemy">
    <flavor>The pink liquid in this small glass bottle constantly fizzes and bubbles.</flavor>
    <rules>At the end of the Adventure, a Warrior may sell this potion to an Alchemist for 1D6x40 gold. (RPG: To sell this potion, the Warrior must first find the Alchemist's Laboratory Special Location in a Settlement!) DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x40G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-battle" name="Potion of Battle">
    <flavor>This robust, pocket-sized bottle is filled with a sparkling yellow liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1 Attack for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-climbing" name="Potion of Climbing">
    <flavor>This tiny bottle provides a big effect. The liquid is thick Ike honey and tastes as sweet.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drink this potion may climb walls or over obstacles for one Turn. This potion does not affect the distance that a Warrior may move. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-disguise" name="Potion of Disguise">
    <flavor>This black liquid has no taste and leaves no trace of moisture on the lips.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion will not be attacked and automatically Escapes from Pinning as long as they do not initiate Combat. As soon as the Warrior attacks a target in any way the potion's effects wear off. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-endurance" name="Potion of Endurance">
    <flavor>This small bottle of sluggish, orange liquid is surprisingly heavy.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may drink this potion to ignore the Wounds from a single blow that might otherwise kill them. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-flight" name="Potion of Flight">
    <flavor>The contents of this bottle bubble and pop. This effervescent liquid goes down easily and leaves the Warrior feeling light- headed and light of body!</flavor>
    <rules>After drinking this potion the Warrior levitates a few inches above the ground while moving. While airborne the Warrior may pass over chasms, pits, etc unhindered and anyone who attacks them suffers -1 To Hit. The effects last for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-flying" name="Potion of Flying">
    <flavor>The grey surface of this thick necked bottle cannot conceal the golden liquid within.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion may fly for one Turn. While airborne they move 1D6+2 squares, can fly over obstacles and may automatically Escape from Pinning. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-fortitude" name="Potion of Fortitude">
    <flavor>A deep red liquid fills this crystal decanter.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1D6 Wounds. These additional Wounds can take the Warrior above their Starting Wounds score. If that is the case, these extra Wounds are temporary. Once they are lost, they are lost for good. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-healing" name="Potion of Healing">
    <flavor>This ornate glass bottle contains a blue coloured liquid with a sweet, fruity smell.</flavor>
    <rules>Testing with the smallest sip reveals that it is a potion of healing. There is enough Potion of Healing in this bottle to restore two Warriors to full Wounds. When the first dose is taken, flip this card upside-down; when the second dose is taken, discard it. USE TWICE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-instability" name="Potion of Instability">
    <flavor>This fine crystal decanter is full of a glowing orange liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>When drunk, this potion shifts the dimensional position of the Warrior, making them _ ethereal and_ insubstantial. They automatically Escape from Pinning, but may not take any offensive action, cast magic or be attacked for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-invisibility" name="Potion of Invisibility">
    <flavor>This vial contains a multi-coloured liquid that swirls sluggishly and gives off heady vapours once the seal is broken.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion becomes invisible for one Turn. While invisible the Warrior cannot be attacked or cast spells, but may otherwise fight as normal. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-keensight" name="Potion of Keensight">
    <flavor>A small magical icon decorates this bottle, inside of which is a fiery yellow liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion may make a number of missile attacks equal to their Attack Characteristic this Turn, rather than the standard one shot per Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-lightning-blades" name="Potion of Lightning Blades">
    <flavor>This tiny glass bottle is full of a bitter purple liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1 To Hit (RPG: +1 To Hit per Battle-level) for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-magic" name="Potion of Magic">
    <flavor>This small bottle contains a cloudy purple substance.</flavor>
    <rules>When drunk, this potion restores 1D6 of the Wizard's Power Tokens. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-might" name="Potion of Might">
    <flavor>An intoxicating liquid flows from this bottle, bringing a sense of power and might to whoever drinks it.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1D6 Strength for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-pain" name="Potion of Pain">
    <flavor>This large bottle seems to barely contain the bubbling orange liquid within.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may drink this potion to ignore the Wounds from a single blow that might otherwise kill them. In addition, it the Warrior has 2D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-power" name="Potion of Power">
    <flavor>This effervescent yellow-orange liquid has a sour taste, but leaves the Warrior feeling powerful.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior drinks this potion, their next regular Attack causes maximum Damage if it hits. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-preservation" name="Potion of Preservation">
    <flavor>Inside this bottle is a lucent orange liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion has 1D6 Wounds restored. In addition, the drinker will not suffer any Wounds that occur at the end of the Turn (RPG: the drinker does not suffer any Fatal Damage this Turn). USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-rage" name="Potion of Rage">
    <flavor>A fiery reddish-orange solution churns in this flask.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion flies into a furious rage. They double their regular Attacks and suffer -1 To Hit for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-respiration" name="Potion of Respiration">
    <flavor>The hue of this coral coloured liquid seems to shift and change with how the bottle is held.</flavor>
    <rules>When drunk, this potion allows the Warrior to ignore anything that might affect their respiration, such as water or poison gas. The effects last for 1D6 Turns. There is enough liquid for four drinks. If sold the potion is worth 100 gold for every drink still left in the bottle. DISCARD WHEN ALL DRUNK</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-strength" name="Potion of Strength">
    <flavor>The bright red liquid in this bottle swishes about by its own volition.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1 Strength for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-swiftness" name="Potion of Swiftness">
    <flavor>Inside this stoppered glass bottle is a glossy blue liquid much thicker than water.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1D6 Movement and may automatically Escape from Pinning. The effects of the potion last for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-toughness" name="Potion of Toughness">
    <flavor>This shining bottle is full of a thick purple liquid.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +1 Toughness for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-water-walking" name="Potion of Water Walking">
    <flavor>This effervescent liquid has a salty tang reminiscent of the sea.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion may walk on water for one Turn, moving at a rate of (3 x their normal Movement) squares per Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-weapon-mastery" name="Potion of Weapon Mastery">
    <flavor>The warm amber liquid in this stoppered glass phial goes down smoothly and leaves a pleasant aftertaste.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion gets +2 To Hit and causes +2D6 Wounds when attacking with a missile weapon or in hand-to-hand Combat. The effects of the potion last for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-pouch-of-gold" name="Pouch of Gold">
    <flavor>The Warrior hears the pleasant sound of coins jingling as they shake this small, leather pouch.</flavor>
    <rules>This pouch contains 3 gold pieces. RECORD THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>3G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-precious-icon" name="Precious Icon">
    <flavor>This mysterious, unusual icon might be worth something to someone.</flavor>
    <rules>The casket contains an icon which belongs to the Elders of a far distant village. After the Adventure, the icon may be sold back to the Elders for 1D6x200 gold. (RPG: Obviously the Warrior must first visit a Village to claim their reward!) DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-pritty-stonez" name="Pritty Stonez">
    <flavor>This small drawstring bag contains some _ ordinary-looking stones.</flavor>
    <rules>When the Warrior looks through the 'stones', roll 1D6 below: 1-2 They are indeed pretty, but ordinary, stones worth nothing. 3-4 Mixed with normal stones are 1D6 gold nuggets wroth 25 gold each. 5-6 Mixed with normal stones are 1D6 gemstones worth 100 gold each. RECORD THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-prophet-shield" name="Prophet Shield">
    <flavor>This shield allows the bearer to anticipate attacks made from a distance.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior bearing this shield gets +1 Toughness. In addition, all incoming missile Attacks against the bearer suffer -1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-protection-ring" name="Protection Ring">
    <flavor>This small ring has the image of a shield engraved on its uppermost surface.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this ring gets +1 Toughness. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-quake-scroll" name="Quake Scroll">
    <flavor>This dusty scroll is inscribed with magic runes and sigils that contain words of power.</flavor>
    <rules>This scroll can be used at any time, and causes a 2 square by 2 square area of any one Board Section to cave in. Use the Cave- in marker to mark the area affected. Any Warrior or Monster caught in the area covered by the cave-in suffers 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-quarg-horn" name="Quarg Horn">
    <flavor>Who created this very unusual, gold-leaf covered, baroque horn is a mystery. This horn can only be used during the Hunting Settlement Event.</flavor>
    <rules>When they are alone in the forest, the Warrior may blow the horn and roll 1D6: 1-5 The horn makes an awful noise, like a flatulent ogre. Nothing happens. 6 The horn makes a beautiful, clear sound. A fabulous beast bounds out of the bushes and fawns at the Warrior's feet. They have captured a Quarg! They can sell the Quarg for 1000 gold, but no one will buy the horn off them... ROLEPLAYING GAME ONLY PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>0G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rapid-fire-bracelets" name="Rapid Fire Bracelets">
    <flavor>These bracelets were created by the Elves to complement the fabled Silver Band of Loren.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing these bracelets gets +1 Attack when using a missile weapon. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-reaper-sword" name="Reaper Sword">
    <flavor>This mighty sword is sharper than a razor. Its keen blade glistens in the light of the lantern, and even in the shadows it shimmers with an eerie inner light.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this sword they get +2 Strength. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rebound-scroll" name="Rebound Scroll">
    <flavor>As the bearer of this scroll chants the words of this spell, a shimmering mirror of power surrounds the target, protecting them from harm.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick any Warrior on the Board. Each time they are physically struck by a blow this Turn, roll 1D6. On a score of 6 all the Damage from the blow is rebounded onto whoever caused it. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-relic-blade" name="Relic Blade">
    <flavor>This holy blade is an artefact of great religious significance within the Empire, and was reputed to have been used by the realm's mightiest heroes in numerous battles.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this sword they get +2 To Hit. (RPG: If the To Hit roll is a natural 1, however, the Warrior misses and is so off-balance that they lose any remaining Attacks they have this Turn.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ricochet-helm" name="Ricochet Helm">
    <flavor>Magic runes of warding are emblazoned upon this otherwise smooth helm.</flavor>
    <rules>The wearer of this helm gets +1 Toughness. In addition, each time the wearer is hit by a missile attack, roll 1D6. If the score is a 6, the attack ricochets off and hits a random Monster within the wearer's Line of Sight instead. But if the result is a 1, the attacks pings off and hits a random Warrior within the wearer's Line of Sight instead! PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-anurandel" name="Ring of Anurandel">
    <flavor>Anurandel was a Wood Elf Sorceress, renowned for her peaceful demeanour, sunny disposition and hatred of battle. She fashioned many items to aid her followers should they be assailed by dark forces.</flavor>
    <rules>If the bearer of the ring takes no offensive action this Turn, the ring will restore 1D6 Wounds at the end of the turn. If the score is a 1 or 2 the ring's power is drained for the rest of the Adventure. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-dadaan" name="Ring of Dadaan">
    <flavor>This ring crackles with power and feels unusually heavy for its size. The Ring of Dadaan allows a Warrior to cast a spell. Take one of the Wizard's Starting Spell Cards at random: this is the spell that is stored in the ring.</flavor>
    <rules>The bearer of the ring may cast the stored spell automatically at any time. After use, the ring is drained of all magic and becomes worthless. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-invisibility" name="Ring of Invisibility">
    <flavor>Slipping this ring on, the wearer fades from sight.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this ring, a Warrior is invisible and cannot be attacked, although they may fight as normal. The ring contains enough power to Keep the bearer invisible for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-life" name="Ring of Life">
    <flavor>Within the central gemstone of this silver, jewel-encrusted ring, a tiny flame burns brightly.</flavor>
    <rules>The ring has the power to heal grievous wounds. It may only be used to heal another Warrior (not the bearer) if they are on zero Wounds. To use the ring, roll 1D6. On a roll of 1 the flame flickers and dies, and has no effect. On any other score the Warrior is restored to full Wounds. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-power" name="Ring of Power">
    <flavor>This simple band of stone slips easily onto a Warrior's finger, contracting until it is a perfect fit.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this ring one of the Warrior's Characteristics is increased by +1. The Warrior may choose to increase Movement, Weapon Skill, Ballistic Skill, Strength, Toughness, Initiative, Attacks, Luck, Willpower or Escape Pinning. The Warrior must choose which Characteristic is affected the first time they put on the ring. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-solitude" name="Ring of Solitude">
    <flavor>This silver ring is inset with tiny emeralds in the shape of leaves.</flavor>
    <rules>When drawing a Warrior Counter to determine who the target is for a group of Monsters who all attack a single Warrior (RPG: Monsters who have the Gang Up ability), the first time the bearer's counter is pulled out they may put it back and draw again. If it comes up a second time, they are attacked as normal. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-sure-seeing" name="Ring of Sure Seeing">
    <flavor>This ring has a large gem set in its surface that, in times of danger, warns of what is to come.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this ring may swap an Event Card that has just been drawn for another. Shuffle ALL the other Event Cards together (including any that have already been used) to make a new Event Deck. Take the top card and carry on as usual. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rod-of-wounds" name="Rod of Wounds">
    <flavor>This baton is actually a powerful rod that can give or take life. The Warrior wielding this rod may choose up to 3 targets and roll 3D6.</flavor>
    <rules>The result is the number of points the Warrior may use to heal the targets as they see fit. But note that the points of healing from a single dice cannot be divided and must be spent on a single Warrior, and all targets must be healed. If two of the dice come up a 1, however, all of the targets suffer 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. When the rod is found it contains 1D6 charges. Each use drains one charge. The rod is worth 75 gold per unused charge. DISCARD WHEN DRAINED</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-death" name="Rune of Death">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Death into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Death itself is permanent. For one Attack per Adventure, this weapon causes +2D6 Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-destruction" name="Rune of Destruction">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Destruction into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Destruction itself is permanent. Once per Adventure, the wielder of this weapon can double their regular Attacks for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-fortitude" name="Rune of Fortitude">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Fortitude into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Fortitude itself is permanent. At the beginning of each Adventure the wielder of this weapon gets +1D6 extra Starting Wounds. These Wounds are temporary and once they are lost, they are lost for the rest of the Adventure. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-fury" name="Rune of Fury">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Fury into the blade and then vanishes. The Rue of Fury itself is permanent. While wielding this weapon a Warrior gains +1 Attack. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-magic" name="Rune of Magic">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Magic into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Magic itself is permanent. The rune glows dully, and Keeps the blade sharp. From now on, this weapon is treated as being magical. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>25G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-prowess" name="Rune of Prowess">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Prowess into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Prowess itself is permanent. While wielding this weapon the Warrior gets +1 To Hit. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-slaying" name="Rune of Slaying">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Slaying into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Slaying itself is permanent. For one Attack per Adventure this weapon will now inflict Double Damage when it strikes. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-smashing" name="Rune of Smashing">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Smashing into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Smashing itself is permanent. This weapon now ignores 1 point of Armour when determining Damage. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-rune-of-sure-striking" name="Rune of Sure Striking">
    <flavor>This stone of Dwarf construction is inscribed with a glowing rune.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Sure Striking into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Sure Striking itself is permanent. When rolling more than one Damage Dice, the wielder of this weapon may re-roll the Damage Dice that scores the lowest. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sack-of-gold" name="Sack of Gold">
    <flavor>Although this sack is tattered, the gold coins within it still glisten.</flavor>
    <rules>The sack contains 1D6x50 gold. RECORD THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-salve-of-mending" name="Salve of Mending">
    <flavor>Inside a stone container is a thick red paste.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior applies this salve to themselves or one of their companions, it immediately restores 1D3 of the recipient's Wounds. If a natural 1 is rolled when determining how many Wounds are restored, the effects of the salve are complete. Otherwise, the salve will continue restoring 1D3 Wounds at the beginning on the next Turn. This process continues until a natural 1 is rolled when determining how many Wounds are restored. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-salve-of-strength" name="Salve of Strength">
    <flavor>This stoppered jade-stone phial contains a glittering bronze salve.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who uses this salve gets +1 Strength for 1D6 Turns. There is only enough salve in the phial for one application. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sands-of-time" name="Sands of Time">
    <flavor>The Mad Sorcerer of Araby, Abdul Alhazred, created this magical timepiece so that he could steal a powerful artefact from the Palace of the Wizard Caliph.</flavor>
    <rules>When this hourglass is turned over, time stops. Every model on the Board, except the bearer of the hourglass, is frozen in time. The bearer may automatically Escape from Pinning and can do anything (move, heal, etc.) but may not take any offensive action. At the beginning of each Turn thereafter, the bearer must roll 1D6. If the score is a 1, 2 or 3, the sands have reached the bottom and time begins again. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>350G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-satchel-of-shallya" name="Satchel of Shallya">
    <flavor>This satchel has the mark of the Temple Hospice of Shallya in</flavor>
    <rules>Altdorf and is usually carried by travelling priests. The Satchel contains 1D6 Bandages. Each bandage restores 3 Wounds. (RPG: At the end of each Adventure, any remaining Bandages in the satchel vanish. However, at the start of the next Adventure, the satchel will have magically replenished itself, and will contain 1D6 Bandages again!) 1D6 BANDAGES PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>175G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sceptre-of-docility" name="Sceptre of Docility">
    <flavor>Alikahn the Keeper was an expert beast handler from Araby. This sceptre helped him control the may wild creatures that he kept in his menagerie.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wields this sceptre as a weapon gets +1 To Hit with it. (RPG: In addition, if a Warrior wields the sceptre in Combat, Monsters on the same Board Section as the bearer are not subject to the Frenzy or Hate abilities.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>450G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sceptre-of-ruination" name="Sceptre of Ruination">
    <flavor>This ram-headed scepter feels heavy in the hand when swung against certain foes.</flavor>
    <rules>The sceptre may be wielded like a weapon, and causes Double Damage against any Chaos creatures. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-scroll-of-the-chimera" name="Scroll of the Chimera">
    <rules>When unrolled, words of power glow dully on this ancient parchment. The spell on this scroll gives the bearer the appearance of a ferocious monster. The scroll may be read at any time, causing any Monsters to be so terrified of the affected Warrior that they will suffer -2 To Hit against them. The spell lasts until a 1 or 2 is rolled in the Power Phase. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-second-chance-token" name="Second Chance Token">
    <flavor>This mysterious token has a large, laughing skull in its center.</flavor>
    <rules>The power of this curio may be used when a Counter is drawn randomly (such as a Warrior Counter, Catacombs Counter, Creep Counter, etc.) The bearer of this token may ignore the result and draw another one instead. The first counter drawn is then mixed back in with the others, as if it had never been drawn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-shield-of-deliverance" name="Shield of Deliverance">
    <flavor>This shield is of simple yet exquisite craftsmanship. It seems to be made of a substance stronger than steel, yet weighs little more than a sheet of parchment.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior bearing this shield gets +1 Toughness. In addition, they may ignore the Damage from any two blows. The first time the shield is used, flip this card upside-down; when it is used a second time, discard it. USE TWICE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silks-of-cathay" name="Silks of Cathay">
    <flavor>Inside a long abandoned crate the Warriors discover elegant silks from the distant land of Cathay.</flavor>
    <rules>There are 1D3 pieces of beautiful silk and each one will fetch 25 gold. (RPG: If sold in a Town, each piece is worth 50 gold. If sold ina City, each piece is worth 100 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D3x25G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silver-band-of-loren" name="Silver Band of Loren">
    <flavor>This ring was created by the Elves to complement the fabled Rapid Fire Bracelets.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this ring gets +1 Ballistic Skill. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silver-cubes-of-ogham" name="Silver Cubes of Ogham">
    <flavor>These glowing silver cubes were fashioned from the Ogham Stones on the misty island of Albion.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may toss these cubes down at the feet of a single Monster during Combat by choosing as many D6 as they wish and rolling them all at the same time. For every dice that comes up a 6, the Monster suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. But for every dice that comes up a 1, the Warrior suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. If this reduces the Warrior to zero Wounds, they are dead and cannot be revived. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>475G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silver-dagger" name="Silver Dagger">
    <flavor>This dagger is made of pure silver and therefore highly sought after by Witch Hunters.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this dagger gets +1 To Hit. The dagger is Strength 2 and can be used in hand-to-hand Combat or as a missile weapon. Against Undead and Chaos creatures the dagger is considered magical and causes Double Damage if the To Hit roll is a 5 or 6. If thrown, it may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silver-sigil-sword" name="Silver Sigil Sword">
    <flavor>Doznes of magical runes symbolising freedom, capability and advantage have been etched onto this blade.</flavor>
    <rules>While wielding this sword a Warrior gets +3 Initiative. In addition, the wielder may add +1 to their roll to Escape from Pinning. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silver-stone" name="Silver Stone">
    <flavor>The Silver Stone imbues a weapon it touches with magical powers.</flavor>
    <rules>The stone may be used once to permanently enchant a single weapon. The Silver Stone vanishes, but the affected weapon is now magical, and causes +1D6 Wounds on a To Hit roll of 6. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-silver-tipped-arrows" name="Silver-tipped Arrows">
    <flavor>The head of these arrows are made from pure silver.</flavor>
    <rules>These arrows cause +1 Wound. (RPG: If used against a Werewolf, these arrows cause Double Damage instead.) There are 1D3 arrows and each arrow may be used only once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>50G each</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sky-arrows-of-naloer" name="Sky Arrows of Naloer">
    <flavor>These magical arrows were enchanted long ago by an Elven mage.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using these arrows gets +1 To Hit and cause +1D3 Wounds when attacking Monsters with the F/y ability. There are 2D6 arrows and each may be used only once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>50G each</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sleep-scroll" name="Sleep Scroll">
    <flavor>Murmuring quietly, the bearer of the scroll sends their opponents into an enchanted sleep.</flavor>
    <rules>The bearer may target any Monster on the same Board Section by rolling 4D6. If the total score is more than the target's Starting Wounds it falls asleep for 1 Turn. The dice may be split between multiple targets. The bearer must declare how the dice are being split before rolling. If split, the total of the combined dice for each target must be greater than its Starting Wounds for the spell to work on that Monster. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-soulstone" name="Soulstone">
    <flavor>The Soulstone captures the departing soul of the bearer, should they be slain. Someone with the correct knowledge can then restore the soul to their body, resurrecting the unfortunate person.</flavor>
    <rules>If the Warrior with the Soulstone is killed, by whatever means, they can be resurrected once the Adventure is over. They lose any Treasure and gold they have accumulated during that Adventure, and are unchanged from the Warrior they were when they set off on the Adventure. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-spear-of-precision" name="Spear of Precision">
    <flavor>This hefty-looking spear has a wickedly sharp head.</flavor>
    <rules>In addition to any other attacks they may have, a Warrior may throw this spear as a missile weapon at any time, at a target on the same Board Section as the wielder. To throw the spear, roll 1D6. On a 3, 4, 5 or 6 the Warrior has hit the target and causes 3D6 Wounds. They spear may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-speed-scroll" name="Speed Scroll">
    <flavor>Breathing deeply, the Warrior uses the power of the scroll to speed up their movement.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who uses this scroll has their Movement doubled for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-spell-ring" name="Spell Ring">
    <rules>Any Wizard recognizes this potent ring as being capable of storing magical knowledge. Take one Starting Spell Card at random: this is the spell that is stored in the ring. The bearer of the ring may cast the stored spell automatically at any time. After use, the ring is drained and the Spell Card must be discarded. (RPG: If it is drained, the ring will slowly recharge itself. At the start of the next Adventure take a new Starting Spell Card to represent the new spell that is stored in the ring.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-spices-of-araby" name="Spices of Araby">
    <flavor>Araby, scorched land of sand and blazing sun, is home to some of the most learned men in the world.</flavor>
    <rules>This earthenware pot is full of rich spices, and their pungent tang fills the air. The spices are worth 1D3x100 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D3x100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-spiderweb-paste" name="Spiderweb Paste">
    <flavor>This bottle is filled with a sparkling purple solution.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may throw this bottle as a missile weapon at any time with a Range of 4 squares. It hits automatically, shattering upon impact. Roll 1D6. If the score is equal to or greater than the target's Movement Characteristic, the target is truck in a pool of gooey paste reminiscent of a spider's web. They cannot move or perform any offensive actions for one Turn, and any Attacks made against them get +1 To Hit. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-spinebreaker" name="Spinebreaker">
    <flavor>This fine weapon seems to magically reshape to fit into the wielder's hand perfectly.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this mace causes +1 Wound (RPG: +1 Wound per Battle-level) if their To Hit roll is a 5 or 6. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-spinning-top" name="Spinning Top">
    <flavor>This large cone-shaped device vibrates with energy. This metal cone may be placed on the ground during Combat where it spins out of control with an extraordinary amount of force. Roll 1D6 for each model on the Board Section Cincluding any Warrior).</flavor>
    <rules>If the score is a 6 when rolling for a Monster, it is Knocked down and spends the next Monsters' Phase getting back up. Any Warrior attacking a fallen Monster gets +2 To Hit. If the score is a 1 when rolling for a Warrior, they are Knocked down, must spend one full Turn getting up and Monsters attacking them get +2 To Hit. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-stone-icon-of-ghamaluk" name="Stone Icon of Ghamaluk">
    <flavor>Ghamaluk was a grand vizier of Araby and created a series of stone icons specifically to combat the Undead hordes amassed against him.</flavor>
    <rules>Many of these icons have passed into the hands of the famous Witch Hunter Gunter Grafftag of Sylvania. This icon may be used to restore the bearer back to full Wounds. It fails to work while the bearer is on zero Wounds. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-stone-of-bravery" name="Stone of Bravery">
    <flavor>This stone gives great confidence to the bearer, such that fear seems but a dream.</flavor>
    <rules>This valuable semi-precious stone is worth 250 gold. (RPG: The bearer gets +1 to all psychology based tests such as Fear and Terror.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-stone-of-transmutation" name="Stone of Transmutation">
    <flavor>This small, plain stone hangs from a delicate copper chain.</flavor>
    <rules>The item may be used to transmute a single Monster into stone, killing it. To determine whether the stone works roll 1D6+1 (RPG: 1D6 + the Warrior's Battle-level). If the total is greater than the target Monster's current Wounds, it becomes a statue, otherwise the spell fails. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-stonebread" name="Stonebread">
    <flavor>Dwarf stonebread is exactly what its name suggests - bread with the consistency of stone.</flavor>
    <rules>Only a Dwarf would ever consider eating Stonebread, and they take a gruff satisfaction in the fact that only they can eat the stuff. Eating Stonebread is obviously no quick task. If a Dwarf does nothing for a Turn, except chew their way through a piece of Stonebread, at the end of the Warriors' Phase they have 1D6 Wounds restored. There are 1D6 pieces. DISCARD AFTER ALL EATEN</rules>
    <goldValue>30G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-stormhammer" name="Stormhammer">
    <flavor>Sparks fly from this warhammer each time it strikes.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior wielding this weapon rolls a natural 6 To Hit, in addition to normal Damage, the target is stunned and suffers - 1 Attack for one Turn. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-strength-scroll" name="Strength Scroll">
    <flavor>The scroll bears the words for the Strength spell. When cast, the targeted Warrior feels renewed energy surging through their aching muscles.</flavor>
    <rules>When the scroll is used, pick any Warrior on the Board. That Warrior gets +1 Strength for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-strongmans-mallet" name="Strongmans Mallet">
    <flavor>This sizeable wooden mallet is the kind used in carnivals to test one's strength.</flavor>
    <rules>This magical two-handed mallet causes +1D6 Wounds (or Double Damage if the To Hit roll is a natural 6) and ignores non- Magical Armour. The mallet is deliberately weighted poorly, however, so each time a Warrior attemps to swing it, they must roll 1D6 and add their Strength. If the total is 7 or more, they are able to use it normally. If the total is 6 or less, they suffer -2 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sunfire-amulet" name="Sunfire Amulet">
    <flavor>This amulet radiates warmth and comfort to the wearer.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this amulet gets +2 Starting Wounds. (RPG: In addition, each Turn that there is a Vampire on the same Board Section as the wearer, roll 1D6. If the score is a 4, 5 or 6, the Vampire may not use their special Vampire Ability this Turn.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-liberation" name="Sword of Liberation">
    <rules>While holding this sword, the bearer feels light and unencumbered by their belongings. A Warrior wielding this sword gets +2 to any dice rolls when trying to escape spider webs, goblin nets or any other type of physical restraints. In addition, they may ignore any terrain effects or Armour penalties that would reduce their Movement. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-might" name="Sword of Might">
    <flavor>This sword is imbued with the strength of an Ogre, and any blow struck with it delivers that power to the target.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this sword they get +1 Strength. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-resilience" name="Sword of Resilience">
    <flavor>This sword throws a mantle of power around its wielder, protecting them from their enemies.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this sword they get +1 Toughness. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-stone" name="Sword of Stone">
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this weapon feels their skin hardening into a stone-like material, which remains as flexible as normal flesh. While a Warrior is using this sword they get +2 Toughness. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-swords-of-doom-scroll" name="Swords of Doom Scroll">
    <flavor>Instead of wielding one sword, a great many blades suddenly start to whirl and slash the air before the Warrior bearing the scroll.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the Warrior bearing the scroll gets +2 Attacks. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-tablet-of-anurandel" name="Tablet of Anurandel">
    <flavor>Anurandel was a Wood Elf Sorceress of Loren, renowned for her peaceful demeanour, sunny disposition and hatred of battle.</flavor>
    <rules>She fashioned many items to aid her followers should they be assailed by dark forces. The tablet has the power to completely destroy a single item carried by an enemy. Roll 1D6. If the score is a 5 or 6, the item may no longer be used. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-talisman-of-alcadizzar" name="Talisman of Alcadizzar">
    <flavor>This talisman protected a great Priest King against the decaying magic of the evil Liche Lord Nagash himself. This talisman allows the Warrior to counter Necromantic Magic.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time a Necromantic spell is cast against the bearer of the amulet, roll 1D6. On a score of 5 or 6 the spell has no effect on them. (RPG: the amulet gives the bearer the Magic Resistance 5+ ability against Necromantic spells). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-talisman-of-ravendark" name="Talisman of Ravendark">
    <flavor>The gemstone in the center of this talisman glows like a full moon obscured by dark clouds.</flavor>
    <rules>When the power of this talisman is invoked, all Monsters on the Board with the Fly ability only hit the Warriors on a natural To Hit roll of 6, while any Warrior attacking those Monsters only misses on a natural To Hit roll of 1. The effects of the talisman last for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-talon-of-death" name="Talon of Death">
    <flavor>This magical artefactsucks all of the light from the surrounding area, creating an aura of darkness.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior bearing the Talon of Death may use it once they have finished moving to cause 1D6 Wounds on every adjacent Monster, with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. Roll for each Monster separately. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-tankard" name="Tankard">
    <flavor>Although covered in verdigris, this metal tankard is obviously of fine craftsmanship.</flavor>
    <rules>This is a Dwarf tankard, specially designed for the drinking of Bugman's beer. Tankards like this are much valued by Dwarfs. If a Dwarf finds this tankard, they will never sell it! DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>20G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-tapestry" name="Tapestry">
    <flavor>This beautiful tapestry is intricately patterned and most likely hails from a faraway land such as Ind or Cathay.</flavor>
    <rules>Such tapestries are highly sought after by affluent nobles. It is worth 1D6x50 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-tea-leaves-of-nippon" name="Tea Leaves of Nippon">
    <flavor>Grown in the rich and fertile fields of the majestic island empire, these tea leaves are highly sought after for their unique flavour.</flavor>
    <rules>There are 1D6 small bundles of leaves and each is worth 10 gold. (RPG: If sold in a Town, each bundle is worth 20 gold. If sold in a City, each bundle is worth 30 gold.) DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x10G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-throwing-knife" name="Throwing Knife">
    <flavor>This is an extremely well balanced throwing knife that seems to leap from the thrower's hand.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may throw the knife at any Monster in their Line of Sight that is not in an adjacent square to them. The knife hits on a roll of 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6. It causes 2D6+Strength Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness and Armour. The knife may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. USE ONCE PER COMBAT</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-throwing-ring" name="Throwing Ring">
    <flavor>This polished bronze ring expands and contracts to fit around its target.</flavor>
    <rules>This ring may be thrown at any time as a missile weapon with a Range of 3 squares. On a successfully hit, the ring drops over one of the Monster's limbs and constricts. The Monster may not cast spells and suffers -2 To Hit. At the beginning of each subsequent Turn, roll 1D6. If the score is a 6, the ring remains in place and the target suffers the penalties above. On any other score, the Monster manages to free itself. The ring may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-time-freeze-ring" name="Time Freeze Ring">
    <rules>When this ring is put on, it freezes like ice and bursts into a cold blue flame, yet still feels comfortable to wear. The Time Freeze Ring may be used at any time, giving the Warriors an additional Warriors' Phase straight away. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-trance-stone" name="Trance Stone">
    <flavor>Strands of energy swim serenely throughout this small blue stone.</flavor>
    <rules>If the bearer does nothing, including move, for one Turn, and there are no Monsters on the Board, they have 1 Wound restored. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>75G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-transportation-scroll" name="Transportation Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior mumbles a few words and then disappears in a mist of yellow smoke.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may use this scroll at any time by rolling 1D6. If the result is a 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, the Warrior may immediately move from the space they are in to any unoccupied space on the Board that has already been explored. If the score is a 1, the Warrior disappears and is never seen again. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>250G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-tunic-of-brawn" name="Tunic of Brawn">
    <flavor>This tunic made from bear and wolf hides has been enchanted by a Norse shaman.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is wearing this tunic, they get +1 Stregnth. If the tunic is worn in addition to armour, the wearer suffers -1 Movement and -1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-undead-bane" name="Undead Bane">
    <flavor>This sealed silver pot is full of a thick and foul smelling unguent.</flavor>
    <rules>A weapon coated with this unguent causes +1 Wound (RPG: +1 Wound per Battle-level) to any Undead it hits. There is enough unguent to coat one weapon and the effects last for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>50G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-voidmaster-scroll" name="Voidmaster Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior temporarily leaves the physical universe for the cold depths of the void, where they can recover their strength.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, this scroll allows the bearer to disappear from the Board. After one whole Turn, roll 1D6. If the result is a 2, 3, 4,5 or 6, they reappear anywhere on the same Board Section with all of their Wounds restored. If the result is a 1, however, the Warrior disappears in the void and must be removed from the game. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wall-of-steel" name="Wall of Steel">
    <flavor>This cool blue steel blade flickers as if alive, creating a deadly shimmering blur through which none may pass. In a Corridor or Doorway, no Monster may pass the Warrior while they use this sword, whether they are flying Monsters or even Monsters who are never Pinned.</flavor>
    <rules>PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wand-of-light" name="Wand of Light">
    <flavor>The bright, magical light of this wand radiates an aura of protection.</flavor>
    <rules>The bearer of the wand can use it to explore just as if they carried the Lantern. In addition, a Warrior carrying this wand gets +1 Toughness. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-warhammer-of-eruption" name="Warhammer of Eruption">
    <flavor>Molten lava spews from this warhammer each time it finds its mark.</flavor>
    <rules>This two-handed warhammer causes Double Damage to a target if the To Hit roll is a natural 6, and all adjacent models to the target (friend or foe) suffer 1 Wound with no modifiers for anything. However, if the wielder rolls a natural 1 To Hit, they are splashed with magma and suffer 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-warlock-slayer-helm" name="Warlock Slayer Helm">
    <flavor>This card appears on the dungeon treasure table, but the scan did not preserve its description text clearly enough to recover it reliably.</flavor>
    <rules>The full rules text could not be recovered from the source scan.</rules>
    <goldValue>?</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-weaponmaster-scroll" name="Weaponmaster Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior calls on the powers of the scroll to guide their hand as they move to strike down their enemies.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the Warrior bearing the scroll gets +2 Weapon Skill for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>150G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-whirlwind-staff" name="Whirlwind Staff">
    <flavor>The Wizard-warrior Oscurus the Intrepid carried this staff into the darkest dungeons of the Old World.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this staff, they get +1 Attack. Each time the wielder rolls a natural 6 To Hit with the staff the target is flung into the air, and crashes down into an unoccupied square (determined at random) on the same Board Section. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-white-wolf-cowl" name="White Wolf Cowl">
    <flavor>This cowl has been imbued with a mysterious energy during the rituals of a Norse shaman.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this cowl gets +1 Toughness (RPG: or +2 Toughness against any cold-based attacks). This cowl cannot be worn at the same time as a helmet. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>300G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-window-of-the-void-scroll" name="Window of the Void Scroll">
    <flavor>The scroll creates a dark portal that hypnotically attracts Monsters. The portal is created in any empty square within the bearer's Line of Sight. Roll 1D6 for each Monster adjacent to the portal. On a score of 1, 2, 3 or 4 that Monster stands its ground and may ignore the portal. On a roll of 5 or 6 the Monster is hypnotically attracted to the portal, steps through it and vanishes.</flavor>
    <rules>Once you have rolled for each adjacent Monster, the portal closes with a loud crack. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wines-of-bretonnia" name="Wines of Bretonnia">
    <flavor>The kingdom of Bretonnia is a lordly realm of knights and castles, barons and chivalry.</flavor>
    <rules>The Bretonnians are second only to the Elves of Ulthuan when it comes to the creation of fine wines, and their best vintages fetch a high price throughout the world. There are 1D6 unopened bottles of 100-year old wine, a spectacular find indeed! Each bottle is worth 100 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x100G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wings-of-power-scroll" name="Wings of Power Scroll">
    <flavor>Leathery wings sprout from the Warrior's back, lifting them into the air.</flavor>
    <rules>This scroll allows the Warrior bearing it to fly for one Turn. While airborne the Warrior may not make any attacks, and may not be attacked in hand-to-hand Combat. While in the air a Warrior moves normally and may ignore any ground-based obstacles such as chasms or pits. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>100G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wizard-s-staff" name="Wizard's Staff">
    <flavor>This ornate staff radiates with power.</flavor>
    <rules>If the Wizard wields the staff like a weapon, he gets +1 Toughness but suffers -1 To Hit. The Wizard may use the staff to re-roll the Power Phase roll once Per Adventure. The Wizard's Staff contains 1 point of Power, which the Wizard can use in the same way as his Power Tokens. (RPG: The Wizard may recharge the staff by visiting the Font of Power.) PERMANENT USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wood-carving-of-kislev" name="Wood Carving of Kislev">
    <flavor>The Kingdom of Kislev is famous for its history of horse warriors.</flavor>
    <rules>This masterfully wood-carved horse statue, decorated with tiny gemstones, hails from the war-driven nation of Kislev, and is worth 1D6x25 gold. DISCARD AFTER SALE</rules>
    <goldValue>1D6x25G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wood-elf-warpaint" name="Wood Elf Warpaint">
    <flavor>This magic paint is imbued with the power of Orion, giving an Elf even more agility and nimbleness during battle.</flavor>
    <rules>If an Elf smears this paint on their arms and face, any Monsters attacking them suffer -1 To Hit in hand-to-hand Combat and -2 To Hit with a missile weapon. Once applied, the paint lasts for one Combat. There is enough paint for 1D3 applications. Each unused application is worth 100 gold. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>1D3x100G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-wyvern-staff" name="Wyvern Staff">
    <flavor>This staff was made from the bones of a wyvern and the essence of the creature is said to still reside within.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wields this two-handed weapon gets +2 Toughness and causes +1 Wound but suffers -1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-zhen-s-left-gauntlet" name="Zhen's Left Gauntlet">
    <flavor>Zhen was a warrior from Cathay who played a significant role in expelling the Hobgoblin invaders.. The first Attack each Turn made against the wearer of this gauntlet suffers -1 To Hit. For one Turn per Adventure all Attacks against the wearer only hit on a natural 5 or 6 To Hit.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior wears both gauntlets, the first attacks suffers -2 To Hit and for one Turn per Adventure all Attacks made against them only hit on a natural 6. PERMANENT USE ONE TURN PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-dungeon-zhen-s-right-gauntlet" name="Zhen's Right Gauntlet">
    <flavor>Zhen was a warrior from Cathay who played a significant role in expelling the Hobgoblin invaders... The first Attack each Turn made against the wearer of this gauntlet suffers -1 To Hit. For one Turn per Adventure all Attacks against the wearer only hit on a natural 5 or 6 To Hit.</flavor>
    <rules>If a Warrior wears both gauntlets, the first attacks suffers -2 To Hit and for one Turn per Adventure all Attacks made against them only hit on a natural 6. PERMANENT USE ONE TURN PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>400G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-amulet-of-protection" name="Amulet of Protection">
    <flavor>This amulet glows with a reddish light and has the power to transmute the energy of its wearer.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this amulet gets +2 Toughness and may ignore any spell cast against them on a D6 roll of 6 (RPG: they get +1 Willpower and the Magic Resistance 6+ ability). To achieve this, the amulet saps the wearer's strength and agility. While wearing the amulet the Warrior suffers -1 Strength, -1 To Hit and -2 Initiative. Once donned, this amulet cannot be removed. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-amulet-of-resistance" name="Amulet of Resistance">
    <flavor>The soft, magical glow from this amulet betrays the fact that it is anything but ordinary. This amulet is worth 500 gold.</flavor>
    <rules>If used by a Witch Hunter, the amulet has 1D6 charges and each charge confers the Magic Resistance ability for one Turn. When the amulet is activated roll 1D6 for each spell cast against the bearer. On a score of 4, 5 or 6, the spell has no effect. (RPG: The amulet can be recharged (or ruined) at the Witch Hunters' Guild like other amulets the Witch Hunter has, but it will never be one that appears on the altar.) LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-aphreeta-s-box-of-tricks" name="Aphreeta's Box of Tricks">
    <flavor>This strange ornate box has no apparent lid.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may attempt to open this box during Combat by rolling 1D6. If the score is a 1, the box explodes and the Warrior suffers 3D6 Wounds. If the score is a 2 or 3, the box does not open but the Warrior may try again next Turn. If the score is a 4, 5 or 6, the box opens and beams of light shoot out toward the Warrior's foes. Every Monster in the Warrior's Line of Sight suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. Roll for each Monster separately. At the beginning of the next Adventure, the box mysteriously closes and can be used again. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE LASTS UNTIL EXPLODES</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-armour-of-dargan" name="Armour of Dargan">
    <flavor>The glow from this deep red armour lights up the area.</flavor>
    <rules>This armour makes the wearer harder to hit: they get +4 Toughness and any Monster attacking them suffers -1 To Hit unless using a Magic Weapon. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-armour-of-meteoric-iron" name="Armour of Meteoric Iron">
    <flavor>This armour looks pitted and dull, but it glows with a dim radiance that betrays its true nature.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this armour gets +3 Toughness. However, once worn it fuses to the Warrior's flesh and cannot be removed. Unfortunately, given its weight, it cannot be carried. It must be donned immediately or left where it is found. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-armour-of-taakan" name="Armour of Taakan">
    <flavor>This matt black suit of full armour has dull bronze battle runes engraved on the breastplate, arms and helm. It is said to be endowed with a life of its own, striking at the enemy no matter what its wearer intends.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this suit gets the benefits of Heavy Armour and a Warhelm (+5 Toughness, -1 Movement). Every time an enemy wounds the Warrior the armour retaliates and forces its wearer to strike back. Make a single Attack against the enemy that just hit them. Note that, if successful, this attack does not cause a Death-blow. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-armour-of-turiss" name="Armour of Turiss">
    <flavor>Turiss was a fearsome Warrior who had this armour enchanted to protect him against Necromantic Magic.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this armour gets +2 Toughness. In addition, roll 1D6 any time a Necromantic spell is cast against the wearer. If the score is a 4, 5 or 6, the spell has no effect. If the score is a 1, however, the armour is destroyed and must be discarded. LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-arrows-of-loren" name="Arrows of Loren">
    <flavor>These arrows were cut from the greatest trees in the forest of Loren and carefully crafted so that their flight is the truest of all.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using these arrows gets +2 To Hit. In addition, they ignore 1 point of Armour and cause +1 Wound. There are 3D6 arrows and each arrow may only be used once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>100G each</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-axe-of-blood" name="Axe of Blood">
    <flavor>This axe can overpower even the most steadfast Warrior.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this axe gets +1 Attack and +1 Strength. If Monsters are on the Board at the start of the Warriors' Phase, roll 1D6 to see how the Warrior reacts this Turn: 1 Insane! They attack the nearest Warrior, ignoring Pinning, and suffer -1 To Hit. Roll again next Turn. 2-5 Fury! They attack the nearest Monster but suffer -1 To Hit. Roll again next Turn adding +1 to the roll. 6 Control! The Warrior may fight as normal and need not roll again this Combat. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-axe-of-khemri" name="Axe of Khemri">
    <flavor>This magical axe was forged many centuries ago by the Priest Kings of the ancient realm of Khemnri. It is a mighty weapon with a pure white blade. When their kingdom fell, the axe was lost, presumed destroyed.</flavor>
    <rules>When using this Axe, the wilder may roll an extra dice for Damage and discard the lowest score. They then add their Strength to the score as normal. In addition, when used against Undead, the wielder gets +1 To Hit. (RPG: The abilities of this axe cannot be added to in any way, such as runes etc.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-axe-of-slaying" name="Axe of Slaying">
    <flavor>This axe was once wielded by the Dwarf Giant Slayer Umgrul</flavor>
    <rules>Grunnson at the final battle of Karak Azgal. For one Attack this axe automatically hits its target. Roll1D6 to determine the axe's Damage. If the score is a 1, the axe causes 1D6+Strength Wounds. If the score is a 2, the axe causes 2D6+Strength Wounds, and so on. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-bands-of-the-immortal" name="Bands of the Immortal">
    <rules>Upon donning these bracelets the Warrior feels a surge of tremendous power coursing through their veins. While a Warrior wears these bands, they get +1 Strength and +1 Toughness. In addition, once per Adventure one of the Warrior's regular Attacks causes Double Damage. The bands cannot be worn with any armour that gives the wearer more than +2 Toughness (RPG: until the wearer is Battel-level 4 or higher). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>2000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-bane-sword" name="Bane Sword">
    <flavor>As soon as it is drawn in the presence of its hated foe this blade snarls and growls, eager to spill blood.</flavor>
    <rules>Draw an Event Card until it reveals Monsters to determine what sort of Monsters the sword hates. (RPG: Roll on the Monster Table that is the same level as the Warrior's Battle-level). The sword causes Double Damage against all Monsters of that race. df you roll Skaven Assassins, for instance, the Bane Sword affects all Skaven.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-battle-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Battle Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Battle Stone of the Marquis. Any one of the Warrior's Attacks (but not a Death-blow) automatically hits the target. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-belt-of-gagron" name="Belt of Gagron">
    <flavor>This thick leather belt belonged to the Dwarf Gagron the Giantslayer who lived to a surprisingly ripe old age.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time the wearer of this belt is reduced to zero Wounds, roll 1D6 at the end of the Turn (as long as the Warrior has received no other form of healing during the Turn). On a score of 3, 4 or 5 the belt restores 1D6 Wounds. On a score of 6 the belt restores 2D6 Wounds. Once donned, the Belt of Gagron cannot be removed. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-blade-of-leaping-bronze" name="Blade of Leaping Bronze">
    <flavor>Ass soon as it is drawn this blade strikes with incredible speed.</flavor>
    <rules>While wielding this sword a Warrior gets +2 Attacks. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-blade-of-leaping-gold" name="Blade of Leaping Gold">
    <flavor>This blade Is superbly balanced and moves in a swift golden arc with almost no effort on the wielder's part, slicing through the enemy ranks with ease.</flavor>
    <rules>While wielding this sword a Warrior gets +3 Attacks. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-blazeshot-pistol" name="Blazeshot Pistol">
    <flavor>This pistol delivers a burning blast of shot can perforate even the most durable armour. This pistol is a missile weapon with Strength 6 and a Range of 6. It takes one Turn to reload after it has been fired.</flavor>
    <rules>Any shot fire from this pistol becomes so hot that it ignores all non-masgical Armour. There is enough gunpowder and shot to last one Adventure. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>DW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-blood-ring" name="Blood Ring">
    <flavor>A lustrous blood-red stone is mounted in the center of this ring.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time the wearer of this ring suffers Wounds, the ring absorbs one of the Wounds instead of the wearer. The ring can store a total number of Wounds equal to the wearer's Starting Wounds score. If there are no Monsters on the Board, the wearer can use as many of the stored Wounds as they would like to heal themselves. Once the ring is put on, it may not be removed. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-blood-sword" name="Blood Sword">
    <flavor>This ominous-looking longsword perpetually drips blood onto the floor. After any other attacks the Warrior using this sword makes each Turn, roll 1D6 for each model (Warriors as well as Monsters) in a square adjacent to them.</flavor>
    <rules>On a score of 6, the sword lashes out and strikes the target of its own volition, causing Damage as normal. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-book-of-arcane-knowledge" name="Book of Arcane Knowledge">
    <flavor>The pages of this aged book rustle with a life of their own. This book contains spells that a Wizard may cast. Take any Spell Cards not currently in play to represent the spells contained within the book. (RPG: Roll 4D6. These dice are used to buy spells for the book in the same way the Wizard gains spells when he goes up a Battle-level.)</flavor>
    <rules>Each spell may be cast once automatically at no Power cost. Once a spell has been cast that page of the book crumbles to dust. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-book-of-metamorphosis" name="Book of Metamorphosis">
    <flavor>This ancient book whispers the name of the Warrior who holds it in their hands.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior whose eyes fall upon the pages of this tome may improve either their Attack, Strength, Toughness, Weapon Skill, Ballistic Skill, Initiative, or Escape Pinning (RPG: or Luck or Willpower) Characteristic by 1, or they may add 1D6 to their Starting Wounds. This increase is permanent. A Warrior may only read a Book of Metamorphosis once in their lifetime. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>2000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-boots-of-flight" name="Boots of Flight">
    <flavor>These elegant boots float an inch or so off the ground, their outline shimmering with magical energy.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing these boots a Warrior may levitate a few inches above the ground while moving. While airborne the Warrior may pass over chasms, pits, etc. unhindered and anyone who attacks them suffers -1 To Hit. The boots last for one Adventure, after which they lose their magic and must be discarded. LASTS FOR ONE ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-bow-of-loren" name="Bow of Loren">
    <flavor>This slender bow was fashioned by the Wood Elves of Loren.</flavor>
    <rules>This bow is Strength 4. (RPG: It causes 1D6 Wounds per Battle- level of the wielder). If the Damage is sufficient to kill the target outright, and there is a Monster directly behind it in the direction the bow was fired, the arrow continues. Roll To Hit that Monster too. This process continues until there are no Monsters in the direct line of fire, or one of them survives, or the arrow misses. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>2000G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-bracelet-of-saphery" name="Bracelet of Saphery">
    <flavor>This slender, glittering bracelet is said to come from Saphery, created by the Elven Mages who dwelt there in ages past.</flavor>
    <rules>When the Warrior finds the bracelet, randomly select one of the Wizard's Starting Spell Cards. This spell is stored in the bracelet, and may be cast once automatically during the Adventure. (RPG: Before each Adventure randomly select one spell with a Casting Number that is equivalent to the Warrior's Battle-level. This spell may be cast automatically.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-brooch-of-power" name="Brooch of Power">
    <flavor>This brooch glows too brightly to look at, as if it contained the energy of a fallen star.</flavor>
    <rules>At the end of each Turn, the Wizard may store any unused Power that he has left over within the brooch. This stored Power may then be used at any time to in the same manner as the Wizard's Power Tokens. The brooch can hold a maximum of 6 Power (APG: 6 + Battle-level) at any one time. In addition, the bright aura cast by the brooch distracts any Monsters attacking the Wizard, so they suffer -1 To Hit him. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-century-bow" name="Century Bow">
    <flavor>Every hundred years this bow is passed on to an Elf who performs a great deed.</flavor>
    <rules>This Bow is Strength 3 and causes +1 Wound (RPG: +1 Wound per Battle-level). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-chalice-of-battle" name="Chalice of Battle">
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks from this black chalice finds their head filled with visions of war and conflict. A Warrior who drinks from the chalice gets +1 Attack, +1 To Hit and their attacks cause +1D6 Wounds for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-chalice-of-sorcery" name="Chalice of Sorcery">
    <flavor>This dull metal chalice seems wholely unremarkable. Rubbing away the grime of years reveals it to be a Chalice of Sorcery.</flavor>
    <rules>This chalice acts as a source of Power that allows the Wizard to carry on casting spells when his own Power has run out. The Wizard can try to draw as many points of Power out of the chalice as he likes. For every point of Power he draws, roll 1D6. All the extra Power must be drawn at once so all the dice are rolled at the same time. For each dice that scores a 1 the Wizard suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>700G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-chandra-s-mirror" name="Chandra's Mirror">
    <flavor>Lady Chandra de Celeone gave this mirror to the Bretonnian Knight Marius Rand who used it to defeat the Gorgon Thusela in her Black Mountains Lair.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time a Monster casts a spell on the Warrior holding this mirror roll 1D6. On a score of 6 the spell is rebounded back onto the caster. (RPG: In addition, any time a Monster with the Petrify ability rolls a natural 1 To Hit the bearer, roll 1D6. On a score of 3, 4, 5 or 6 the Monster's gaze is reflected back on itself and it suffers the full effects of its own gaze attack. If the Monster's Movement ever reaches zero due to this mirror, it turns to stone and is killed.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-citadel-helm" name="Citadel Helm">
    <flavor>A champion wore this helm to defend Estalia during an invasion from Araby.</flavor>
    <rules>The wearer of this helm gets +3 Toughness during the first round of each Combat, +2 Toughness during the second round of each Combat and +1 Toughness at all other times. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>700G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-cleats-of-cutback" name="Cleats of Cutback">
    <flavor>These cleats have been enchanted by a Wizard from the Colleges of Magic in Altdorf.</flavor>
    <rules>When worn by an Ex-Blood Bowl Player, these cleats allow him to change direction once when performing a Running Blitz Attack. They can only be sold at a Foote Locker in a Blood Bowl Stadium. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-cloak-of-darkness" name="Cloak of Darkness">
    <flavor>This dark cloak exudes trails of black smoke, making the wearer undetectable in a dark dungeon.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may conceal themselves with this cloak at the star of the Warriors' Phase. They cannot be attacked, but can do nothing else for the rest of the Turn. At the start of the next Turn, the wearer may make a special Ambush Attack against one adjacent Monster. They get +1 To Hit and cause Double Damage. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-cloak-of-invulnerability" name="Cloak of Invulnerability">
    <rules>When a Warrior puts this cloak on, a hazy sheen of magical protective power descends upon them. The first time that the wearer of this cloak is hit each Turn, roll 1D6. If the result is a 6, the Warrior is protected by the power of the cloak and the attack, whatever its origin, has no effect. When wearing this cloak, a Warrior cannot wear armour but they may wear a helmet and carry a shield. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-courage-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Courage Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Courage Stone of the Marquis. It is worth 500 gold. (RPG: A Warrior using the Courage Stone may automatically pass one Fear or Terror test.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-criscorra-s-crossbow" name="Criscorra's Crossbow">
    <flavor>Criscora, a sorceress from Stirland, created this crossbow to defend her residence from a legion of Undead.</flavor>
    <rules>Over 100 ghastly creatures fell before she was finally overrun. This Repeating Crossbow is Strength 3, a Range of 8 and can fire up to 2 shots per Turn. It uses no quarrels, firing magical bolts of energy instead. In addition, the first bolt fired in each Turn causes extra Wounds equal to the Power Phase roll ona successful hit. If the Power Phase roll is a 1, the crossbow cannot be fired that Turn. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-crown-of-sorcery" name="Crown of Sorcery">
    <flavor>As soon as they put this crown on, the wearer is plunged into the alien and dark world of magical power familiar to wizards. The wearer takes two Starting Spell Cards of each type at random: these are the spells they may cast just like the Wizard. They may now also use Wizard-only treasure and can still wear Armour.</flavor>
    <rules>Each Turn the Warrior gets to cast one or more of their spells just like the Wizard. Each time they cast one of their spells roll1D6. If the score is a 1 that spell fails and the Warrior is immobilised. They can do nothing for the rest of the Turn and any Attacks made against them hit on anything buta 1. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-crown-of-thoughts" name="Crown of Thoughts">
    <flavor>This battered crown is a powerful magic artefact.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this crown can detect hostile vibrations in the atmosphere, and is seldom surprised. When Monsters appear who would normally Ambush the Warriors, the wearer should roll 1D6: 1-3. Ambushed as normal. 4-5 The Warrior parries any blows made against them. The Monsters' Ambush Attacks have no effect. 6 As 4-5, and the Warrior gets an extra Attack before the Monsters strike, in addition to any others they may have that Turn. All the other Warriors are ambushed as usual. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-dawnstone" name="Dawnstone">
    <flavor>This crystal-like stone is mounted in a black iron brooch and radiates a pale light like that of the early morning.</flavor>
    <rules>The Dawnstone may be used to restore any one Warrior to full Wounds immediately, even if they are on zero Wounds or died several Turns ago. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-deck-of-destiny" name="Deck of Destiny">
    <flavor>Neatly wrapped inside a piece of cloth is a deck of mysterious cards.</flavor>
    <rules>This rare deck will fetch 600 gold from the right collector. (RPG: A Warrior may draw one of these cards just before travelling to a Settlement by rolling 1D6. If the score is a 1, the card symbolises misfortune and they must deduct 1 from all rolls made for Travelling Hazards and Settlement Events. If the score is 2, 3, 4 or 5 the card represents protection and they may add +1 to all rolls for Travelling Hazards. If the score is a 6, as per 2-5 above, but the Warrior may also add +1 to all rolls made for Settlement Events.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-dragon-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Dragon Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Dragon Stone of the Marquis. A Warrior using the Dragon Stone gets +1D6 Toughness for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-dragon-sword" name="Dragon Sword">
    <flavor>This blade is fashioned from the venom fang of a Great Fire Dragon and is ancient beyond ail telling. This sword causes Double Damage on a natural To Hit roll of 5 or 6. However, the sword is partially sentient and refuses to be drawn from its scabbard by unworthy Warriors. At the start of each Turn the wielder wants to use the sword, roll 1D6.</flavor>
    <rules>On a roll of 1, 2 or 3 the sword refuses to leave its scabbard. (RPG: It will not let itself be used by Warriors of Battle-level 3 or below.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-elf-bow" name="Elf Bow">
    <flavor>This fine weapon is exquisitely carved and possesses a strength far above that of any other bow.</flavor>
    <rules>While using this bow a Warrior may make as many shots per Turn as they have Attacks, at their full Strength. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1200G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-elf-helm" name="Elf Helm">
    <flavor>A fine Elf helm. Light but surprisingly strong.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this helm gets +1 Toughness. When hit, the wearer may elect to take the blow on the head by rolling 1D6: 1 The Elf Helm absorbs all the Damage from the blow, but is destroyed in the process. 2-4 Resolve the blow as normal. 5-6 The blow glances off, causing no Damage. LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-elf-shield" name="Elf Shield">
    <flavor>This finely crafted shield glitters with an unearthly sheen.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using the Elf Shield gets +1 Toughness. In addition, the bearer can ignore the Damage from the first blow they take each Turn unless the attacker's To Hit roll was a natural 6. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-elven-armour" name="Elven Armour">
    <flavor>This amour looks extremely delicate but is amongst the most effective protection in the known world.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this armour, a Warrior gets +1 Toughness. In addition, if any of the attacker's Damage Dice score an unmodified 1 or 2, ignore these dice when resolving the Damage. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>2000G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-enchanted-great-shield" name="Enchanted Great Shield">
    <flavor>The surface of this shield gleams as brightly as a mirror. Clouds roll across its surface, and shards of light cut the air around it.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this shield gets +3 Toughness but may not use any other Armour, except for a helmet (RPG: until the wearer is Battle-level 4 or above). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-enchanted-jade-amulet" name="Enchanted Jade Amulet">
    <flavor>This amulet resembles a stone worn smooth by the action of the sea.</flavor>
    <rules>This amulet has the power to heal wounds Each time the wearer uses the amulet roll 1D6: 1 The amulet crumbles to dust and the Warrior suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. 2 The amulet has no effect. 3-6 The Warrior has 1 Wound (RPG: 1 Wound per Battle- level) restored. The amulet fails to work while the Warrior wearing it is on zero Wounds. USE ONCE PER TURN LASTS UNTIL DESTROYED</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-fireball-wand" name="Fireball Wand">
    <flavor>The gems set into the crown of this wand glow with a flickering light.</flavor>
    <rules>Pick a 2 square by 2 square area of the Board Section within the Warrior's Line of Sight. Each Monster in that area suffers 1D6+3 Wounds. When found, the wand has a single charge. (RPG: At the start of each Adventure, the wand will have 1D3 charges. Charges not used by the end of the Adventure are lost.) 1D3 CHARGES PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-firestorm-icon" name="Firestorm Icon">
    <flavor>This shard of crystal has a raging fire burning at its core, which flares up to a blazing wall of fire at the wielder's command. Pick a 2 square by 2 square area within the Warrior's Line of Sight. All Monsters in the targeted area suffer 6D6 Wounds Croll once for all the Monsters), with no modifiers for anything.</flavor>
    <rules>USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>2000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-flail-of-decimation" name="Flail of Decimation">
    <flavor>Brynjar Thundmoor was a Norse warrior renowned for his ability with this flail. It is said that the enchantment in it evolved from his constant battles against wicked foes.</flavor>
    <rules>While wielding this flail, a Warrior gets +2 Strength, +1 To Hit and causes +1D6 Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-frostblade" name="Frostblade">
    <flavor>This pale metallic blue weapon exudes a freezing aura and its blade glitters like ice.</flavor>
    <rules>When wielding the Frostblade the Warrior may only make 1 Attack per Turn. If the Warrior makes a successful Attack with the Frostblade that causes at least 1 point of Damage (after all deductions and Special Abilities), the target is automatically slain. A blow from a Frostblade cannot cause a Death-blow. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-gauntlets-of-soul-rending" name="Gauntlets of Soul Rending">
    <flavor>These cold steel gauntlets have been steeped in powerful magic, and are able to tear the life essence from their victim.</flavor>
    <rules>With these gauntlets, a Warrior may make an extra Attack every Turn, which must be made before the Warrior makes any other Attacks. The Attack with the Gauntlets suffers -1 To Hit and causes normal Damage. (RPG: The first time that the Warrior kills a Monster with these gauntlets in every Adventure, roll 1D6. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 they add +1 Wound to their Starting Wounds score permanently.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-gems-of-life" name="Gems of Life">
    <flavor>These small gems sparkle with a strange, otherworldly energy. This pair of gems is worth 700 gold. (RPG: One of these gems should be worn while the other is kept in a safe place away from the Dungeon. If the wearer is killed, shortly after their death their body starts to dwindle in size until it is a pinprick of light contained with the gem. The only things left behind are mundane items such as bandages, the Lantern or a rope.</flavor>
    <rules>If the other Warriors survive the rest of the Dungeon and bring the two gems back together, their magical power recalls the dead Warrior, alive and well, just as they were before the Adventure started.) USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>700G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-glacier-axe" name="Glacier Axe">
    <flavor>A magical, freezing sheet of ice envelops a portion of this axe.</flavor>
    <rules>Each time a Warrior wounds a target with this axe, roll 1D6. If the score is equal to or greater than the target's Toughness, it suffers an additional 1D3 Wounds and is encased in a sarcophagus of ice and may not move or fight. While entombed, the target cannot be attacked. Roll 1D6 at the beginning of the next Monsters' Phase. If the score is greater than the target's Toughness, the target suffers another 1D3 Wounds and remains encased. If the score is less than the target's Toughness, then the ice melts and the target is free. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-gladiator-belt" name="Gladiator Belt">
    <flavor>A metal skull acts as the clasp for this studded belt.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this belt a Warrior gets +1 Strength. If worn by a Pit Fighter, he also gets +1 Attack. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>700G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-gold-sigil-sword" name="Gold Sigil Sword">
    <flavor>Golden runes gleam on this blade, granting the wielder the first chance to strike.</flavor>
    <rules>While wielding this sword, a Warrior will always go first in the Warriors' Phase unless another rule specifies otherwise. In addition, the wielder may add +2 to their roll to Escape from Pinning. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-gravesword" name="Gravesword">
    <flavor>This sword feels as light as wood but is more powerful than regular steel.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior is using this word they get +1 To Hit against any Undead creature. In addition, once per Adventure it causes +3D6 Wounds to one Undead creature. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-greater-antidote" name="Greater Antidote">
    <flavor>The liquid in this bottle is thin like water and has a floral aroma.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this potion has 1D6 Wounds restored. (RPG: In addition, a Warrior who drink this antidote will restore all the points to their Characteristics that had previously been reduced for any reason. This potion cannot restore Wounds that have been permanently reduced.) USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-gromril-blade" name="Gromril Blade">
    <flavor>This mighty axe is a Dwarf artefact, able to cut through all but the most powerful armour.</flavor>
    <rules>This two-handed axe ignores non-Magical Armour and causes Double Damage. However, the axe is partially sentient and refuses to be drawn by unworthy Warriors. At the start of each Turn that the bearer wishes to use it, roll 1D6. On a roll of 1 or 2 the axe cannot be drawn. (APG: It will not let itself be used by Warriors of Battle-level 2 or below.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1200G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-halberd-of-defiance" name="Halberd of Defiance">
    <flavor>This halberd was created by the High Elves of Ulthuan to defend against the constant raids from Naggaroth.</flavor>
    <rules>When wielding this two-handed weapon in Combat a Warrior gets +1 Strength, +3 Toughness and may attack from up to 2 squares away in hand-to-hand Combat. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-halberd-of-hatred" name="Halberd of Hatred">
    <flavor>An aura of deep hatred surrounds this wicked halberd.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this two-handed weapon gets +2 Strength and may attack from up to 2 squares away in hand-to-hand Combat. If used against Orcs, the wielder gets double their regular Attacks but is so full of rage that they suffer -1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hammer-of-shattering" name="Hammer of Shattering">
    <flavor>A magical rune of an anvil has been emblazoned upon this hammer.</flavor>
    <rules>The Hammer ignores non-magical Armour. In addition, if the To Hit roll is a 6, the target's Armour is destroyed! If the target's Armour is magical, however, roll another 1D6. On a 6 the magical Armour is destroyed. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>900G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hammer-of-sigmar" name="Hammer of Sigmar">
    <flavor>This weapon was given to the legendary hero Sigmar by King</flavor>
    <rules>Kurgan Ironbeard, to cement an alliance between Dwarfs and Men. It is perhaps the most ancient and revered of all the magic weapons in the Empire. The Hammer of Sigmar ignores all except Magical Armour when rolling for Damage. In addition, if the To Hit roll was a natural 6, it causes Quadruple Damage. There can only ever be one Hammer of Sigmar in the party. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>2000G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hammer-of-spite" name="Hammer of Spite">
    <flavor>This Hammer seeks certain Monsters, to be slain at all costs.</flavor>
    <rules>Choose a Monster as it is placed on the Board as the hammer's hated foe. If there is an empty space adjacent to that Monster, the wielder of the hammer may be placed in that space, no matter how far away or what Monsters intervene. The Warrior gets an immediate Ambush Attack against that Monster, and gains +1 Attack every Turn against that Monster until it is dead. If the wielder kills the Monster, they gain double its Gold Value. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hell-bird" name="Hell Bird">
    <flavor>This two-handed weapon has been suffused with the skin shed by a Coatl, a mystical creature from the land of Lustria.</flavor>
    <rules>While wielding the Hell Bird, in addition to their regular Attacks, a Warrior may leap into the air to make an extra Death Chop Attack into an adjacent square. Roll To Hit as normal. If the Attack hits, then the model in that square, as well as any model in the square directly behind it suffers Damage as normal Croll separately for each modelO&gt; The Death Chop may not cause a Death-blow. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hellfire-sword" name="Hellfire Sword">
    <flavor>Flames leap and burn along the length of this other-worldly sword. As it swings through the air it leaves a trail of spitting magma in its wake.</flavor>
    <rules>If the wielder hits their opponent with a natural To Hit roll of 6, as well as causing normal Damage the target and all adjacent models to the target (including the wielder!) burst into flames and take an extra 1D6+1 (RPG: 1D6 + Battle-level) Wounds, with no modifiers for Toughness or Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-helm-of-alcadizzar" name="Helm of Alcadizzar">
    <flavor>This glittering helmet was worn by Alcadizzar as he rode into battle against the Undead hordes.</flavor>
    <rules>It is said that the helm had the magic ability to store the light of the sun, and the Undead would flee in terror from the blazing figure of Alcadizzar as he galloped across the battlefield. This helm illuminates the area allowing the wearer to explore just as if they carried the Lantern. In addition, they get +1 Toughness, and any Undead attacking them suffer -1 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-helm-of-blitzing" name="Helm of Blitzing">
    <flavor>The wings fashioned on this helm have been deliberately sharpened.</flavor>
    <rules>While wearing this helmet a Warrior gets +1 Toughness. In addition, if worn by an Ex-Blood Bowl Player, he causes an extra +1D3 Wounds on each successful hit during a Running Blitz Attack. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-helm-of-farseeing" name="Helm of Farseeing">
    <flavor>This black helm has no apparent visor, yet it imparts upon the wearer the ability to see clearly even in the dim light of a dungeon.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears this helm gets +1 Toughness. In addition, this helmet allows the wearer to see in the dark and explore just as if they carried the Lantern. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-helm-of-possession" name="Helm of Possession">
    <flavor>From within the depths of this ugly helm, the Warrior's eyes stare out with an otherworldly intensity.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this helm gets +1 Toughness. In addition, once per Turn, the Warrior wearing the helm may attempt to hypnotise any one Monster that is within their Line of Sight. Roll 1D6. On a score of 6, the Monster is hypnotised for one Turn. Whilst hypnotised, the Monster loses 1D6 Attacks. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hero-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Hero Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Hero Stone of the Marquis. A Warrior using the Hero Stone gets +1D3 Attacks for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-holy-stake-and-hammer" name="Holy Stake &amp; Hammer">
    <flavor>These wooden tools were cut from the branches of a sacred tree, hardened in a holy flame and blessed by a priest of Sigmar.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Adventure, a Warrior adjacent to a Vampire in Combat may attempt to use the stake to slay the creature. Roll 1D6. If the score is a natural 6, the Warrior manages to strike the creature directly in the heart and it dies immediately. This roll cannot be affected by Luck, Faith or any other means. DISCARD AFTER SUCCESSFUL USE (From 'Vampire Slayers' Adventure)</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-horn-of-defiance" name="Horn of Defiance">
    <flavor>This bronze horn shines as if it was recently polished.</flavor>
    <rules>When blown, the magical power of this horn allows all the Warriors to parry incoming blows. When a Warrior is attacked in hand-to-hand Combat, roll 1D6. On a score of 6 they turn the blow and it causes no Damage (RPG: They gain the Parry 6+ ability). The effect lasts until the Combat ends, or a 1 is rolled in the Power Phase. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-horn-of-vengeance" name="Horn of Vengeance">
    <flavor>As this horn is blown a howling wind tosses the Monsters to the ground.</flavor>
    <rules>When a Warrior blows this horn. roll 1D6 for every Monster on the same Board Section. If the score is more than the Monster's Toughness, it is hurled to the ground and suffers 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for Armour. It will take a Monster a whole Turn to get up. During this time it may do nothing else. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-hydra-sword" name="Hydra Sword">
    <flavor>Steeped in the blood of a hydra as it was forged, this blade has taken on some of the properties of these terrible beasts.</flavor>
    <rules>For one Attack, this blade causes +6D6 Wounds. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>850G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-lantern-of-revelation" name="Lantern of Revelation">
    <flavor>This lantern is more than a light source...</flavor>
    <rules>When activated, this magical lantern can be used just like the leader's Lantern. In addition, the bearer can never be ambushed by Monsters. At the end of each Combat, the bearer may roll 1D6. On a score of 6, they receive an extra Dungeon Room Treasure which does not count toward their share. (RPG: The bearer may also add +1 to any rolls to find secret doors). The lantern draws power from whoever carries it. If the Power Phase roll is a 1, the bearer must roll 1D6. If the result is a 1 or 2, the bearer must subtract 1 from their Starting Wounds score permanently. The lantern cannot be turned off until the bearer exits the Dungeon. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-left-gauntlet-of-damzhar" name="Left Gauntlet of Damzhar">
    <flavor>This thick iron gauntlet is covered with studs in the shape of Dwarf runes.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears the Left Gauntlet of Damzhar gets +1 Strength, as well as +1 Attack with the weapon they hold in the gauntlet. If a Warrior wears both Gauntlets of Damzhar, they get a total of +2 Strength and +1 Attack for each weapon they wield (or +2 Attacks if holding a two-handed weapon). In addition, once per Adventure, they gain a special Gauntlet Attack that gets +1 To Hit and causes 4D6 Damage (do not add Strength to the score). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-life-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Life Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt Cone finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Life Stone of the Marquis. The bearer can use this magical stone at any time to ignore the Damage from a single blow that would otherwise kill them. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-lifestone-of-ashraaz" name="Lifestone of Ashraaz">
    <flavor>Ashraaz was one of the insane sorcerers of Araby. Fables tell that he created mystical stones which sucked the essence of life from the air itself.</flavor>
    <rules>Each Turn the bearer may use the Lifestone to restore 1D3 Wounds, so long as the Warrior is on 1 or more Wounds when they choose to use it. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-lightning-spear" name="Lightning Spear">
    <flavor>Bolts of energy streak up and down the blade of this two- handed spear.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may throw this spear as a missile weapon (Range 4, may be retrieved at the end of Combat) or may use it to attack from up to 2 squares away in hand-to-hand Combat. If the To Hit roll is a 6, then the target suffers an additional 2D6 Lightning Damage (no modifiers for Armour). Roll another 1D6. If the score is a 5 or 6, the bolt arcs to the next nearest Monster and hits it for 2D6 Wounds (no modifiers for Armour). This process continues until the bolt fails to arc. A Monster may not be hit a subsequent time. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>900G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-mending-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Mending Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Wizard from</flavor>
    <rules>Bretonnian. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Mending Stone of the Marquis. A Warrior using the Mending Stone is restored to full Wounds. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-mirror-of-imprisonment" name="Mirror of Imprisonment">
    <flavor>Carvings of tormented souls line the frame of this mirror.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Combat a Warrior may show this mirror to an adjacent Monster by rolling 1D6. If the score is equal to or greater than the Monster's Toughness, it becomes trapped inside the mirror and is removed from the Board. At the start of each Turn thereafter, roll 1D6. If the score is a 1 or 2, the Monster escapes and is placed next to the Warrior with the mirror (moving models as necessary). It receives an immediate attack against the Warrior, and then attacks as normal in the Monsters' Phase. The bearer can shatter the mirror at any time whereupon any Monster inside is killed. The Warriors do not receive any gold for a Monster killed in this manner. USE ONCE PER COMBAT LASTS UNTIL SHATTERED</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-net-of-curtailment" name="Net of Curtailment">
    <flavor>This magic-imbued and restrain even the strongest creatures!</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may throw this net at a single Monster up to 2 squares away by rolling 1D6 (a Pit Fighter may add +1 to the roll). If the score is a 4, 5 or 6, the target is netted for the rest of the Combat and suffers -1 To Hit. Any Warrior attacking a netted Monster gets +1 To Hit it. The net may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>B</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-orb-of-divination" name="Orb of Divination">
    <flavor>Strange images flash inside this crystal and the Warriors swear that they caught a glimpse of themselves.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior can use this orb to see what is beyond each Doorway on the current Board Section. This includes drawing Dungeon or Event Cards and rolling on any tables or sub-tables as a result. If the Warriors choose to enter those new Board Sections, they must roll 1D6. If the score is a 1, the orb was wrong and the Warriors must interact with the Board Section anew. If the score is 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, then the orb was accurate and they must play it as it was foretold. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-pistol-and-shot" name="Pistol &amp; Shot">
    <flavor>Nestled within an engraved wooden box, this pistol looks as expensive as it does deadly.</flavor>
    <rules>The pistol is a missile weapon with Strength 6 and a Range of 6. It takes one Turn to reload after it has been fired. The pistol comes with enough gunpowder and shot to last for for one Adventure. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>DW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-power-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Power Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Wizard from</flavor>
    <rules>Bretonnian. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Power Stone of the Marquis. A Warrior using the Power Stone gets +1D6 to their Strength for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-quarg-foot-talisman" name="Quarg Foot Talisman">
    <flavor>This curious talisman brings rare bouts of good fortune to its wearer.</flavor>
    <rules>This talisman is worth 500 gold. (RPG: The power of this talisman can be invoked during a single stay at a Settlement. It allows the bearer to re-roll one Settllement Event per day, but they must accept the second result, even if it's worse. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-quarrels-of-agony" name="Quarrels of Agony">
    <flavor>The tips of these vicious quarrels are designed to cause as much injury as possible.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using these quarrels gets +1 To Hit. In addition, they cause Double Damage if the To Hit roll is a natural 6. There are 2D6 quarrels. Each quarrel may be used only once. DISCARD WHEN ALL USED</rules>
    <goldValue>100G each</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-rending-sword" name="Rending Sword">
    <flavor>The serrated points along the cutting edge of this blade grind and gnash together like teeth, tearing through armour, flesh and bone.</flavor>
    <rules>This sword causes +2D6 Wounds. In addition, if the To Hit roll was a natural 5 or 6, the blow ignores 2 points of Armour. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1200G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-restore-flesh-scroll" name="Restore Flesh Scroll">
    <flavor>Sprinkling a mixture of earth and water, the Warrior bearing the scroll casts a magical enchantment that reverts stone back to flesh.</flavor>
    <rules>This spell may be cast on a single Warrior who has been turned to stone. The Warrior returns to normal but must roll 1D6. If the result is a 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6, then the Warrior suffers no lasting effects from the petrification. If the score is a 1, however, then the Warrior must deduct 1D3 from their Starting Wounds _ score permanently. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-right-gauntlet-of-damzhar" name="Right Gauntlet of Damzhar">
    <flavor>This thick iron gauntlet is covered with studs in the shape of Dwarf runes.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who wears the Right Gauntlet of Damzhar gets +1 Strength, as well as +1 Attack with the weapon they hold in the gauntlet. If a Warrior wears both Gauntlets of Damzhar, they get a total of +2 Strength and +1 Attack for each weapon they wield (or +2 Attacks if holding a two-handed weapon). In addition, once per Adventure, they gain a special Gauntlet Attack that gets +1 To Hit and causes 4D6 Damage (do not add Strength to the score). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BD</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ring-of-cheshnakk" name="Ring of Cheshnakk">
    <flavor>Cheshnakk was a great wizard from Araby whose expertise was the creation of exquisite flying carpets.</flavor>
    <rules>The pinnacle of his achievement, however, was forging the Rings of Cheshnakk. On command, one of these rings can transport the bearer to safety. This exquisite and mysterious ring is worth 1000 gold. (RPG: While wearing this ring a Warrior may at any time leave the Dungeon and be transported to safety. They are out of this Adventure and meet the other Warriors at the next Settlement.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ring-of-immunity" name="Ring of Immunity">
    <flavor>This ring has two crystal hands clutching a gold nugget that emits a soft, warm glow.</flavor>
    <rules>While a Warrior wears this ring, they may ignore the effects of any diseases they carry. (RPG: In addition, if the rules ever state that the bearer is affected by Paralysis, Petrify, Poison, or Fatal Damage, roll 1D6. If the score is a 5 or 6, the bearer is immune to the effects.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ring-of-orion" name="Ring of Orion">
    <flavor>This golden ring is said to be imbued with the power of Orion, the King of the Woods.</flavor>
    <rules>The bearer of this ring gets +2 Strength. (RPG: If the bearer must ever subtract a point permanently from one of their Characteristics (due to Poison for example), it may be deducted from the ring instead. The ring now only gives the bearer +1 Strength and is worth only 250 gold. If the ring is used a second time, it is drained and becomes useless and worthless.) DISCARD WHEN DRAINED</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ring-of-regeneration" name="Ring of Regeneration">
    <flavor>This stone band holds the power of life itself, healing even the most grievous of wounds.</flavor>
    <rules>At the end of any Turn in which the wearer of this ring has suffered Wounds, they may attempt to heal by regenerating with the ring. To do this, roll 1D6. If they are currently above zero Wounds, then on a score of 6 they have 2D6 Wounds restored. If they are on zero Wounds, then on a score of 6 they have 1D6 Wounds restored. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>650G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ring-of-seeking" name="Ring of Seeking">
    <flavor>This glittering ring is fashioned from a material that looks like quicksilver.</flavor>
    <rules>When worn, the ring constantly shifts and changes like a shining, liquid-metal band. This ring allows the Warrior to attempt to avoid a trap they have just activated. Roll 1D6. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the trap is magically disarmed and fails to work. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ring-of-the-warp" name="Ring of the Warp">
    <flavor>This black ring constantly moves from finger to finger, blinking and shimmering with an unholy light. Instead of moving normally, the wearer may use the ring to teleport. They must declare that they are using the ring before they move. Roll 1D6. The result shows how many squares they may move by teleporting. The Warrior must move to an empty square. If there is no empty square, the Warrior must stay where they are and can do nothing for the rest of the Turn.</flavor>
    <rules>When teleporting, the Warrior ignores any obstacles and automatically Escapes from Pinning. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-rockjaw-s-axe" name="Rockjaw's Axe">
    <flavor>Rockjaw Sevenfingers was famous for eating stonebread and throwing axes. It is said that after he had this magical axe created, it took him three unfortunate attempts to master it.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wielding this axe gets +1 Strength. It can be used in hand-to-hand Combat or as a missile weapon. If thrown as a missile weapon the axe will return to the Warrior. After resolving the attack, roll 1D6. On a score of 3, 4, 5 or 6 the Warrior catches the axe safely. On a 1 or 2 the Warrior cuts themselves while catching the axe and suffer 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers for anything. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>D</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-ruby-chalice" name="Ruby Chalice">
    <flavor>This silver chalice is covered in tear-dropped shaped rubies.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior may drink from this chalice any time during Combat. If they then suffer Wounds from a Monster for any reason, the Warrior immediately gets +1 Toughness. If they suffer Wounds again, the Warrior gets an additional +1 Toughness, and so on up to a maximum of +3 Toughness. The effects of the chalice last until the end of the Combat or until the Warrior is reduced to zero Wounds. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>850G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-rune-of-annihilation" name="Rune of Annihilation">
    <flavor>This stone has a Dwarf rune embossed upon its surface and is warm to the touch.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Annihilation into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Annihilation itself is permanent. If the To Hit roll with this weapon is a natural 6, the weapon causes +2D6 Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-rune-of-restoration" name="Rune of Restoration">
    <flavor>This stone has a Dwarf rune embossed upon its surface and is warm to the touch.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the runestone burns a Rune of Restoration into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Restoration itself is permanent. A Warrior who wields this weapon automatically has 1 Wound restored at the end of each Turn. It fails to work while the bearer is on zero Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-sceptre-of-zandri" name="Sceptre of Zandri">
    <flavor>The Sceptre of Zandri protects its wielder from the baneful gaze of the Undead, making them harder to hit.</flavor>
    <rules>The Sceptre may be wielded like a weapon, and causes +1D6 Wounds against any Undead. In addition, any Undead attacking the wielder suffer -2 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-shield-scroll" name="Shield Scroll">
    <flavor>Shouting words of power, the Warrior bearing the scroll is surrounded with a glowing screen of magical energy.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, the Warrior bearing the scroll is immune to all attacks except those made with either a natural 6 To Hit or from spells (or similar magic) for one Turn. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-shield-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Shield Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Shield Stone of the Marquis. A Warrior using the Shield Stone may ignore the effects of any one spell cast against them. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-shield-of-ptolos" name="Shield of Ptolos">
    <flavor>This shield throws a shimmering haze around its bearer, making them a difficult target in battle.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior using this shield gets +2 Toughness. In addition, when drawing Warrior Counters to determine who has been hit by missile fire, the first time the bearer's counter is pulled out they may put it back and draw again. If it comes up a second time they are hit as normal. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-spear-of-light-scroll" name="Spear of Light Scroll">
    <flavor>The Warrior hurls a spear of pure energy at their chosen victim.</flavor>
    <rules>When used, any single Monster in the bearer's Line of Sight immediately suffers 4D6 Wounds. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>DEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-speed-stone-of-le-marquis" name="Speed Stone of Le Marquis">
    <flavor>Michel d'un Doigt (one finger) was a powerful Bretonnian</flavor>
    <rules>Wizard. He laboured long to create a series of enchanted artefacts to be used by the chivalric knights of that realm. Unfortunately, the essential ingredient in the creation of each Was powdered bone from a human finger. Michel created nine in all... This is the fabled Speed Stone of the Marquis. A Warrior using the Speed Stone gets +2 Movement and may automatically Escape from Pinning for one Turn. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-spelleater-rune" name="Spelleater Rune">
    <flavor>This rune contains powerful spells of negation. Magic in the immediate vicinity arcs as the rune tries to pull it in and absorb it.</flavor>
    <rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the Spelleater Rune burns a copy of itself into the blade and then vanishes. The rune on the blade itself is permanent. Each time a spell is cast against the bearer of this weapon, roll 1D6. If the score is a 5 or 6, the spell has no effect on them (RPG: the wielder gets the Magic Resistance 5+ ability). USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BDW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-spirit-robe" name="Spirit Robe">
    <flavor>This robe shimmers with an eerie dark purple glow.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior wearing this robe becomes ethereal upon command. They may automatically Escape from Pinning and may move freely through other models and obstacles. Any attacks made with a non-magical weapon against the wearer suffer -1 To Hit. The effects last for one Turn. The Spirit Robe may not be worn with any helmet or armour. USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-staff-of-command" name="Staff of Command">
    <flavor>This staff had runes of command burned into it many centuries ago.</flavor>
    <rules>Once per Event the Wizard may use this staff to attempt to control any Monster on the Board. The attempt must be made as the Monsters appear. Roll 1D6. On a score of 5 or 6 the Wizard may choose one Monster and make it do whatever he wants for one Turn as long as the action does not cause it to harm itself. The Monster fights in the Warriors' Phase and if it kills another Monster, no one gets the gold. USE ONCE PER EVENT</rules>
    <goldValue>900G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-staff-of-silencing" name="Staff of Silencing">
    <flavor>This staff was created by a mage to protect his village against the repeated attacks from Chaos Dwarfs.</flavor>
    <rules>Any Chaos Dwarf Sorcerer who attempts to cast a spell while on the same Board Section as the wielder of this staff must roll 1D6. If the result is a 5 or 6, the spell has no effect. The staff can be used as a weapon, causing Damage as normal. If used against a Chaos Dwarf, the wielder gets +1 To Hit and causes +1D6 Wounds. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1200G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-super-supplement" name="Super Supplement">
    <flavor>The thin purple liquid in this vial can promote a strong vitality.</flavor>
    <rules>A Warrior who drinks this liquid may add +1 to their Starting Wounds score permanently. If an Ex-Blood Bowl Player drinks it, he may add +1D3 to his Starting Wounds score permanently. USE ONCE THEN DISCARD</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-surefire-bow" name="Surefire Bow">
    <flavor>This elegant bow has a single Rune of Surefire carved on it.</flavor>
    <rules>Ancient stories tell of a bow that never misses and this may be that very weapon... This bow is Strength 4. A Warrior using this bow gets +2 To Hit. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>900G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-sword-of-avelorn" name="Sword of Avelorn">
    <flavor>A dying High Elf Mage imbued this sword with a desire for vengeance against his killers.</flavor>
    <rules>This sword causes Double Damage against Dark Elves (Triple Damage if the To Hit roll is a natural 6). Against any other opponent it causes only +1 Wound. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1500G</goldValue>
    <users>E</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-sword-of-destruction" name="Sword of Destruction">
    <flavor>This sword resonates with a deep hum and flickers with lightning.</flavor>
    <rules>When drawn from its scabbard, this sword nullifies all magic within 1 square of the wielder. As long as the sword remains drawn, the wielder and any models in adjacent squares cannot use or benefit from any spells or other magic items. In addition, the sword causes +1 Wound (APG: and gives the bearer the Magic Dispel 6+ ability). PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-sword-of-heroes" name="Sword of Heroes">
    <flavor>This sword shines with the undimming fire of righteousness - smiting down evil wherever it may be found.</flavor>
    <rules>This sword causes an extra +3D6 Wounds when used against Monsters with a Toughness of 6 or more. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>900G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-sword-of-hoeth" name="Sword of Hoeth">
    <flavor>This sword was forged in Hoeth, in the realm of the High Elves. It is lightning fast and, once mastered, makes the wielder all but unstoppable in battle.</flavor>
    <rules>When using this sword a Warrior must roll 1D6 each Turn. On a score of 5 or 6 they gain double their regular Attacks. On a score of 2, 3 or 4 they attack as normal. On a score of 1 the Warrior trips and falls over and may do nothing at all for the rest of the Turn. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-sword-of-vengeance" name="Sword of Vengeance">
    <flavor>This blade shines with a pure light and never dulls.</flavor>
    <rules>Attacks made with this sword ignore Toughness and non- Magical Armour when determining Damage. In addition, once per Turn the wielder can re-roll one Attack with the sword that missed. PERMANENT USE ONCE PER TURN</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>BW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-tablet-of-adain" name="Tablet of Adain">
    <flavor>This stone table weighs surprisingly little and is covered in indecipherable hatchings and markings. This magical tablet is worth 1000 gold. (RPG: When used by a Wizard, the tablet allows them to re-roll any or all of his 'spell determining' dice each time he goes up a Battle-level (see New Spells in the Wizards' Training section).</flavor>
    <rules>They may only re-roll each dice once and must take the result of the second roll, even if it is worse.) PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1000G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-talisman-of-jet" name="Talisman of Jet">
    <flavor>This glittering black jewel feels warm to the touch. This talisman allows a Wizard to exchange one of the spells he has learned for a new one.</flavor>
    <rules>If he wants to exchange one of his spells, roll 1D6. On a score of 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6 he may exchange the spell he doesn't want for another of the same type. Select the new spell at random. (RPG: If he wishes to exchange one of his spells for another, roll 1D6. On a score of 1 the talisman crumbles to dust and must be discarded. On a score of 2, 3, 4, 5 or 6 the Wizard may exchange one of his spells for one of the same Casting Number.) USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-talisman-of-obsidian" name="Talisman of Obsidian">
    <flavor>This black talisman throbs dully with the rhythm of a pulsing wound. This talisman interferes with the powers of nearby spellcasters.</flavor>
    <rules>Any spells cast by models adjacent to the bearer of the talisman fail on a 1D6 roll of 4, 5 or 6 and the Power used to cast the spell is redirected to restore 1D6 of the wearer's Wounds. If the wearer attempts to cast a spell, roll 1D6. On a score of 1 the spell fails. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-unyielding-blade" name="Unyielding Blade">
    <flavor>This immense blade was created by the High Elves of Ulthuan to defend against the constant raids from Naggaroth.</flavor>
    <rules>Attacks made with this two-handed sword suffer -1 To Hit. In addition, roll 1D6 at the beginning of each Turn to see what other benefit it bestows: 1-4 +3 Toughness. 5-6 +4 Toughness. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>800G</goldValue>
    <users>BE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-wand-of-diabolum" name="Wand of Diabolum">
    <flavor>This wand is pure white, shot through with streaks of diabolum, a bright red substance capable of harnessing magical energy.</flavor>
    <rules>While using this wand, all of the Wizard's spells cost one less Power to cast. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-wand-of-jade" name="Wand of Jade">
    <flavor>This wand has strange icons engraved upon its surface. This wand increases the effect of any spell that involves rolling dice for its effects by adding +2 to the total. The Wand does not increase the chance of success, however. For example, if used to increase the effects of the Finger of Life spell, the spell still succeeds on a roll of 4, 5 or 6, but now heals 6, 7 or 8 Wounds (depending on the success roll).</flavor>
    <rules>When found, the wand has 2D6 charges. Each use of the wand drains 1 charge. DISCARD WHEN DRAINED</rules>
    <goldValue>600G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-wand-of-transmutation" name="Wand of Transmutation">
    <flavor>A soft hum emanates from this mysterious wand. This wand contains spells that a Wizard may cast. Take 1D6 Starting Spell Cards not currently in play to represent the spells contained in the wand. The bearer may cast each spell once automatically at no Power Cost. (RPG: Once all the spells are used, the wand may be recharged at the Font of Power for 1D6x100 gold.</flavor>
    <rules>Follow the rules above to see which spells are now stored in the wand.) USE THEN RECHARGE (From 'Rooftop Murder' Adventure) OM TREASURE</rules>
    <goldValue>500G</goldValue>
    <users>W</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-war-spear" name="War Spear">
    <flavor>This deceptively crude-looking spear can penetrate even the most robust armour. This spear may be used in hand-to-hand Combat or as a missile weapon up to 6 squares away. It ignores up to 2 points of non- magical Armour (1 point if the Armour is magical).</flavor>
    <rules>If thrown, the spear also causes Double Damage if the To Hit roll is a 5 or 6. If may be retrieved at the end of the Combat. PERMANENT</rules>
    <goldValue>700G</goldValue>
    <users>BDE</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-warningstone-of-asuryan" name="Warningstone of Asuryan">
    <flavor>This sky-blue jewel is said to be linked to the god Asuryan himself and imparts lightning-fast reactions to the wearer.</flavor>
    <rules>When ambushed, the bearer rolls 1D6. On a score of 6, they sense the danger and warn the other Warriors, so the attackers do not get their Ambush Attack. The Warrior may try this once per Event which generates Monsters with the Ambush ability. USE ONCE PER EVENT</rules>
    <goldValue>1100G</goldValue>
    <users>BEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-treasure-objective-warp-jump-spell-jewel" name="Warp Jump Spell Jewel">
    <rules>When they use this arcane jewel, the Warriors vanish with a thundercrack. The jewel bearer and all adjacent Warriors are transported to anywhere in the Dungeon already explored, appearing in the same order as when they disappeared. If a Warrior who is transported is carrying the only light source, the remaining Warriors are Lost in the Dark and must roll on the Escaping the Dungeon Table. This also happens if Warriors transport without a light source. USE ONCE PER ADVENTURE</rules>
    <goldValue>750G</goldValue>
    <users>BDEW</users>
    <treasure>true</treasure>
  </event>
</events>
