<?xml version="1.0"?>
<events xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='whq-events-schema.xsd'> 
  <!--  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-take-treasure-card" name="Take a Treasure Card as Normal"><rules>Take a Treasure card as normal.</rules><goldValue>-</goldValue><treasure>true</treasure></event>-->
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-heartseeker" name="Heartseeker"><flavor>This sword has the ability to warp time, guiding its own destiny to the benefit of whoever wields it in battle.</flavor><rules>Once per turn, while your Warrior is using this sword, you may re-roll any one of his Attacks that misses.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-berserker-sword" name="Berserker Sword"><flavor>This brutal weapon appears to be crudely fashioned from a dull, iron-like metal, and has sinister-looking runes engraved upon its hilt.</flavor><rules>When used by the Barbarian, this sword adds +1 to the dice roll to see if he becomes berserk. When used by other Warriors, this sword has no magical effect.</rules><goldValue>250G</goldValue><users>B</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-bronze-sigil-sword" name="Bronze Sigil Sword"><flavor>The runes on this blade shimmer in the light. It is exceptionally light and well-balanced in the hand.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gains +2 Initiative.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-quargskin" name="Boots of Quargskin"><flavor>These boots are made of a strange, soft leather covered with multicoloured swirls and stripes.</flavor><rules>For one turn per adventure, while your Warrior is wearing these boots, he gains +2 Movement. If your Warrior tries to sell these boots, no trader will take him seriously, and they will refuse to buy them.</rules><goldValue>0G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-ensorcelled-iron" name="Sword of Ensorcelled Iron"><flavor>This dark iron blade is surrounded by a crackling, spitting aura of energy.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +1 on all to hit rolls.</rules><goldValue>150G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-biting-blade" name="Biting Blade"><flavor>This sword has been magically sharpened to a razor-fine edge, and is capable of biting through sheet steel as if it were paper.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword each attack he makes ignores the first point of his opponent's armour.</rules><goldValue>150G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-stone" name="Sword of Stone"><flavor>As soon as your Warrior picks up this sword, he feels his skin hardening into a stone-like material, which remains as flexible as normal flesh.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +2 Toughness.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-leaping-copper" name="Blade of Leaping Copper"><flavor>This sword seems to have a life of its own, striking in a blurred arc of slicing metal.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +1 Attack.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-couronne" name="Blade of Couronne"><flavor>This is the blade that the master swordsmiths of Bretonnia forged to defeat an Undead Liche-king many centuries past.</flavor><rules>While he uses this sword, each undead Monster in a square adjacent to your Warrior automatically suffers 1 Wound at the end of each turn, after any Regeneration (see the Bestiary), with no modifiers for Toughness or armour.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-magic-sword" name="Magic Sword"><flavor>This blade glows with a yellow light and is slightly warm to the touch.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he may attack Monsters that are only affected by magical weapons.</rules><goldValue>25G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-relic-blade" name="Relic Blade"><flavor>This holy blade is an artefact of great religious significance within the Empire, and was reputed to have been used by the realm's mightiest heroes in numerous battles.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +1 on his to hit roll.</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-slicing" name="Blade of Slicing"><flavor>This sword moans softly as it is drawn from its scabbard, in eager anticipation of the blood it is about to spill.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he causes +2 Wounds on each successful attack.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-darting-steel-blades" name="Darting Steel Blades"><flavor>These daggers guide the hand of whoever wields them and have never been known to miss their target.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using these daggers he gets +1 Attacks and you do not have to roll to see if he hits his opponent. Each attack hits automatically. However, each hit from one of these daggers only does 1D6 Wounds, with no modifier for Strength.</rules><goldValue>350G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-magical-quiver" name="Magical Quiver"><flavor>This quiver is made from soft leather and has magical runes branded into its surface.</flavor><rules>Any arrows or crossbow bolts placed in this quiver immediately become enchanted so they can affect Monsters that can only be hit with magical weapons.</rules><goldValue>25G</goldValue><users>BE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-bone-blade" name="Bone Blade"><flavor>This magical blade is made of a bleached white substance that looks like bone, but is as sharp as steel.</flavor><rules>Once per adventure your Warrior may trade in all his normal attacks and use this sword to make a single attack that causes normal damage +(1D6 x his Battle-level) extra wounds.</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-eltharions-bow" name="Eltharion's Bow"><flavor>This bow is enchanted with Elf magic that makes it much more accurate.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this bow he gets +1 to hit.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-might" name="Sword of Might"><flavor>This sword is imbued with the strength of a Minotaur, and any blow it strikes is delivered with the power of a raging beast.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +1 Strength.</rules><goldValue>150G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-stealth" name="Cloak of Stealth"><flavor>This cloak is made of an odd material that is slippery to the touch.</flavor><rules>Once per adventure, while your Warrior is wearing this cloak, he may automatically break from pinning.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-obsidian-blade" name="Obsidian Blade"><flavor>It is believed that this sword is made from the solidified blackness of the void, explaining its ability to destroy any armour it touches.</flavor><rules>After your Warrior has made a successful attack while using this sword, roll a D6. On a score of 1, 2 or 3 the sword makes a normal attack. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the sword ignores and destroys the target's armour.</rules><goldValue>450G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-giant-slayer" name="Giant Slayer"><flavor>This massive sword may only be wielded with both hands and even then it takes a mighty Warrior to use it effectively.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +3 Strength. This sword may not be used while using a shield.</rules><goldValue>250G</goldValue><users>BDE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-sword-of-resilience" name="Sword of Resilience"><flavor>This sword throws a mantle of power around its wielder, protecting him from his enemies.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he gets +1 Toughness.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-helmet-of-farseeing" name="Helmet of Farseeing"><flavor>This black helm has no apparent visor. Yet it imparts upon the wearer the ability to see clearly even in the dim light of the dungeon.</flavor><rules>While wearing this helmet your Warrior gets the normal +1 Toughness for wearing a helm. In addition, this helmet allows him to move around and see in the dark just as if he had a lantern.</rules><goldValue>800G</goldValue><users>BDE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-parrying-blade" name="Parrying Blade"><flavor>This sword darts forward of its own volition to meet the weapon of an attacker, stopping the blow from hitting home.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he may attempt to parry any single incoming attack. Roll a D6. On a score of 1, 2 or 3 the blade fails to work and the attack hits home. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the attack is magically turned away and has no effect.</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-deathsword" name="Deathsword"><flavor>This sword's power is such that it cannot really be controlled and would soon overwhelm whoever carried it.</flavor><rules>Once per adventure your Warrior may use this sword to increase his Strength to 10 for one turn.</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-dragonhelm" name="Dragonhelm"><flavor>This ancient Elven helm is inscribed with a glowing rune of fire.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is wearing this helmet he gets +2 Toughness against all fire-based attacks.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>BE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-blade-of-sea-gold" name="Blade of Sea Gold"><flavor>Forged from gold taken from the depths of the sea when the world was young, this blade is covered in runes so ancient and worn that they can no longer be read.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword each attack he makes ignores the first point of his opponent's armour.</rules><goldValue>150G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-ogre-slayer" name="Ogre Slayer"><flavor>This brutal, broad-bladed axe is a powerful weapon, almost certainly of Dwarf origin.</flavor><rules>While using this axe your Warrior gets +2 Strength (+3 if he is a Dwarf).</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-blessed-sword" name="Blessed Sword"><flavor>Cooled in the waters of the temple of Ulric, this sword is a powerful weapon of purity.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword he only misses his opponent if his to hit roll is a 1 or a 2.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-grey-armour-of-eshkalon" name="Grey Armour of Eshkalon"><flavor>This dull grey armour is made of a flaky, stone-like substance and is extremely resilient.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is wearing this armour roll 1D6 for each incoming attack. On a score of 1 the armour shatters and is useless. On a score of 2 or more the armour absorbs that many Wounds.</rules><goldValue>400/0G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-armour-of-fortune" name="Armour of Fortune"><rules>This armour's gleaming metal plates magically reflect all the battles in which it has been worn in a rainbow array of never-ending carnage and war. This armour absorbs and stores damage. When your Warrior finds it, it is completely discharged, with no Wounds stored. Once he has put it on he cannot remove it for the rest of the adventure. It can absorb 30 Wounds, after which it explodes, taking the Warrior down to zero wounds (and out of the game if there is no potion or spell handy!).</rules><goldValue>500/0G</goldValue><users>BDE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-undead-bane" name="Undead Bane"><flavor>This sword was forged in the time of Nagash, the Liche-king, and is a powerful weapon against his undead hordes.</flavor><rules>While your Warrior is using this sword each Attack he makes against undead Monsters causes an extra 1D6 Wounds.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-dispel-magic-scroll" name="Dispel Magic Scroll"><flavor>The parchment of this scroll is crumbling with age, the faint sigils and runes now barely readable.</flavor><rules>This scroll allows the Wizard to render harmless a single spell cast against himself or his companions, whatever its source. The scroll may only be used by a Wizard.</rules><goldValue>150/0G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-energy-jewel" name="Energy Jewel"><flavor>This glowing jewel, set in a silver clasp, stores powerful magic.</flavor><rules>This jewel contains 1D6 points of Power that the Wizard can use to augment his spellcasting ability. Once drained the jewel is useless and worthless.</rules><goldValue>200/0G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-amulet-of-fury" name="Amulet of Fury"><flavor>At the heart of this crystal amulet a golden, magical fire rages.</flavor><rules>The Amulet of Fury allows a Warrior who is otherwise nonmagical to cast a spell. As soon as your Warrior finds the amulet, take a Spell card at random: this is the spell it contains. The bearer of the amulet may attempt to cast the spell once per turn, rolling equal to or over its casting number on 1D6 to succeed. After successful use, the amulet disintegrates into powder.</rules><goldValue>200/0G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-arrow-of-slaying" name="Arrow of Slaying"><flavor>A thick black light drips from the end of this arrow, consuming nearby energy and chilling the air.</flavor><rules>The magical venom that permeates this weapon can fell even the toughest monster. If your Warrior hits a Monster with this arrow, roll 1D6. On a score of 1, 2 or 3 the arrow does normal damage. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the Monster is immediately slain. Use once, then discard.</rules><goldValue>500/0G</goldValue><users>BE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-crown-of-night" name="Crown of Night"><flavor>This jet black crown is fashioned from bands of iron and engraved with powerful runes that crackle and spit with an incandescent blue light.</flavor><rules>While wearing this crown your Warrior may attempt to resist any one spell cast against him per turn, just as if he had the Magic Resistance Ability that some Monsters get. Roll 1D6. On a score of 1-5 the crown fails to stop the spell and it affects your Warrior as normal. On a score of 6 the crown works and the spell doesn't affect him.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-talisman-of-jet" name="Talisman of Jet"><flavor>This glittering black jewel feels warm to the touch and pulses when picked up.</flavor><rules>This talisman allows a Wizard to exchange the spells he has learnt for new ones. At the start of the game you may roll 1D6 to see if your Wizard can exchange one of his spells for another. On a score of 1 the exchange fails, the talisman's power is exhausted and it crumbles to dust. On a score of 2 or more you may exchange any one of the Wizard's spells for one of the same casting number. Once drained the talisman is useless and worthless.</rules><goldValue>600G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-spell-ring" name="Spell Ring"><flavor>Any Wizard recognises this as a potent magical ring, capable of storing magical knowledge that can be harnessed to cast spells.</flavor><rules>As soon as your Warrior finds the ring, take one Spell card at random: this is the spell that is stored in the Spell Ring at the moment. The bearer of the ring may cast the stored spell automatically at any time. After use, the ring is drained until the start of the next dungeon, when you can take another Spell card, and so on. One use per adventure.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-destroy-magic-scroll" name="Destroy Magic Scroll"><flavor>This piece of crisp white parchment rustles and crackles as it is handled, its spidery, silver lettering shifting across the page as you try and read it.</flavor><rules>This scroll allows the Wizard to automatically dispel and destroy any one spell cast against him or his companions. By destroying the spell the Wizard prevents the target from casting it ever again. If you roll a destroyed spell on a Monster's Spell Table when determining which spell it casts, roll again. One use, then discard.</rules><goldValue>350/0G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-cloak-of-invisibility" name="Cloak of Invisibility"><flavor>This cloak catches the light in a very strange manner, becoming transparent in places as if it were full of holes. One use per adventure.</flavor><rules>While wearing this cloak your Warrior becomes invisible and therefore cannot be attacked. He may fight as normal. The cloak contains enough power to keep your Warrior invisible for 1 turn per adventure.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-arrows-of-piercing" name="Arrows of Piercing"><flavor>These white arrows have magically sharpened tips and are reputed to be able to pierce the toughest armour or hide at a thousand paces.</flavor><rules>Each time your Warrior successfully hits his target with one of these arrows roll an additional D6. On a score of 1, 2, 3 or 4 the arrow fails to have any additional effect and you should determine damage as normal. On a score of 5 or 6 (6 if the armour is magical) the arrow goes straight through the target's armour as if it wasn't there and you should determine damage without it. There are enough arrows to last one adventure.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>BEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-the-ring-of-dadaan" name="The Ring of Dadaan"><flavor>This ring feels unusually heavy for its size and crackles with power.</flavor><rules>The Ring of Dadaan allows a Warrior to cast a spell once per adventure. As soon as your Warrior finds the ring take one Spell card at random: this is the spell that is stored in the ring. The bearer of the ring may cast the stored spell automatically at any time. After use, the ring is drained of all magic and becomes worthless. One use, then discard.</rules><goldValue>200/0G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-leaping" name="Boots of Leaping"><flavor>These boots are fashioned from the tough leather of a Wyvern's wings.</flavor><rules>These boots allow your Warrior to leap 1 square in any direction as part of his move, landing in the square beyond. Any obstacle in the square being leaped is ignored, though it still counts as 1 square of movement. These boots may be used once per turn.</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-swiftness" name="Boots of Swiftness"><flavor>As soon as these boots are put on the rest of the world seems to slow down.</flavor><rules>While wearing these boots your Warrior gets +1 Movement.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-flight" name="Boots of Flight"><flavor>These elegant boots float an inch or so off the ground, their outline shimmering with magical energy.</flavor><rules>While wearing these boots your Warrior may levitate a few inches above the ground while moving. While airborne your Warrior may pass over chasms, pits, etc. unhindered and anyone who attacks him is at -1 on his to hit roll. Lasts one adventure, then discard.</rules><goldValue>750/10G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-boots-of-battle" name="Boots of Battle"><flavor>These sturdy iron-shod boots are magically made to be an exact fit for whoever wears them.</flavor><rules>While wearing these boots your Warrior gets an extra kick attack at -1 to hit and +1 Strength.</rules><goldValue>250G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-flight" name="Potion of Flight"><flavor>The contents of this bottle bubble and hiss as they are drunk, burning the throat and searing the tongue.</flavor><rules>After drinking this potion your Warrior levitates a few inches above the ground while moving. While airborne your Warrior may pass over chasms, pits, etc. unhindered and anyone who attacks him is at -1 on his to hit roll. Lasts one turn.</rules><goldValue>250G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-healing" name="Potion of Healing"><flavor>This green bottle contains a sweet-smelling liquid with a treacly consistency.</flavor><rules>Upon drinking this potion your Warrior regains 1D6 Wounds.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-invisibility" name="Potion of Invisibility"><flavor>This vial contains a multi-coloured liquid that swirls sluggishly and gives off heady vapours as the seal is broken. Lasts for one turn.</flavor><rules>After drinking this potion your Warrior becomes invisible and therefore cannot be attacked. He may fight as normal, but may not cast spells if he has that ability.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-strength" name="Potion of Strength"><flavor>An intoxicating liquid flows from this bottle, bringing a sense of power and might to whoever drinks it.</flavor><rules>After drinking this potion your Warrior gets +1D6 Strength. Lasts for one turn.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-disguise" name="Potion of Disguise"><flavor>This black liquid has no taste and leaves no trace of moisture on the lips.</flavor><rules>After drinking this potion your Warrior will not be attacked or pinned as long as he does not initiate a combat. As soon as your Warrior attacks a target in any way the potion's effects wear off.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-water-walking" name="Potion of Water Walking"><flavor>This effervescent liquid has a salty tang reminiscent of the sea.</flavor><rules>After drinking this potion your Warrior can walk over areas of water at a rate of (3 x his normal Movement) squares per turn. Lasts for one turn.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-potion-of-toughness" name="Potion of Toughness"><flavor>Upon drinking this red-flecked liquid you feel your muscles bulge and your sinews toughen.</flavor><rules>After drinking this potion your Warrior gets +3 Toughness. Lasts for one turn.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-protection-ring" name="Protection Ring"><flavor>The image of a shield is engraved on the uppermost surface of this small ring.</flavor><rules>While wearing this ring your Warrior gets +1 Toughness.</rules><goldValue>300G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-invisibility" name="Ring of Invisibility"><flavor>As soon as you slip this ring onto your finger you fade from sight.</flavor><rules>While wearing this ring your Warrior is invisible and therefore cannot be attacked. He may fight as normal. One use per adventure. Lasts for one turn.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-power" name="Ring of Power"><flavor>This simple band of stone slips easily onto your finger, contracting until it is a perfect fit.</flavor><rules>While wearing this ring one of your Warrior's characteristics is increased by +1. Choose which characteristic is affected the first time your Warrior puts the ring on.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-arkais-powder" name="Arkai's Powder"><flavor>This silver dust swirls in its casket as if shifted by an unseen finger.</flavor><rules>After your Warrior has consumed this powder his movements speed up and he may immediately move another 3D6 squares, ignoring pinning. Arkai's powder may be consumed at any time. Use once, then discard.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-charm-of-learning" name="Charm of Learning"><flavor>As soon as you put on this charm the world seems to have a clearer definition and edge...</flavor><rules>This charm allows your Warrior to assimilate the knowledge required for training very quickly indeed. It costs him 300 less gold than usual to train to the next Battle-level. Use once, then discard.</rules><goldValue>100G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-ring-of-sure-seeing" name="Ring of Sure Seeing"><flavor>This ring has a large gem set in its surface that, in times of danger, shows a picture of what is to come.</flavor><rules>This ring allows you to re-roll any single Hazard or Settlement Event roll for your Warrior. You must take the result of the second roll. Use once, then discard.</rules><goldValue>200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-gems-of-life" name="Gems of Life"><flavor>These small gems sparkle with a strange, otherworldly energy.</flavor><rules>These gems come as a pair. One should be worn while the other is kept in a safe place away from the dungeon. If the wearer is killed, shortly after his death his body starts to dwindle in size until it is a pinprick of light contained within the gem. The only things left behind are items of mundane equipment, such as bandages, the lantern or a rope. If the other Warriors survive the rest of the dungeon and bring the two gems back together, their magical power recalls the dead Warrior, alive and well, just as he was before the adventure started. Use once, then discard.</rules><goldValue>700G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-bracelet-of-transformation" name="Bracelet of Transformation"><flavor>This plain bronze bracelet has a single rune embossed on its surface.</flavor><rules>Upon donning this bracelet your Warrior may take on the appearance, and only the appearance, of any other creature. While transformed your Warrior will not be attacked or pinned as long as he does not initiate combat. As soon as your Warrior attacks a target in any way the bracelet's effects wear off. One use per adventure.</rules><goldValue>350G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-lifestone" name="Lifestone"><flavor>The Lifestone has the power to drain the life energy from the surrounding area and transfer it to its wearer.</flavor><rules>Upon invoking the Lifestone choose any other Warrior in the party. Your Warrior now has the same number of Wounds as this Warrior, while his are changed to the number your Warrior had. In effect, their Wounds are swapped. This spell may never be used to take a Warrior above his Starting Wounds, which remain as they were. One use per adventure.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-bracelet-of-ashain" name="Bracelet of Ashain"><flavor>This slim golden band fits comfortably around the wearer's forearm, even on top of armour.</flavor><rules>While wearing this bracelet your Warrior gets +3 Starting Wounds.</rules><goldValue>350G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-circlet-of-wrath" name="Circlet of Wrath"><flavor>This band of silvered, luminescent metal, worn around the forehead, glistens and gleams with an unnatural light.</flavor><rules>This circlet allows the wearer to enter a blood rage of destruction at will. Upon entering this state roll a D6. On a score of 2 or more your Warrior gets double Attacks. On a score of 1 your Warrior gets double Attacks but must move towards the nearest Warrior it is possible for him to attack and fight him instead of a Monster. In addition, while in this state your Warrior may not be pinned. One use per adventure. Lasts for one turn.</rules><goldValue>400G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-belt-of-gagron" name="Belt of Gagron"><flavor>This thick leather belt belonged to the Dwarf Gagron the Giantslayer. It possesses the magical property of staunching serious wounds and knitting torn flesh back together.</flavor><rules>Each time your Warrior is reduced to zero Wounds while wearing this belt roll 1D6 at the end of the turn, as long as your Warrior has taken no other form of healing during the turn. On a score of 1 or 2 the belt has no effect and your Warrior remains unconscious. On a score of 3, 4 or 5 the belt restores 1D6 of your Warrior's Wounds. On a score of 6 the belt restores 2D6 of your Warrior's Wounds. The Belt of Gagron cannot be removed.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-stone-of-transmutation" name="Stone of Transmutation"><flavor>This small, plain stone hangs from a delicate copper chain.</flavor><rules>The item may be used to transmute a single Monster into stone, thereby killing it. To determine whether the stone works roll 1D6 and add your Warrior's Battle-level. If the total is greater than the target Monster's current Wounds it is turned into a statue. If the total is equal to or less than the target Monster's current Wounds the spell fails. Use once, then discard.</rules><goldValue>200/0G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-dungeon-gauntlet-of-damzhar" name="Gauntlet of Damzhar"><flavor>This thick iron gauntlet is covered with studs in the shape of Dwarf runes.</flavor><rules>A Gauntlet of Damzhar gives the wearer +1 Attack at -1 to hit and at +1 to Strength. If your Warrior wears two gauntlets of Damzhar, their combined power gives an additional +1 Attack, making a total of +3: 1 for each Gauntlet plus +1 for their combined attack, at +1 to hit and causing 4D6 damage.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-ring-of-seeking" name="Ring of Seeking"><flavor>This glittering ring is fashioned from some material that looks like quicksilver. Once placed on the finger, the ring shifts and changes as a shining, liquid-metal band.</flavor><rules>This ring allows your Warrior to attempt to avoid a trap he has just activated. Roll 1D6. On a score of 1, 2 or 3 the ring's magic fails to work and the trap goes off as normal. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the trap is magically disarmed and fails to work.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-chalice-of-sorcery" name="Chalice of Sorcery"><flavor>This dull metal chalice sits in a small alcove in the wall, covered in verdigris and cobwebs. Rubbing the grime of years from its pitted surface, the Wizard recognises it as a Chalice of Sorcery.</flavor><rules>The Chalice of Sorcery acts as a source of Power that allows the Wizard to carry on casting spells when his own Power has run out. The Wizard can try to draw as many points of Power out of the Chalice as he likes. For every point of Power the Wizard draws to cast spells with, roll a D6. All the extra Power must be drawn at once so all the dice are rolled at the same time. For each dice that scores a 1 the Wizard loses 1D6 Wounds, with no modifiers for Toughness or armour.</rules><goldValue>700G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-enchanted-jade-amulet" name="Enchanted Jade Amulet"><flavor>The amulet of enchanted jade looks like a stone washed up on a beach, worn smooth by the action of the sea.</flavor><rules>The Amulet of Enchanted Jade allows your Warrior to attempt to regenerate (1 x his Battle-level) Wounds per turn, up to his Starting Wounds score. Each turn that your Warrior uses the amulet roll 1D6 on the following table: 1 The amulet crumbles to dust, causing 1D6 Wounds on your Warrior, with no modifier for Toughness or armour. 2 The amulet has no effect this turn. 3-6 The amulet works as usual. The amulet automatically fails to work while the Warrior wearing it is on zero Wounds. One use per turn.</rules><goldValue>600G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-book-of-arcane-knowledge" name="Book of Arcane Knowledge"><flavor>This book has a cracked and aged leather cover, with a rusted metal spine and lock. Upon opening it, the pages rustle with a life of their own.</flavor><rules>The Book of Arcane Knowledge contains spells that the Wizard may cast. As soon as the book is found roll 4D6. These dice are used to buy spells for the book in the same way that the Wizard gains spells when he goes up a Battle-level, as described under 'New Spells' in the Wizards' Training section. Each spell in the book may be cast once automatically at no Power cost. Once a spell has been cast that page of the book crumbles to dust.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-brooch-of-power" name="Brooch of Power"><flavor>This brooch glows too brightly to look at, as if it contained the energy of a fallen star.</flavor><rules>At the end of each turn the Wizard may use the brooch to store any unused Power he has left over, up to a maximum of (6 + his Battle-level). This stored Power may then be used at any time to augment his spellcasting. In addition, the bright aura cast by the brooch distracts any Monsters attacking the Wizard, adding +1 to his Toughness.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-wand-of-jade" name="Wand of Jade"><flavor>This wand is the size of a walking stick and is made from a single piece of fine jade. Strange icons engraved upon its surface glow with power.</flavor><rules>This wand increases the effect of any spell that requires you to roll one or more dice for its effects, such as Heal Wounds or Lightning Bolt, by adding +2 to the total. Note that the wand does not increase the spell's chance of success in any way. For example: if the Wizard uses this wand to increase the effects of the Finger of Life spell it still succeeds on a roll of 4, 5 or 6, but now heals 6, 7 or 8 Wounds, depending on the success of the roll. When found, the wand has 2D6 charges. Each use of the wand expends 1 charge.</rules><goldValue>600G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-dawnstone" name="Dawnstone"><flavor>This crystal-like stone is mounted in a black iron brooch and radiates a pale light like that of the early morning.</flavor><rules>The Dawnstone may be used to restore any one Warrior to full Wounds immediately, even if he is at zero Wounds or dead. One use, then discard.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-rune-of-death" name="Rune of Death"><flavor>This stone has a Dwarf rune embossed upon its surface and is warm to the touch.</flavor><rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the Runestone burns a Rune of Death into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune of Death itself is permanent. If the to hit roll with this weapon is a natural 6, the Rune of Death causes an extra 2D6 Wounds on the target.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-crown-of-sorcery" name="Crown of Sorcery"><flavor>As soon as he puts this crown on, the wearer is plunged into the alien and dark world of magical power familiar to Wizards.</flavor><rules>The Crown of Sorcery allows any Warrior who is otherwise nonmagical to cast spells and use items of Wizard-only treasure. The Warrior wearing the crown can still wear armour. As soon as your Warrior finds the crown, take two Spell cards from each deck at random: these are the spells he may cast. Each turn your Warrior gets the same amount of raw Power as a Battle-level 1 Wizard (roll 1D6+1 in the Power Phase), and may use it to cast one or more of his spells according to the normal rules. However, each time your Warrior casts one of his spells roll 1D6. If the score is 1 that spell fails and your Warrior is immobilised by the backlash of magical Power and can do nothing for the rest of the turn. While he is immobilised any attacks made against him hit on anything but a 1.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>BDE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-talisman-of-obsidian" name="Talisman of Obsidian"><flavor>This black talisman throbs dully with the rhythm of a pulsing wound and the air around it hangs heavy.</flavor><rules>This talisman negates the powers of any Wizard or other spellcaster adjacent to the wearer. Any spells cast by such models fail on a 1D6 roll of 4, 5 or 6 and the Power used to cast the spell is redirected to heal 1D6 of the wearer's Wounds. If the wearer attempts to cast a spell himself roll 1D6. On a score of 1 the spell fails.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-tablet-of-adain" name="Tablet of Adain"><flavor>This stone tablet weighs surprisingly little and is covered in indecipherable hatching and markings.</flavor><rules>When used by a Wizard, the Tablet of Adain allows you to re-roll any or all of his 'spell determining dice' when he goes up a Battle level (see 'New Spells' in the Wizards' Training section). You may only re-roll each dice once and must take the result of the second roll, even if it is worse.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-armour-of-taakan" name="Armour of Taakan"><flavor>This matt black suit of full armour - with dull bronze battle runes engraved on the breastplate, arms and helm - is said to be endowed with a life of its own, striking at the enemy no matter what its wearer intends.</flavor><rules>While wearing the Armour of Taakan your Warrior gets the benefits of Heavy Armour and Warhelm (+5 Toughness and -1 Movement). Every time an enemy wounds your Warrior the armour immediately retaliates and forces its wearer to strike back straight away. Your Warrior must make a single attack against the enemy that just hit him, in addition to his normal attacks this turn. Note that, if successful, this attack does not cause a deathblow.</rules><goldValue>1,500G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-wand-of-diabolum" name="Wand of Diabolum"><flavor>This wand is pure white, shot through with streaks of diabolum, a bright red substance capable of harnessing magical energy.</flavor><rules>While using this wand all your Wizard's spells have their casting number reduced by -1.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-ring-of-cheshnakk" name="Ring of Cheshnakk"><flavor>Cheshnakk was a great wizard from Araby whose expertise was the creation of exquisite flying carpets. The pinnacle of his achievements, however, was forging the Rings of Cheshnakk. On command, one of these rings can transport its wearer back to his home, be that a castle, a forest clearing or a humble cottage.</flavor><rules>While wearing this ring your Warrior may at any time leave the dungeon and be transported to his home and safety. He is out of this adventure and meets the Warriors at the next Settlement.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-the-hammer-of-sigmar" name="The Hammer of Sigmar"><flavor>This is perhaps the most ancient and revered of all the magic weapons in the Empire, forged by Dwarf Runesmiths to cement an ancient alliance between Dwarfs and Men.</flavor><rules>The Hammer of Sigmar ignores all except magic armour when rolling for damage. In addition, if the to hit score for the attack is a natural 6 it causes 4 x normal damage. There can only ever be one Hammer of Sigmar in the party.</rules><goldValue>2,000G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-blade-of-leaping-gold" name="Blade of Leaping Gold"><flavor>This blade is superbly balanced and moves in a swift golden arc with almost no effort on the wielder's part, slicing through the enemy ranks with ease.</flavor><rules>While wielding this weapon your Warrior gets +3 Attacks.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-frostblade" name="Frostblade"><flavor>This pale metallic blue weapon exudes a freezing aura and its blade glitters like ice.</flavor><rules>When wielding the Frostblade your Warrior may only make 1 Attack per turn. If your Warrior makes a successful attack with the Frostblade that causes at least 1 Wound, after taking into account Toughness, armour, any special abilities such as Ignore Blow, etc., the target is automatically slain. A blow from a Frostblade can cause a deathblow. The Frostblade may only be used once per adventure.</rules><goldValue>750G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-rending-sword" name="Rending Sword"><flavor>The serrated points along the cutting edge of this blade grind and gnash together like teeth, tearing through armour, flesh and bone.</flavor><rules>This sword causes an extra 2D6 Wounds upon a successful hit. In addition, the blow ignores 2 points of armour if the to hit roll was a natural 5 or 6.</rules><goldValue>1,200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-sword-of-destruction" name="Sword of Destruction"><flavor>This sword resonates with a deep hum and flickers with lightning.</flavor><rules>When drawn from its scabbard, this sword nullifies all magic within 1 square of the wielder. As long as the sword remains drawn, the wielder and any models in adjacent squares cannot use or count the benefits of any magic items or spells. In addition, the sword causes +1 Wound and gives the bearer the Magic Dispel 6+ special ability (see the Bestiary).</rules><goldValue>750G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-bane-sword" name="Bane Sword"><flavor>As soon as it is drawn in the presence of its hated foe this blade snarls and growls, eager to spill blood.</flavor><rules>As soon as your Warrior finds this sword, make a D66 roll on the Monster Table that is the same level as your Warrior's Battle-level. The sword does 2 x normal damage against all Monsters of that race, if you roll Skaven Assassins, for instance, the Bane Sword affects all Skaven.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-dragon-sword" name="Dragon Sword"><flavor>This blade is fashioned from the venom fang of a Great Fire Dragon and is ancient beyond all telling.</flavor><rules>This sword causes double damage on a successful natural to hit roll of 5 or 6. However, the sword is partially sentient and refuses to be drawn from its scabbard by a Warrior of Battle-level 3 or below.</rules><goldValue>1,200G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-hellfire-sword" name="Hellfire Sword"><flavor>Flames leap and burn along the length of this other-worldly sword. As it swings through the air, it leaves a trail of spitting magma in its wake.</flavor><rules>If your Warrior hits his opponent with a natural to hit roll of 6, as well as causing normal damage the target and all adjacent models, including your Warrior, burst into flames and take an extra 1D6 Wounds for each of your Warrior's Battle-levels, with no modifiers for Toughness or armour.</rules><goldValue>1,500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-gromril-blade" name="Gromril Blade"><flavor>This mighty two-handed axe is a Dwarf artefact, able to cut through all but the most powerful armour.</flavor><rules>This axe ignores all except magical armour and does double damage on a successful hit. However, the axe is partially sentient and refuses to be drawn by a Warrior of Battle-level 2 or below. The Gromril Blade may not be used with a shield.</rules><goldValue>1,200G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-hydra-sword" name="Hydra Sword"><flavor>Steeped in the blood of a hydra as it was forged, this blade has taken on some of the properties of these terrible beasts.</flavor><rules>On each successful hit, this blade does an extra 6D6 Wounds. The Hydra Sword may be used once per adventure.</rules><goldValue>850G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-sword-of-vengeance" name="Sword of Vengeance"><rules>The blade shines with a pure light and never dulls. This sword ignores the Monster's Toughness and all except magical armour when determining damage. In addition, the wielder can re-roll one miss per turn.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>BW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-axe-of-slaying" name="Axe of Slaying"><flavor>This axe was once wielded by the Dwarf Giantslayer Umgrul Grunnson at the final battle of Karak Azgal.</flavor><rules>This axe automatically hits its target - the wielder does not have to make a to hit roll. In addition, instead of a normal damage roll, to work out the axe's damage roll roll 1D6: if the score is a 1 the axe causes 1D6 (+ Strength) Wounds, if the score is a 2 the axe causes 2D6 (+ Strength) Wounds, and so on. Use for one turn per adventure.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>D</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-sword-of-heroes" name="Sword of Heroes"><flavor>This sword shines with an undimming fire - the fire of righteousness smiting down evil wherever it may be found.</flavor><rules>This sword causes an extra 3D6 Wounds when used against Monsters with a Toughness of 6 or more.</rules><goldValue>900G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-blade-of-leaping-bronze" name="Blade of Leaping Bronze"><flavor>As soon as it is drawn this blade strikes with incredible speed.</flavor><rules>This sword gives its wielder +2 Attacks.</rules><goldValue>450G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-bow-of-loren" name="Bow of Loren"><flavor>This slender bow was fashioned by the Wood Elves of Loren.</flavor><rules>This bow inflicts 1D6 Wounds per Battle-level of the wielder. If this is sufficient to kill the target outright, and there is a Monster directly behind it in the direction the bow was fired, the arrow continues, hitting that Monster too. This process continues until either there are no more Monsters in the direct line of fire, or one of them survives.</rules><goldValue>2,000G</goldValue><users>E</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-surefire-bow" name="Surefire Bow"><flavor>This elegant bow has a single rune of Surefire. Ancient stories tell of a bow that never misses and this may be that very weapon...</flavor><rules>This bow has Strength 4 and adds +2 to the wielder's to hit roll.</rules><goldValue>900G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-enchanted-shield" name="Enchanted Shield"><flavor>The surface of this shield gleams as brightly as a mirror. Clouds roll across its surface, and shards of light cut the air around it.</flavor><rules>This shield gives its bearer +3 Toughness, but may not be used with any other armour, except a helmet, until the wearer is Battle level 4 or above. A Warrior may not wield a two-handed weapon while using the Enchanted Shield.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-armour-of-meteoric-iron" name="Armour of Meteoric Iron"><flavor>This armour's appearance is pitted and dull, but it glows with a dim radiance that betrays its true nature.</flavor><rules>This armour gives its wearer +3 Toughness, with no deductions for movement. However, once worn it fuses to the flesh and cannot be removed. Unfortunately, because the armour is so heavy, it cannot be carried. It must be worn immediately or left where it is found.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-shield-of-ptolos" name="Shield of Ptolos"><flavor>This shield throws a shimmering haze around its bearer, making him a difficult target in battle.</flavor><rules>This shield gives the bearer +2 Toughness. In addition, when drawing Warrior counters to determine who has been hit by missile fire, the first time the bearer's counter is pulled out you may put it back and draw again. If it comes up a second or subsequent time he is hit as normal.</rules><goldValue>250G</goldValue><users>BDE</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-armour-of-dargan" name="Armour of Dargan"><flavor>The glow from this deep red armour lights up the dungeon.</flavor><rules>This armour makes the wearer harder to hit: he gets +4 Toughness and any Monster attacking him is at -1 on its to hit roll unless using a magical weapon.</rules><goldValue>1,000G</goldValue><users>BD</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-spelleater-rune" name="Spelleater Rune"><flavor>This rune contains powerful spells of negation. Magic in the immediate vicinity arcs as the rune tries to pull it in and absorb it.</flavor><rules>When pressed into contact with any bladed weapon, the Spelleater Rune burns a copy of itself into the blade and then vanishes. The Rune on the blade itself is permanent. Any spells cast against the bearer of this magical blade now fail on a 1D6 roll of 5 or 6.</rules><goldValue>500G</goldValue><users>BDEW</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
  <event id="rpb-treasure-objective-the-staff-of-command" name="The Staff of Command"><flavor>This staff had runes of command burned into it many centuries ago.</flavor><rules>Once per Event the Wizard may use this staff to attempt to control any Monster on the board. The attempt must be made as soon as the Monsters appear. Roll 1D6. On a score of 1, 2, 3 or 4 the magic fails. On a score of 5 or 6 the Wizard may choose one Monster and make it do whatever he wants, as long as the action does not cause it to harm itself. The Monster fights in the Warriors' phase and if it kills another Monster no-one gets the gold. At the end of the turn, the possessed Monster returns to normal.</rules><goldValue>900G</goldValue><users>W</users><treasure>true</treasure></event>
</events>
