<?xml version="1.0"?>

<rules xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	     xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='whq-rules-schema.xsd'>
  <rule id="hothq-breathes-smoke" name="BREATHES SMOKE (AMBUSH, MAGIC A)">At the start of each turn roll 1D6. The result shows how many Warriors are engulfed by the oily fumes. If the score is higher than the number of Warriors present, all of them are hit. If not, use Warrior counters to determine who is affected. Roll 1D6 for each Warrior hit, subtract their Toughness from the score and multiply the result by 2. The total shows how many D6 Wounds that Warrior suffers, with no modifiers for Toughness or armour. This attack is used in addition to the dragon's normal hand-to-hand attacks.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-breathes-noxious-vapour" name="BREATHES NOXIOUS VAPOUR 4+">At the start of each turn roll 1D6 for each Warrior on the same board section. If the score is 4 or more, that Warrior suffers the listed attack with no modifiers for Toughness or armour. This attack is used in addition to the dragon's normal hand-to-hand attacks.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-dragon-cloak" name="DRAGON CLOAK">A Black Ark Corsair wears a cloak made from Sea Dragon scales. When rolling Damage Dice against a Corsair with a Dragon Cloak, any roll of 1 or 2 is ignored as the blow is deflected.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-poison-slime" name="POISON SLIME (1D3)">A Cold One's hide drips with toxic slime. Any Warrior wounded in hand-to-hand combat also suffers an extra 1D3 Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or armour.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-executioners-blow" name="EXECUTIONER'S BLOW">Executioners are trained to deliver a single perfect strike. On a natural 6 to hit, the attack ignores the target's armour and Toughness.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-venom" name="VENOM">The Monster's blades are coated in deadly toxins. When the Monster is placed, roll 1D6: on 1-3 it uses Dark Venom, on 4-6 it uses Manbane. Resolve any Wounds caused by these poisoned attacks with no healing until the end of the turn.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-wardog-attack" name="WARDOG ATTACK">If Julong starts the Monsters' Phase adjacent to Demona Ryme, he may make one extra attack against the same Warrior she attacks.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-disappear" name="DISAPPEAR n+">After making its attacks, the Monster may melt back into the shadows. Roll 1D6. If the score is equal to or higher than the value shown, remove it from the board. At the start of the next Monsters' Phase, place it back on the board adjacent to a randomly determined Warrior.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-slimy-skin" name="SLIMY SKIN">A River Troll's skin is coated in foul mucus. Any non-magical attack that wounds it is reduced by 1D6 before Toughness and armour are applied.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-2x-magic-item" name="2 x MAGIC ITEM">This Monster carries two Magic Items. Roll twice on the standard Magic Item table, rerolling duplicates if needed.</rule>
  <rule id="hothq-3x-magic-item" name="3 x MAGIC ITEM">This Monster carries three Magic Items. Roll three times on the standard Magic Item table, rerolling duplicates if needed.</rule>
</rules>
