<?xml version="1.0"?>

<rules xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	     xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='whq-rules-schema.xsd'>
  <rule id="lotol-orc-magic-armour" name="ORC MAGIC ARMOUR">When an Orc or Goblin Monster has magic armour, use the following Orc Magic Armour table. 
  * 1 Armour of Gork. This blackened chain-mail shimmers in the light. Icy faces shift and move across its dirty surface, and the sound of its worn links move in the sound of deep laughter. The armour plays tricks with the light, making it hard for a Warrior to concentrate on his target. Any Warrior attacking the Monster or shooting at it suffers a -1 to hit modifier. 
  * 2 Armour of Magrot. The strange sigils and runes carved on this breastplate give off crackling sparks. When a Warrior hits the Monster roll 1D6. On a roll of 1 the hit has no effect, but the Warrior is hit by an electrical discharge through his weapon. The Warrior takes 1D6 Wounds with no modifiers at all. 
  * 3 Gork's Big Belt. The massive crude leather belt seems to be pulsating in response to the wearer's heartbeat. At the start of any Monsters' Phase when the Monster has 1 Wound or more the belt will magically heal 1D6 Wounds, up to its starting Wounds score. If the Monster is reduced to 0 Wounds the belt falls to work and the Monster dies. 
  * 4 Animated Armour of Iron Rock Fortress. This armour was forged by the Orc Shaman Ragratt Bonebenda, and is imbued with the lightning reflexes of the hapless Gobbo sacrificed in its creation. The armour itself attempts to dodge attacks. Each time a hit is scored against the Monster roll 1D6. On a roll of 6 the armour throws the Monster to one side and the attack misses. 
  * 5 Helm of Gunbad. Ughulz Arrenda was a Goblin chieftain renowned for his cunning luck where arrows or other missile attacks were concerned. As enemies just couldn't hit him. The secret of his luck was an ancient helmet scavenged from the depths of Mount Gunbad. This steel helmet has a green gem set in it which pulses with an inner light. The helm turns aside all missiles directed against the wearer. No normal fired or thrown weapon will hit the wearer. If a magic missile is employed roll 1D6. On a roll of 5 or 6 even this will be turned aside. 
  * 6 Mork's 'Ead. This black iron helm is fashioned in the shape of a scowling Orc, more of a crudely sculpted mask than a conventional helmet, it is blessed by Mork, god of the Orcs, and is a potent magical helm. When a hit is scored against the wearer of any nature at all roll 1D6. On a roll of 6 the attack is turned aside. Furthermore, if the attack was made by a non-magical weapon that weapon is destroyed by the helm.</rule>
  <rule id="lotol-orc-magic-item" name="ORC MAGIC ITEM">When an Orc or Goblin Monster has a magic item, use the following Orc Magic Items table. 
  * 1 Gluvvz of Deff. The greenskin is wearing a pair of heavy duty black gloves, studded with iron, and glittering with a baleful light. The gauntlets give the Monster +2 Strength, and an extra Attack each turn. 
  * 2 Da Speedstone of Skabnoze. The Monster has around its neck a jewelled amulet that shines with a malicious and sickly light. The amulet makes the wearer's metabolism somewhat unpredictable. The Monster makes 1D6 Attacks per turn, whatever its profile says. 
  * 3 Armband of Agrog the Slayer. This battered bronze armband has obviously seen a great deal of action, marked by blows from many weapons. The armband projects a magical shield round the wearer. The shield gives +1D6 Toughness against any form of attack whatsoever. 
  * 4 Da Burning Brew of Peak Pass. Around its neck the Monster wears a small leather flask. On the flask is the insignia of the Red Eye Goblins. The flask contains a healing potion. When the Monster is first reduced to 0 Wounds it quickly drinks its potion and immediately regains 2D6 Wounds. In addition, the brew sends the Monster crazy. Until it is killed, the Monster gains an extra Attack every turn, and gains +2 Toughness. 
  * 5 Ring of Stomping. This crude ring bears a leering Orc face on its surface. At the start of the Monsters' Phase roll a dice. On a score of 1-5 the ring has no effect. On a score of 6 there is a loud thunderclap and a huge Orc foot slams down from the ceiling. Draw a Warrior counter to see who is hit. That Warrior is stomped to the floor, taking 1D6 Wounds per battle-level. Normal modifiers apply. Once the Monster has activated the ring it will not roll it again while it holds the stomped Warrior. He will be back on his feet in time for the start of the next turn. 
  * 6 Grimfang's Deff Curse. On the greenskin's left hand is a chunky gold ring bearing a red gemstone. The ring brings about a death curse on the slayer of the wearer. When the Monster is reduced to 0 Wounds the ring explodes. The Warrior who killed the wearer immediately takes 2D6 Wounds with no modifiers at all.</rule>
  <rule id="lotol-orc-magic-weapon" name="ORC MAGIC WEAPON">When an Orc or Goblin Monster has a magic weapon, use the following Orc Magic Weapons table. 
  * 1 Axe of Slasha. The finely honed edge of this battle axe scatters the light of the lantern. The magically sharp edge of the axe does an extra 1D6 damage when the Monster wielding it rolls 4+ to hit. 
  * 2 Hammer of Mork. This evil-looking hammer howls as it swings towards its target. This magic hammer adds +1D6 to the wielder's Strength. 
  * 3 Sword of Stabbin'. The obsidian blade of this blood-encrusted sword tapers to a wickedly sharp point. The sword ignores all armour. Any hit caused with the sword is modified for natural Toughness only.
  * 4 Bloodletting Sword. This dark blade glows with an internal pulse. The sword drinks the blood of its victims, causing an extra 1D6 Wounds every time it hits. However, if the Warrior rolls a 1 when rolling to hit, the blade takes the energy it needs from the Warrior instead, causing 1D3 Wounds not modified for armour or Toughness.
  * 5 Frowing Nife. This is an extremely well balanced throwing knife that seems to leap from the thrower's hand. Once per combat, the Warrior may throw the knife at any Monster he can see that is not in an adjacent square to him. The knife hits on a roll of 2+. The knife does 2D6 + Strength damage, and ignores armour and Toughness. Once the combat is over, the knife may be retrieved.
  * 6 A Dead 'Ard Weapon. The Warriors find a cache of dirty but well fashioned weapons, scavenged from who knows where. Roll 1D6 to determine the weapon found, then roll 1D6 for its first ability: 1 causes +1 Wound per battle-level every time it strikes, 2 ignores 1D6 points of armour, 3 gives the wielder +1 to hit, 4 gives the wielder +1 Attacks, 5 allows the wielder to parry incoming blows on a dice roll of 6, 6 causes an extra 6 Wounds on a to hit roll of 6. Roll again, and if the new roll is higher than the previous one the weapon gains that ability too. Continue until you roll the same number or lower. The abilities are permanent.</rule>
</rules>
