<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<objectiveRoomAdventures>
  <objectiveRoom name="FIGHTING PIT">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de la Fighting Pit sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual de la aplicacion. No hay objetivo especial adicional.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="The Beast" generic="false">
      <flavor>Captured by the Goblin Warlord Ugrul Headsticka while exploring the ruins of Karak Azgal, the Warriors have been given a chance to escape and, in the process, provide entertainment for the Goblins. The Warriors must fight their way to freedom without weapons or armour. And as if that were not enough, their only way out is through the Minotaurs' lair.</flavor>
      <rules>The Warriors start this dungeon stripped of any armour and weapons they may have, and must fight with their bare hands. While they are without armour they may only deduct their Toughness from any blows that hit them. They start with no weapons at all, even missile weapons, and must therefore fight in hand-to-hand combat using their fists. While fighting unarmed, each Warrior does 1D6 Wounds when he hits, with no modifiers for Strength. When the first Monster Event Card is triggered, the Warriors notice that their assailants are carrying, but not using, their weapons. If the Warriors kill all these monsters, they may retrieve their weapons. When the second Event Card that reveals Monsters is triggered, the Warriors see that their assailants are guarding their armour. If the Warriors kill all these monsters, they may retrieve their armour. When the Warriors reach the objective room do not roll on the Objective Room Monster Table. The only way for the Warriors to escape the dungeon is through the trapdoor at the bottom of the fighting pit. For every Warrior, up to a total of three, who jumps into the pit, a Minotaur appears next to him and will fight him to the death. As soon as a Warrior is placed in one of the fighting pit squares, place a Minotaur model in any adjacent square in the pit. If all four Warriors jump into the pit, use the rule of One-on-One to determine which Warriors the three Minotaurs attack. Any Warriors that stay out of the fighting pit may help defeat the Minotaurs, for example by firing bows, without causing another Minotaur to appear. When the first Minotaur is killed, it and all the other Minotaurs who magically appeared immediately vanish and the combat is over. Once the Warriors defeat the Minotaurs, they each find one item of treasure in the bottom of the pit and may escape through the trapdoor.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="Sword of Power" generic="false">
      <flavor>The last Warrior to brave the perils of the fighting pit took a sword of great power to help him slay the Minotaur that dwelt within it. However, despite the sword he was destroyed by the Minotaur and his body eaten. The sword now lies rusting at the bottom of the pit. The sword was an ancient heirloom stolen from the Barbarian's father many years ago, and the Barbarian has sworn to get it back. He must therefore descend into the dungeon and kill the Minotaur himself. The other Warriors may accompany him, but it must be the Barbarian who slays the beast and retrieves the sword.</flavor>
      <rules>This is a straightforward dungeon. The Warriors must find the pit, and the Barbarian must slay the Minotaur who lives in it and reclaim his father's sword. The Barbarian does not want any help with killing the Minotaur, not even magic or missile weapons. This means that the Barbarian is the only Warrior that will get any gold for killing the Minotaur. If the Barbarian manages to retrieve the sword, while using it he gets +1 on his roll to go berserk. When the Warriors reach the objective room do not roll on the Objective Room Monster Table. When the Warriors enter the objective room place a Minotaur in any square in the pit. The Minotaur will not climb out of the pit unless attacked by a Warrior with missile weapons or magic. The Minotaur attacks in the Monsters' Phase as normal, but this Minotaur is particularly powerful and gets an extra 5 Wounds. Once the Minotaur is defeated, the Warriors may retrieve the sword and escape the dungeon through the portcullis in the far wall.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="Hell's Gate" generic="false">
      <flavor>In the dungeons below Karak Azgal, a gate has been opened by evil sorcery. The gate leads to the plains of the Dark Lands, and monsters are continually spewing out of its black depths into the bowels of Karak Azgal. The more Monsters that gather in the depths of the ruined Dwarf city, the greater the threat to the Old World, so a party of brave Warriors must venture into the city and seal the gate.</flavor>
      <rules>The gate is located in the fighting pit. When the Warriors enter the objective room, consult the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters are in it. The Monsters are placed at the far end of the pit, next to the gate, but will swarm out to engulf the Warriors during the first Monsters' Phase. The Monsters may climb out of the pit with no Movement penalty. There may be so many Monsters coming through the gate that they spill out of the pit anyway. Once the Warriors kill the Monsters, they must try to seal the gate permanently. This can only be done with a complex invocation that only the Wizard can perform. At the start of the Warriors' Phase, the player controlling the Wizard may roll between 1 and 6 dice. If one or more of the dice comes up as a 6 and none of the dice comes up as a 1, the gate is sealed and the Warriors have succeeded in their quest. If any of the dice come up as a 1 the gate remains open that turn, no matter how many 6s are rolled. The Wizard may try and seal the gate once per turn. At the start of each Monsters' Phase that the gate is open, and while there are no Monsters on the board, draw an Event Card. Monsters will continue to appear until the gate is closed. If the Warriors seal the gate and escape alive they are rewarded with one item of treasure each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="Blood Debt" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Warriors must repay a debt that they incurred in an earlier adventure. The Wizard Vestigkalass rescued them from certain death in the dungeons below Crookback Mountain some months ago, in exchange for ten years of their memories, which he has stored in a cursed mirror. The only way the Warriors can regain those memories is to pay him 2,000 gold, or kill the pets of his arch-rival, the evil Sorcerer Grachnach. The only problems for the Warriors are that they do not have 2,000 gold with which to pay the ransom, and that Grachnach's pets are two blood-crazed Minotaurs. Grachnach lives in a carefully concealed labyrinth close to Mad Dog Pass, and is away on some evil errand at the moment. Now is the time for the Warriors to strike.</flavor>
      <rules>The Warriors' main objective is to enter the dungeon and kill Grachnach's Minotaurs, who are kept chained up in the fighting pit. Of course, if they find treasure totalling over 2,000 gold between them en route, they may leave immediately and pay the ransom instead. To complicate matters, while the Warriors are in the dungeon there is a chance that Grachnach will catch them. Every time an Unexpected Event that reveals monsters occurs, roll 1D6. If you score a 1 or 2, Grachnach has returned. Grachnach has been scouring the mountains for Monsters to join his warband, and has returned with his new followers. He will not fight the Warriors himself, preferring to send his servants to crush them while he waits a safe distance away. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Grachnach has recruited, and place them on the board along with the Monsters generated by the Unexpected Event. This only happens once. When the Warriors reach the objective room do not roll on the Objective Room Monster Table. When they enter the objective room place the two Minotaurs in any squares in the pit. The Minotaurs will not climb out of the pit unless attacked by a Warrior with missile weapons or magic. The Minotaurs attack in the Monsters' Phase as normal. Once the Minotaurs are defeated, the Warriors may escape through the trapdoor at the bottom of the fighting pit. On their return Vestigkalass gives them their memories back, although he is not sure whose memories are whose.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Man Eater" generic="false">
      <flavor>In the Drak Wald Forest of the Empire there are rumours circulating of a man-eating monster that is raiding nearby villages and eating the inhabitants. According to the story, the monster is a great Minotaur, but no-one has actually seen the beast and lived to tell the tale. The villagers are so worried that they are staying indoors and doing no work. The local sheriffs have intervened to solve the problem once and for all. They have located the entrance to a cave system, deep in the gloomy forest, and have employed the Warriors to kill the beast that lives within. However, it is not certain that the monster is a Minotaur at all, as the villagers are renowned for scaremongering.</flavor>
      <rules>When the Warriors reach the fighting pit, roll on the Objective Room Monster Table, subtracting 1 from the dice roll to determine the nature of the beast and its pack, though a roll of 1 still counts as 1. If the beast turns out to be a Minotaur, the Warriors must kill it and return its head to the village. If they are successful, they are rewarded with all the villagers' wealth. Unfortunately, this amounts to no more than 10 gold each, as it is a very poor village. If the beast is not a Minotaur, the Warriors are scorned by the villagers, who do not believe them, and go unrewarded.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Free the Prisoners" generic="false">
      <flavor>During a recent raid on Miragliano, the Skaven took around twenty wealthy and influential citizens as captives, and have been making all manner of unreasonable and outrageous threats ever since. The Skaven know full well that their unconditional demands to hand over all the wealth, women and children of the city will never be agreed to, but it gives them a good excuse to send back portions of their victims as proof that they mean business. The Warriors have been employed to enter the Blighted Marshes and rescue the prisoners from the dungeons of the Chaos ratmen.</flavor>
      <rules>The prisoners are being kept below the fighting pit, in a network of cells and guardrooms. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine the guardians of these cells, reading any Goblins as Skaven. When the guardians are dead, each player rolls a dice. The number rolled is the number of prisoners his Warrior finds alive. Every prisoner a Warrior finds gives him 1D6 x 20 gold for freeing them. At the bottom of the cell complex, there is a secret door that leads to the marshes above and to safety. In their weakened state the prisoners have not been able to open it, but the Warriors have no trouble. They soon smash it down and take the captives to freedom.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>

  <objectiveRoom name="FIRECHASM">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de la Firechasm sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual. La ambientacion especifica de la Firechasm no se aplica si no eliges una aventura concreta.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="Destroy the Warpstone Icon" generic="false">
      <flavor>Rumours abound of a powerful long-lost Skaven artefact that has been rediscovered in the Worlds Edge Mountains. The artefact is a skull-shaped icon made from raw warpstone, and its mutating powers are said to be beyond imagination. The icon must be destroyed at all costs to stop the Skaven reclaiming it. Unfortunately, the only way to destroy the icon is to hurl it into the cleansing flames of the firechasm.</flavor>
      <rules>The first dungeon room that the Warriors enter contains a sturdy iron casket holding the icon. When the Warriors have completed the room's event, keep the dungeon room card next to the leader's Adventure Record sheet to remind yourself that the Warriors have the casket. When the Warriors reach the firechasm, they must overcome the defenders of the chamber and hurl the warpstone icon into the flames. Roll once on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine the Monsters that are guarding the firechasm. If the icon is thrown into the chasm it is instantly consumed with a roar of lurid green flames. The room begins to collapse, and the Warriors must get out straight away or be crushed. To escape, the Warriors must cross the chasm and exit through a secret door that opens in the far wall, behind the stone dragon. The Warriors must escape within 2 turns of killing all the Monsters and hurling the icon into the chasm. After that point, the whole room caves in, killing any Warriors still inside. Each Warrior who escapes the dungeon is rewarded with 1D6 x 100 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="Banish the Daemon" generic="false">
      <flavor>The great Wizards of the Empire have scried out a powerful, brooding presence growing below the ancient Dwarf hold of Karak Azgal. As yet, they believe the presence to be relatively weak, and therefore probably bound to some material artefact such as a statue while it gathers strength. Although they do not know its purpose, they suspect that it may be a lesser daemon of the Chaos Powers, trapped in the rocks below the earth in ages past and freed by the incessant digging of the Goblins and Orcs as they search for the lost treasure of the Dwarfs who once inhabited the city. The truth is that the daemon has escaped the prison of rock that held it for so long, and is now resident in a statue of a great fire dragon in an ancient temple, the firechasm. Soon it will fully awaken, and walk the world once more. The Wizards have employed the Warriors to destroy the daemon and ensure that this never happens.</flavor>
      <rules>Each Warrior has been given a magic sword that can only be used once. These blades are the only weapons that can damage the daemon. Against other Monsters the swords hit automatically, whatever their wielder attacks with. To determine the Monsters that are guarding the firechasm, roll once on the Objective Room Monster Table. The magic swords are the only things that will kill the daemon. To destroy it, the Warriors must stand next to the stone dragon at the far end of the firechasm and strike it. For each blow made by one of the swords on the dragon roll 1D6. On a score of 5 or 6, the dragon and the daemon are destroyed. After one blow, each sword is destroyed. If the Warriors kill the daemon, the adventure is over and they are rewarded with 1D6 x 100 gold each. If the daemon is not killed, it becomes enraged and animates the statue. Each Warrior suffers 4D6 Wounds, modified for Toughness and armour, as the dragon breathes fiery, superheated liquid over them. Fortunately, the gouts of flame scorch an ancient tapestry hanging on one of the walls, revealing a passageway leading out to daylight. Any survivors may escape without further harm.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="Extinguish the Flames" generic="false">
      <flavor>Below the lost Dwarf stronghold of Karak Vlag, the ancient forge fires still burn. Now occupied by evil creatures, the flames' magical energies are being used to create chaotic and cursed weapons. The forges must be extinguished before their new masters learn how to manufacture weapons of even more awesome power. The Dwarf Lord of Zhufbar is host to the descendants of the lords of Karak Vlag, and shares their fears. Although the quenching of the ancient flames seems an act of unthinkable wrong, it is the only option available to prevent the creation of a greater evil. The exiled lords of Karak Vlag know that only the first item forged in the magical fires, a ring, can extinguish the flames. As the ring is an ancient Dwarf treasure, it must be hurled into the chasm by a Dwarf. If the Dwarf is killed, then the Warriors have, by default, failed.</flavor>
      <rules>The Warriors must first defeat the guardians of the firechasm, as only then can the Dwarf hurl the ring into its depths. The ring is located on one of the claws of a dragon statue that decorates the firechasm. Roll once on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine the defenders. Once the defenders are killed, the Dwarf may retrieve the ring. To retrieve it, the Dwarf must be standing next to the statue. He may try to get the ring once per turn, at the start of the Power Phase. Roll 1D6 for each attempt. On 1-2 the ring is firmly stuck, and the noise the Warriors are making attracts trouble: take an Event Card. On 3-4 the ring is stuck and he must try again next turn. On 5-6 the ring slips easily off the dragon's claw, and a great panel of stone behind the dragon rolls away, revealing a passageway to the outside world. To be able to throw the ring into the chasm, there must be no Monsters in the room, and the Dwarf must be standing in a square adjacent to the chasm. As the ring is thrown into the chasm, the flames leap upwards and envelop anyone standing nearby. Each Warrior in a square adjacent to the edge of the chasm suffers 2D6 Wounds, modified for Toughness and armour. The flames then slowly flicker and die, and the Warriors may now escape via the tunnel. Each surviving Warrior receives one Treasure Card.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="Destroy the Bridge" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Warriors are being pursued through the Worlds Edge Mountains, via tunnels deep below ground, by the inhabitants of the dark under-realms. With them, the Warriors have the long-lost crown of the ancient Dwarf Kings of Mount Silverspear, now known as Mount Grimfang, which has been retrieved from the evil creatures that stole it. The Warriors have a final obstacle to overcome before they reach safety. The dangerous route that they follow leads to the firechasm, across which lies a slender bridge. If they can cross the bridge and destroy it before their pursuers arrive in great numbers, they will gain precious time and will probably escape from the mountains alive. If not, they will surely perish as the evil hordes overwhelm them.</flavor>
      <rules>When the Warriors reach the firechasm, they must fight whatever Monsters are there before crossing the bridge. Roll once on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what is in the room. Once the Warriors have crossed the bridge, they must break it to prevent pursuit. Any Warrior who is in the square at the end of the bridge, directly between the ropes that hold it up, may attempt to destroy the bridge during the Warriors' Phase instead of making an attack. Roll 1D6 and add the Warrior's Strength to the score. If the total is 8 or over, the bridge is destroyed. At the start of each turn in which the bridge is not destroyed, take an Event Card in addition to any Unexpected Events that occur. Any Monsters generated by these Event Cards must be placed on the side of the chasm next to the door, as they represent the Monsters who are pursuing the Warriors through the dungeon. If a Minotaur appears, it may leap the chasm without using the bridge, taking two squares of its Movement to do so. Once the bridge is destroyed, the Warriors may escape through a small tunnel to the rear of the cave, behind the dragon statue. Each surviving Warrior is rewarded with 1D6 x 50 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Return the Dragon's Eye" generic="false">
      <flavor>Centuries ago, the great Dwarf hold of Karak Azgal fell to rampaging Orc hordes. In the last days before the city fell, the Dwarf smiths and forgemasters of the realm gathered together under their Lords' directions. Their aim was to bind a dragon to the city to smite down its foes, and thus they built a great statue in a cavern far underground to act as a magical focus. Much of their power went into the two great gems that served as the dragon's eyes. A dispute raged for years to decide who owned these precious gems, as two rival Dwarf Lords each claimed to be the rightful owner. One of the embittered Dwarfs crept into the chamber before the ceremony and stole one of the dragon's eyes. Shortly after, Karak Azgal fell to the Orcs and the unbound dragon arrived. The dragon has since been slain by a great Dwarf hero, but the city itself has never been cleared of the Orcs and Goblins who now rule its gloomy caverns. The Dwarfs blame this misfortune on the theft of the gem, and legend tells that Karak Azgal is cursed unless the gem is replaced. Now the gem has been found, and the guardian and self-appointed ruler-in-exile of the city has given the Warriors permission to try and return the stone, as long as they agree to give him half of whatever treasure they find on the way.</flavor>
      <rules>The Dwarf must carry the gem and put it back into the dragon's eye socket. To put the gem back, he has to stand in a square adjacent to the dragon's head. If the Dwarf is killed, the Warriors fail by default. When the Warriors enter the firechasm, roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what is in the room. These Monsters must be killed before the gem can be placed back in the dragon's eye socket. If the gem is successfully replaced, a trapdoor opens in the plinth that the statue sits on. Inside are the remains of the dragon's hoard: 3D6 x 100 gold for each Warrior, of which half must be given up as agreed.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Preserve the Fires" generic="false">
      <flavor>The magical flames of the Dwarf temple, the Firechasm, are in danger of being extinguished by the foul Skaven who now occupy the ancient Dwarf city of Karak Azgal. They plan to fill the entire chasm with debris, hoping to stem the magma flow and cause a pressure build-up deep underground. Even now, their engineers are channelling tunnels to send the diverted magma spurting into the areas of the city occupied by Orcs and other creatures, as well as hopefully burying the Dwarf fortress occupied by Kargun Skalfson that sits at the entrance to Karak Azgal. If the Skaven succeed, there is a good chance that the ancient Dwarf citadel will be sealed off forever, leaving them free to search for the lost Dwarf treasure hoards rumoured to lie in its deepest halls. Spies have reported this fiendish plan to the Emperor and his Dwarf allies. Other bands of Warriors will attempt to block the tunnels created by the Skaven to channel the magma. Your band of Warriors has been chosen to stop the damming of the firechasm itself.</flavor>
      <rules>When the Warriors enter the firechasm, do not roll on the Objective Room Monster Table. Instead, the room is guarded by 1D6 + 6 Skaven warriors. Place all but one according to the normal rules for setting up Monsters. The other Skaven should be placed on the far side of the chasm, next to the dragon statue. He is the head Skaven engineer, and mastermind of the foul plot. As soon as the Warriors enter the firechasm roll 2D6. The Warriors have this number of turns in which to kill the guards, get across the chasm and kill the engineer. If the Warriors succeed, they may escape through a secret tunnel at the back of the chamber, and are rewarded with 1D6 x 50 gold each. If they fail to kill the engineer in time, roll 1D6. On 1-2 the engineer operates a steel lever and tons of debris plunge into the magma pool, killing all the Warriors and Skaven. On 3-4 the Warriors fail and the future of Karak Azgal lies in the hands of the other teams. On 5 the debris blocks the firechasm completely and the Warriors have failed utterly, though they may still make good their escape through a small passageway to the outside world. On 6 the engineer operates the lever to drop tons of debris into the chasm, but it snaps off in his paws, giving the Warriors another 1D6 turns in which to kill him as he fixes it. If he is still not dead by then, roll on the table again.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>

  <objectiveRoom name="FOUNTAIN OF LIGHT">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de la Fountain of Light sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual. No se aplican rituales ni objetivos adicionales sobre la fuente.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="Clearwater" generic="false">
      <flavor>In the south of the Empire lies Bugman's Brewery, where the Dwarf brewers create the finest beers in the Warhammer World. Always striving for perfection in his brews, Bugman has heard of a dried-up fountain that used to be the source of the purest water in the world, and purer water makes better beer. The story is that a potion of dizzying power must be poured into the fountain, a whole barrelful, if the waters are ever to flow again. The only powerful dizzying potion available in barrels that Bugman can think of is a cask of his precious Bugman's XXXXXX Superbrew. The legend tells that the fountain lies in the caves of the Black Mountains, somewhere between Karak Hirn and Black Fire Pass. The Lord of Karak Hirn knows a cave system within the borders of his realm that fits the description, and has agreed to let four Warriors search for the fountain as long as he gets a free supply of the resulting beer. Of course, the cave system is not actually part of the city of Karak Hirn, more a long abandoned labyrinth now populated by all manner of evil beasts.</flavor>
      <rules>Nominate one of the Warriors to carry the cask of beer. The chosen Warrior's Movement is reduced by 1 square per turn while carrying it. There is plenty of beer in the barrel and, if they wish, each Warrior can drink from it. If each Warrior drinks from it more than once, however, there will not be enough left to activate the fountain. Any Warrior who drinks from the barrel must roll 1D6. On 1-2 the Warrior falls senseless to the floor for the rest of the turn and everyone thinks him dead, but at the start of the next turn he awakens healed by 1D6 Wounds. On 3 he is at -1 Weapon Skill, -1 Movement and +1 Attacks for the rest of the adventure. On 4 he is at -1 Weapon Skill and +1 Attacks for the rest of the adventure. On 5 the brew heals 1D6 + 1 Wounds. On 6 the brew restores the Warrior to full Wounds. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the fountain room contains. When they are defeated, the Warrior carrying the barrel may pour it into the fountain, at which point fresh waters spring forth, the clearest ever seen. The adventure is then over, and the Warriors may make their way out of the dungeon via a passageway to the surface, back to Bugman's Brewery to report the good news. Each Warrior receives 1D6 x 20 gold, plus a 2% royalty on all sales of Bugman's Freshbrew XI.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="Skaven Curse!" generic="false">
      <flavor>The water supply for the city of Miragliano comes from many sources. The main supply is from the rivers that run down from the Vaults, but the most precious comes from an ancient shrine hidden in a deep cave system, from which springs a gushing fountain. This fountain provides the purest water in Miragliano, and has done so for countless years. The Skaven of Skavenblight have found the fountain and polluted it, filling it with the twisting influence of warpstone. Already a sickness spreads in Miragliano, and a large reward has been offered to anyone who can find a cure. A far-seeing academic has guessed at the truth, and wishes to find out if the waters are indeed polluted. He has gathered your band of Warriors together to seek the source of the waters and, if need be, cleanse it.</flavor>
      <rules>Do not roll on the Objective Room Monster Table. Instead, the fountain room is guarded by 12 Skaven warriors. When all the Skaven defending the fountain are killed, the Warriors must remove the warpstone from the fountain. There is enough warpstone in the fountain for each Warrior to take a heavy load. To remove it, a Warrior must be in a square adjacent to the fountain. Upon removing it, roll 2D6. The Warrior loses that number of Wounds with no modifiers for Toughness or armour. This may kill the Warrior, but the warpstone is removed. Each Warrior must remove one load. No Warrior can try more than once, as the warpstone's power will kill him immediately if he tries a second time. Once the fountain is purified, the Warriors may return to Miragliano to claim the reward of 1D6 x 50 gold each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="The Waters of Fate" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Emperor's Wizards tell him that the mystical signs warn of an imminent invasion, but they can see no further than this, as dark powers cloud their vision. They have no idea if the assault will come from the Chaos Wastes of the far North, from the Orcs of the Dark Lands to the East, or from some other unsuspected quarter. The most aged Wizard Lord of the Celestial college suggests that the answer lies in a magical pool, the Fountain of Fate, which holds the secrets of all things. While the Empire prepares all its borders for war, a party of four brave Warriors is gathered to search for the fountain, reputed to be found somewhere below the Middle Mountains.</flavor>
      <rules>This is a two-part adventure: the first part is to find the fountain, the second is to return once more to the surface and to safety. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the fountain room contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may look into the fountain. While there are Monsters alive in the fountain room a magical aura prevents the fountain from operating. Each Warrior may look into the fountain once and once only, and must be standing in a square adjacent to it to do so. When a Warrior looks into the fountain, roll 1D6. On a 1, 2 or 3, nothing is revealed. On a 4, 5 or 6, the fountain shimmers and shows Orc and Goblin armies massing in the Worlds Edge Mountains: this is where the attack will come from. Each Warrior may also drink once from the fountain. Roll 1D6. On 1, the waters burn the Warrior from the inside and he dies. On 2-6, the waters heal the Warrior back up to full Wounds and, if he is the Wizard, restore him to his original quota of Power Tokens. As soon as the last Warrior who wishes to has looked into the fountain, a door creaks open in the far wall. Take another 1D6 + 2 Dungeon Cards and create a new Dungeon Deck. These are the rooms the Warriors must get through before they reach the surface. Use them like the normal Dungeon Deck, exploring beyond the new doorway in the fountain room. When the Warriors reach the final room or corridor, they notice light shining in from a hole in the roof and scramble up to return to the Emperor. If they discovered the source of the impending attack, the Warriors gain 2D6 x 100 gold each. If they do not, they get nothing.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="The Sword of True Kingship" generic="false">
      <flavor>It is claimed that an ancient sword holds the secret of the kingship of one of the small realms of the Border Princes. When immersed in water of unparalleled purity, it is said that it reveals the name of the true king of the realm. Unfortunately, no water save that of the legendary Fountain of Light is pure enough to cause the sword to reveal the name. The four Warriors must therefore take the sword and journey to the Middle Mountains to find the fountain. Once there, they can determine which of the three princes who claim the kingship, Bardin, Rudin and Gredin, is the rightful heir.</flavor>
      <rules>Before the Warriors embark on the adventure, each player must secretly choose the prince whom they believe to be the true king and write his name down on their Adventure Record sheet. Nominate one Warrior to carry the sword. If the Warrior decides to wield it in combat rather than his own weapon, it causes 1 extra Wound when it hits. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the fountain room contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may put the sword in the fountain, at which point the name of the true king is magically engraved in its blade. Roll 1D6: on 1-2 Bardin is named, on 3-4 Rudin, on 5-6 Gredin. As the sword is plunged into the waters, there is an earth-shattering roar and the ceiling of the chamber begins to collapse inwards. Each player must roll 1D6 and add his Warrior's Initiative. If the total is 7 or more, the Warrior avoids the falling rubble. If it is less than 7, the Warrior takes 3D6 Wounds, modified by Toughness and armour. As the dust clears, light pours into the chamber revealing a route to the outside world. The Warriors may now return to crown the new king. Warriors that chose the correct prince get 500 gold. Warriors that chose the wrong prince get 1D6 x 30 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Nurgle's Rot" generic="false">
      <flavor>The city of Praag, which lies close to the border of the Chaos Wastes, has been struck with the dreaded Nurgle's Rot, a disease spread by the foul Power of pestilence and decay. The death toll is mounting, but the physicians in the city are powerless unless they can find a cure. There appears to be only one hope. In the ancient myths and songs of Kislev, a fountain is described that has waters so pure and so cold that any creature harbouring any evil nature is frozen to death as soon as it touches the waters. The doctors of Praag believe that this may provide a cure for the disease. The fountain is said to lie in the mountains north of the High Pass. The Warriors must seek it out and return with some of the precious liquid. They are given a special container in which to carry the water.</flavor>
      <rules>First declare which Warrior is carrying the special container. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the fountain room contains. Once the Monsters are dead, the Warrior carrying the container may attempt to take the waters. To do so he must stand in a square adjacent to the fountain. Roll 1D6. If the result is a 1, the Warrior attempting to take the water is not deemed pure enough of spirit and is killed. On any other result the water is safely transferred to the special container. If the attempt fails, another Warrior may try. As the first Warrior tries to take the waters he leans on one of the stone gargoyle heads surrounding the fountain. As he does so, it makes a soft click and an ominous creaking is heard from the far wall. With a groan of stone on stone, an ancient door slides open, leading to the outside world. The surviving Warriors may now take the water back to Praag. The Warrior bearing the water gets a 500 gold reward, while all the other Warriors get 100 gold each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Fountain of Lost Souls" generic="false">
      <flavor>A mighty Sorcerer, resident in Marienburg, wishes to find the Burning Fountain, a mythical place rumoured to exist somewhere in the caves below the Dragonback Mountains. Scrying its exact location has proven to be of no use, but he has managed to obtain a picture of the fountain itself in his sorcerous mirror, confirming that it does indeed lie somewhere under the mountains, and is guarded by ferocious monsters. No matter how much gold he offers, no one can be found to venture that far afield, so he has cunningly entrapped the four Warriors under a curse, capturing their souls in glowing gems. Using powerful magic, he has reached through his mirror and dropped these gems into the fountain. The Warriors have no choice but to find the fountain and retrieve their lost souls. The gems must be returned to the Sorcerer before he can reunite the Warriors' ethereal bodies with their physical bodies. He is apologetic about this underhand trick, but does promise rich rewards if the Warriors succeed in capturing some of the waters in a specially prepared container while they are there.</flavor>
      <rules>Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the fountain room contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may attempt to take the gems from the fountain. Roll 1D6 for each Warrior and add his Toughness. If the result is 6 or over, the Warrior survives the burning waters and retrieves his soul. If the number is 5 or less, the Warrior is consumed by the power of the water and dies in agony. While getting his gem, a Warrior may collect some of the water for the Sorcerer. If the Warriors return to the Sorcerer with some of the water he reunites their souls and bodies and gives each of them 2D6 x 50 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>

  <objectiveRoom name="TOMB CHAMBER">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de la Tomb Chamber sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual. No se aplica ningun ritual o prueba especial adicional en la tumba.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="Exorcism" generic="false">
      <flavor>Deep below Middenheim there is a maze of tunnels inhabited by all manner of evil creatures. No-one ventures into this dark realm, and the entrances in the city have been sealed for centuries. Now, however, an evil presence has been detected by the priests of Ulric, the holy leaders of the city. The source of this malign power is growing, and resides somewhere in the ancient catacombs below the city. The priests suspect it may be the spirit of a long dead Necromancer, returned to wreak havoc once again on the inhabitants of Middenheim. Like moths to a candle, other malign and twisted creatures are being drawn to the tunnels below Middenheim by this evil presence. Carrying holy artefacts from the temples of the city, the Warriors must descend into the catacombs to exorcise the evil before its power grows too strong to contain.</flavor>
      <rules>Each Warrior has been given a holy symbol of Ulric to take into the dungeon below Middenheim. These artefacts must be placed on top of the Necromancer's tomb to lay him to rest. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the tomb chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, each Warrior may move to a square adjacent to the tomb and lay his artefact on the tomb lid in an attempt to exorcise the evil that dwells within it. At the start of the next turn, during the Power Phase, each player must roll 1D6. If any of the dice score a 1, take another Event Card as the evil spirit summons vile creatures to its aid. Once these are killed, the Warriors may try again. This continues until the Warriors do not roll any 1s, at which point the spirit is destroyed and the evil lifted. The Warriors may now make their way to the surface to be hailed as heroes. While in the tomb, the Warriors find 1D6 x 50 gold each, plus they get a further 1D6 x 50 gold each as reward for their part in the adventure.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="The Sword of the Deathking" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Fortress of Vorag lies beyond the Badlands, on the Plain of Bone. It was from this proud, cruel citadel that Ashkral Deathking, a follower of the all-powerful Necromancer Nagash, ruled many centuries ago. Endless legions of the dead strode to battle at his command, and the living fell before their unearthly might. When Ashkral was overthrown by the Orc Warlord Morak Bloodcrusher, the dying Necromancer swore that he would one day return. His shattered body was taken by his acolytes to a secret place deep beneath Cripple Peak, on the shores of the Sour Sea. However, the Deathking was not truly dead; he was merely in a state of limbo between this life and the next. The only weapon truly able to kill him was the sword he himself had wielded. This was to be buried with him so that it could not fulfil its destiny. On the way to his tomb, the acolytes carrying the sword were ambushed and killed, and the blade was hurled into the Sour Sea. After the most recent eruption of nearby Karag Haraz, an ancient sword was thrown up onto the surface, and the entrance to a long-sealed dungeon was revealed. The myth of the Deathking no longer looks like a mere story.</flavor>
      <rules>Nominate one of the Warriors to carry the sword. If used in combat, the blade causes +1D6 Wounds on a successful attack, but automatically strikes an adjacent Warrior if the to-hit roll is an unmodified 1. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the tomb chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may lift the tomb and slay the Deathking. Before they can kill him, they must overcome his magic. Roll 1D6 for each Warrior taking part in the battle of wills. If the combined score is 13 or more, the curse is broken and the Deathking can be slain. If the total is less than 13, the Warriors' minds are broken by the power of the Necromancer and they become mindless thralls of the Deathking. In the tomb is 1D6 x 100 gold, to be shared equally amongst the Warriors. Once the dungeon is finished, the Warriors may safely make their way to freedom.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="Return the Crown" generic="false">
      <flavor>Between the Dwarf hold of Karak Izor and the Dwarf Sea Fortress of Barak Varr lies a small realm, a border principality known as Heldegrad. Normally allied to the cause of the Dwarfs, the rulers of this small state have been thrown into turmoil by the discovery of the ancient and long-lost tomb of their ancestor-kings, renowned to contain the true crown of the realm. This labyrinthine burial ground lies near Karak Izor, and the king demands that the crown of his forefathers is returned to him by the Dwarfs or he will shut down all the trade routes from Barak Varr to Karak Izor. Not wishing to plunge the longstanding allies into bloodshed, and acknowledging the king's right to the ancient crown, the Dwarf Lord of Karak Izor has allowed the Warriors to descend into the long-forgotten tunnels in search of the ancient relic.</flavor>
      <rules>In the first dungeon room that the Warriors enter there is an ancient chest, locked and chained to the ground. Once they have resolved the Event Card for this room, the Warriors may examine it. The chest bears the heraldic crest of Heldegrad on its lid, and obviously contains the crown. Unfortunately, it cannot be opened or shifted, even using magic. To open it the Warriors must find the key that lies elsewhere in the dungeon and return here with it. Put the Dungeon Card for this room to one side to remind yourself where the chest is. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the tomb chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may search the chamber, whereupon they find a key in a small alcove in the side of the tomb. This key will open the chest in the first dungeon room. The Warriors must return to the chest, turn by turn, testing for Unexpected Events in the Power Phase as usual. Any dungeon rooms that they pass through for a second time do not trigger new Event Cards. The chest contains the crown, which may now be returned to Heldegrad. Once the crown is returned, each Warrior gets one Treasure Card.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="The Hero Awakens" generic="false">
      <flavor>To the north of the Empire, bordering on the Northern Wastes and Troll Country, lies the frozen land of Kislev. Beset by the rampaging hordes of Chaos, Kislev is teetering on the brink of destruction, and its people are losing heart as they suffer defeat after defeat. The Ice Queen of Kislev knows a legend of just such a hero, Heinrich Sigmasson, reputed to be a descendant of Sigmar himself, who led a glorious campaign against the Chaos hordes in years past. At the final battle, however, he suffered a mortal wound, and was buried in a tomb somewhere in the far-off mountains. Even on his deathbed he promised to return if Kislev was once again threatened by the Chaos hordes. The Ice Queen has asked the Warriors to journey into the mountains and reawaken Heinrich so that he can keep his promise.</flavor>
      <rules>Before the Warriors depart, the Ice Queen gives the Wizard a shard of glass that she believes will help awaken Heinrich. The shard contains 1D6 + 2 Power Tokens, rolled at the start of the adventure. The shard may be used at any time to augment the Wizard's spell casting. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the tomb chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may try to awaken Heinrich. Looking inside the tomb, his body is perfectly preserved, and it appears as if he is asleep rather than dead. Heinrich can only be awakened by the Wizard, and he has one chance to wake him, during the first Warriors' Phase after all the Monsters in the room are dead. Roll 1D6 and add all the Power Points left in the shard, plus any Power Points and Power Tokens that the Wizard has left. If the total is 12 or more, the spell is broken and Heinrich awakens. If the total is less than 12, Heinrich's body crumbles to dust and the Warriors have failed. If the Warriors succeed, Heinrich will lead them back to Kislev via a concealed door at the rear of the tomb chamber. Each Warrior is rewarded with 1D6 x 50 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Destroy the Tomb" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Dwarf Lords of Karak Azul have recently deciphered an ancient Dwarf scroll written in runes so old that even the Dwarfs have taken many years to identify their true meaning. Early on, the Dwarfs realised that it described a shrine of great magical power located somewhere in the Worlds Edge Mountains, beneath the tomb of a mighty Warrior. The Dwarfs knew that to find the shrine would put them in control of the most powerful forces they could possibly unleash upon their foes. The exact location was a mystery until recently when, after many years of painstaking work, it was finally pinpointed. To the Dwarfs' horror, they realised that the shrine was directly below the Orc Fortress of Iron Rock. The Dwarfs decided that the shrine had to be destroyed to prevent it falling into Orc hands. An attack by a large force would raise the Orcs' suspicions, so the Dwarfs have asked the Warriors to sneak into the Orc stronghold to destroy the shrine.</flavor>
      <rules>The shrine is in the tomb chamber, directly beneath the tomb itself. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the tomb chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Dwarf may attempt to destroy the tomb. Only the Dwarf may damage the tomb, as he is the only one bearing a Dwarf axe. None of the other Warriors can damage it. As long as the Dwarf is standing in a square adjacent to the tomb he automatically hits it. The tomb has a Toughness of 3 and has 12 Wounds. At the start of each turn in which the tomb remains intact and while there are no Monsters on the board, take an Event Card. Before the tomb can be hit again, the Event Card must be resolved. Once the Warriors have destroyed the tomb, and the shrine with it, a gaping hole is revealed in the rubble, leading down into blackness. This tunnel eventually leads out of the dungeon and back to Karak Azul. Each Warrior is rewarded with one Treasure Card.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Identify" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Warriors have been employed to carry out an apparently simple task, for which they will be well paid. All they have to do is solve an inheritance dispute between two Imperial Lords by correctly identifying a body buried in a far away tomb in the Worlds Edge Mountains.</flavor>
      <rules>Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the tomb chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may lift back the lid of the tomb and determine who the body belongs to. Roll 1D6. On 1-3 the skeleton has no teeth. On 4-6 the skeleton is missing its left hand. Having identified the body, the Warriors may make their way to the surface. As they have killed all the Monsters in the dungeon, the way out is clear and they may exit without even rolling for Unexpected Events. If the skeleton has no teeth, it belongs to the household of Luckstein, an honourable family who reward the Warriors with 1D6 x 100 gold each. If the skeleton is missing its left hand, it belongs to the household of Bravia, whose current Lord is a scheming, arrogant individual who refuses to pay them.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>

  <objectiveRoom name="DREAD KING'S THRONE ROOM">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de Dread King's Throne Room sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con las reglas normales de Dread King's Throne Room. Usa la tabla de monstruos de Catacombs of Terror, aplica las reglas de salas multinivel y coloca al Dread King en el estrado con el Grimoire Necris frente al trono.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="Find the Orb of Chalcidar" generic="false">
      <flavor>Rumours have reached the Empire: dark tales of a brooding evil lurking within the pyramid mountain known as the Twisted Spire. This cursed peak lies in the far off Lands of the Dead, amongst the shifting sands and bleached bones of Khemri and Quatar. The Twisted Spire is said to be the time worn remains of an ancient pyramid, the resting place of a once powerful king. It is said that a black soul has returned to haunt this tomb, who plans to blight the world with death and pain. This evil lord of the Undead is known only as Van Damneg the Dread King. The wizards of the Empire need time to consider what course of action to take. While they ponder, the power of the Dread King grows. The Warriors are called upon to seek out the ancient Orb of Chalcidar, as it may be powerful enough to bind the Dread King forever in his pyramid tomb, if not destroy him outright. This powerful magical artefact was stolen by Gunther Laranscheld some months ago, and spirited away to his stronghold Spine Mountain Keep, in the Black Mountains. For the Warriors to stand any chance whatsoever of defeating the Dread King, they must retrieve this orb from the clutches of Laranscheld. Spine Mountain Keep is a dark and dangerous place, and the Warriors must have quick wits and brave hearts to survive this deadly challenge.</flavor>
      <rules>Do not include the Dread King Event card in the Event deck for this adventure, as he is far off in the Lands of the Dead. Whenever the Warriors find a room, they may search it for the lost orb. They may only do this once any event triggered by the room has been completed, and so long as there are no Monsters on the board. If the Warriors want to search the room, it takes a whole turn, during which they may do nothing else except heal each other if they have the means. To search a room, place all the Catacombs of Terror counters in a cup. To find the orb, one of the players rolls 1D6, and another takes a counter at random from the cup. The number on the counter is added to the score rolled on the dice. If the total is 8 or more, then the players have found the orb. Remember that whatever they score, a 1 is a 1 and always fails. Each room can only be searched once per turn, and one dice roll is made per room, not once per Warrior. Once a counter is out of the cup, the Warriors keep it, even if they did not find the orb. When they next search, they add the totals of all the counters that are out of the cup to the dice roll. As soon as the Skull counter is picked, their search is over for now. The room they were searching does not have the orb in it, so there is no point searching further. All the counters go back in the cup, and the Warriors must take an Event card immediately because the noise of their searching has disturbed some evil force within the catacombs. As soon as they find the orb, each Warrior also takes a Treasure card. If the Warriors do not find the orb by the time they come to the objective room, then whatever else happens in the room, the orb will be there. Use the Dread King's Throne Room, which in this adventure is the lair of Laranscheld the Necromancer. Do not roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to see what Monsters lurk inside. The Warriors will face Laranscheld, Luthor, the Grimoire Necris, 1D3 Tomb Guardians and 2D6 Skeleton Bowmen. If the Warriors find the orb before the objective room, they may make off with it without venturing any further. However, such is the fervour within the Empire to stop this insidious Undead menace, that the Warriors have been offered an extra 30 gold for every servant of Undeath that they destroy, on top of whatever gold value the Monsters are worth anyway.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="The Orb and the Dread King" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Wizard has been entrusted with the Orb of Chalcidar, a powerful weapon to be used against the Undead. Now the Warriors must venture far into the Lands of the Dead to the pyramid tomb known as the Twisted Spire. There they must try and destroy the Dread King, the malevolent and malign ruler of this bleak realm. If they fail, his power will grow beyond all telling, and the whole world will be threatened by his deathless legions.</flavor>
      <rules>The orb can be used once in the adventure. When the power of the orb is released all the Warriors gain +2 to their Strength for working out damage against Undead Monsters they hit in hand-to-hand combat. This lasts until the end of the turn. This adventure uses the special Catacombs counters. Take all six counters and put them in a mug or other opaque container, just like the Warrior counters. When the Warriors reach the Dread King's Throne Room do not place Van Damneg sitting in his throne, just put the throne model in place. The Wizard must place the orb in its socket within the back of the throne. To do this he must be standing next to the throne in the Warriors' Phase, and must make a successful to hit roll as if against an opponent with a Weapon Skill of 2, representing the baleful energies surrounding the throne. This counts as an attack. If he is successful, the magic of the throne is cut off, and the Dread King is trapped in his tomb, hopefully for ever more. Until the Wizard places the orb in its socket, all Power rolls of 1 or 2 mean that an Unexpected Event has occurred. Every time an Unexpected Event occurs within the Throne Room, take a Catacombs counter first. If this is the Skull counter Van Damneg has awoken. Place the Dread King on his throne; he can attack and cast spells as normal on the turn he appears. If it is any other counter, place it to one side and do not place it back with the others. Once the orb is in place and all the Monsters on the board are killed the Warriors may leave the Throne Room via a secret tunnel located behind the throne. Before they escape however, the Warriors manage to loot some useful equipment, previously stolen from the Dread King's victims. Each Warrior should take two Treasure cards.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="Banish the Spirit" generic="false">
      <flavor>Heroic Warriors have trapped the Dread King in his tomb, deep within the Lands of the Dead. Although his physical form can no more stride forth at the head of his Undead legions, the brooding spirit of the Dread King is strong, and not easily destroyed. Aided by the twisted Necromancer Gunther Laranscheld, his black spirit is slowly escaping its prison to coalesce in a place carefully prepared by the Necromancer. On the borders of the Lands of the Dead and Araby stands the city of Ka Sabaar. Little do the priests of the city know, but their temple is built upon an older, evil site of magical power. The Dread King seeks to use this pool of dark magic as a conduit for his evil spirit to escape the shackles which bind it. Even now, his evil form coalesces in the dark halls beneath the temple. As the dark power grows, the priests have been driven out by otherworldly night predators, and have offered the Warriors a substantial reward if they can destroy the Dread King and sanctify the temple.</flavor>
      <rules>Take the Fountain of Light Objective Room card and shuffle it into the top half of the Dungeon deck as well as the other six cards. Shuffle the Dread King's Throne Room card into the bottom half of the Dungeon deck as usual. Play proceeds as normal. The Fountain of Light contains three Event cards' worth of Monsters and traps. When the Warriors first enter the Fountain of Light turn over the top three Event cards to see what is in there. Once the Warriors have killed the Monsters in the room they must fill up their water skins with holy water from the Fountain of Light. This takes them a whole turn during which the Warriors must stand next to the fountain and may do nothing else except heal themselves. Once they have done this they must go to the Dread King's Throne Room. Once there, the Warriors must fight whatever creatures are found within, generated normally from the Objective Room Monsters table. Once they have defeated the foul creatures inside the Dread King's Throne Room, the Warriors sprinkle the holy water about the room, exorcising the spirits of the Undead forever and restoring the sanctity of the temple. The priests will give each Warrior 200 gold and an Objective Room Treasure card if they succeed in their quest.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="Retrieve the Grimoire" generic="false">
      <flavor>It appears that once again Gunther Laranscheld has cheated death. Thwarted before by brave Warriors, and left for dead on the sun-drenched deserts of the Lands of the Dead, his iron will alone kept him alive. Now he seeks vengeance. He has crept back into the forbidden libraries of the Empire and stolen a most terrible evil book, the dreaded Grimoire Necris. It is obvious that Laranscheld hopes to use the Grimoire to restore the Dread King to his former glory, bringing about a new era of death and despair to all mortal folk. The Warriors must quest into the dungeons of Laranscheld's old tower and kill him before he succeeds in joining his power to his patron, the Dread King of Twisted Spire.</flavor>
      <rules>Take the Necromancer Event card out of the Event deck. When you roll on the Objective Room Monster Table, replace the Dread King with Gunther Laranscheld. Laranscheld's minions are represented by the other Monsters in the objective room. Laranscheld should be placed at the far end of the room, next to the throne, where he is performing his ritual. His Grimoire Necris should be placed in the space before the throne. The Warriors must retrieve the Grimoire Necris before Laranscheld can complete the summoning. They have 2D6 turns to kill Laranscheld, starting from the first turn after they enter the objective room. If the 2D6 turns pass before the Warriors have killed the Necromancer, Laranscheld completes the ceremony. Place Van Damneg on his throne at the start of the next Power Phase. Van Damneg can cast spells and attack as normal on the turn he appears. Once they have prevented the summoning, or destroyed Van Damneg once and for all, they can return to the wizards of the Empire, where they will each receive a Treasure card and 150 gold as a reward.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Escape from the Depths" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Warriors are travelling back from an adventure in Spine Mountain Keep. One night, as they sleep fitfully in the mountains, they are set upon by a large Undead horde. Outnumbered and surprised, the Warriors have no chance, and are knocked unconscious. They awake to find themselves in a dank cell, chained up beside another prisoner. The prisoner tells them he has a way to escape, but they will have to leave through the throne room of the Dread King himself. The next day he is taken from the cell and led to the sacrificial altar of the Dread King. It seems that the blood of mortals is being used to free the Dread King from the realm of death, and even now he is close to overcoming the magic which holds him prisoner in his dark halls far away in the Lands of the Dead. The Necromancer Laranscheld and many of his minions are scouring the area for more victims.</flavor>
      <rules>Generate the dungeon as usual; the Warriors start just outside their cell. This adventure uses the special Catacombs counters. Take all six counters and put them in a mug or other opaque container, just like the Warrior counters. Every time an Unexpected Event occurs, as well as drawing the next Event card, take one of the Catacombs counters and place it, without looking, to one side. Place the Catacombs counters red face down next to the board. The Warriors manage to break free of their bonds and regain their equipment from the Zombie guards. They must hurry to reach the throne room before the Dread King appears. If they dawdle, however... When the Warriors enter the Dread King's Throne Room take all the Catacombs counters that have been selected and turn them over. If any of them is the Skull counter the Warriors are too late, Van Damneg has awoken. If the Skull counter has not been picked take the next two Event cards to see what is in the Dread King's Throne Room. If the Skull has been picked then roll on the Objective Room Monsters Table as normal. If the Warriors manage to kill all the Monsters in the Dread King's Throne Room they each snatch a piece of treasure before making their escape. Every Warrior gets a single Treasure card. Even though the Warriors have struck a blow to his gathering physical form, they know that they do not have the weapons to banish the Dread King forever. They must return to the Empire and gather magical weapons powerful enough to banish the Dread King once and for all.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="The Final Conflict" generic="false">
      <flavor>After an exhausting journey through the mountains, the Warriors are told by the wizards of the Empire that they must return to Twisted Spire and the Catacombs of Terror to deal the death blow to the Dread King before his power overwhelms the world. Despite all attempts to destroy him, the Dread King's spirit has returned once more to his ancient haunts. Rumours abound that he seeks to awaken Nagash himself once he is restored to power, and this must be prevented at all costs. After much research, it has been discovered that the means to achieve this are kept deep in the Twisted Spire itself. The Dread King cunningly possesses the only weapons powerful enough to destroy him. The Warriors must find these weapons before facing the Dread King.</flavor>
      <rules>Before playing this adventure, remove the Dread King Event card from the Event deck, and place the special Catacombs counters in a cup or mug. Whenever the Warriors finish a combat, then as well as any treasure and gold they gain, the leader takes a counter from the cup for every Event card of Monsters that was involved in the combat. If he finds the Skull counter, then the Warriors have found one of the legendary Death Dealer swords of Malach the Cruel. These are the only weapons capable of harming the Dread King. The leader then places all the counters back in the cup, ready for the next combat, when the Warriors can try to find another sword. There will only ever be four swords, and without one a Warrior will be able to inflict no damage on the Dread King whatsoever. With a Death Dealer sword, a Warrior may fight the Dread King as usual, inflicting damage as normal. If the Warriors manage to defeat the Dread King, at the end of the adventure they are richly rewarded, each Warrior gains two extra Treasure cards. Not only that, but they have the choice of plundering the Dread King's ancient tomb if they wish. Any Warrior who wishes to plunder the gold from the tomb may roll as many dice as he likes, adding up the totals rolled and multiplying the result by 100, to see how much gold he has found. If any dice he rolls come up as a 1, then as the Warrior packs the gold into his bag, he fails to notice the huge stone blocks sliding into place behind him. He has triggered the ancient defences, and will be sealed into the Twisted Spire forever, a rich, yet very dead Warrior. Otherwise, he may escape with the gold intact. Warriors are not allowed to use Luck or any other abilities to re-roll this result.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>

  <objectiveRoom name="IDOL CHAMBER">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de la Idol Chamber sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual. No se aplican objetivos especiales asociados al idol.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="Sacrifice?" generic="false">
      <flavor>One of the Warriors' kinsmen has been captured by Orcs, and even now he is being tortured in their lair. He is to be sacrificed to their foul gods unless the Warriors can rescue him.</flavor>
      <rules>Randomly determine the Warrior whose kinsman has been captured using the Warrior Counters. At the start of each Power Phase, before doing anything else, roll 3D6. If all the dice come up the same number the Warriors are too late and the prisoner has been sacrificed. With the exception of the Warrior whose kinsman has just been sacrificed, the Warriors may choose whether to carry on and avenge the prisoner's death, or to give up and return to the surface. The Warrior whose kinsman has been sacrificed has no choice and must go on. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the idol chamber contains. The Monsters are guarding the prisoner, who is bound in chains in front of a foul idol of Chaos. The Warrior who is his kinsman is so enraged by the sight that he goes insane with battle fury. For the rest of the game, that Warrior is at -1 Weapon Skill and +1 Attacks. Once the prisoner is freed, he shows the Warriors a secret way out of the dungeon that leads past a treasure chamber. From this room, each Warrior may take 2D6 x 50 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="Desecration" generic="false">
      <flavor>Deep in the ruined cities of the Dwarfs, now occupied by Orcs, Goblins and even worse creatures, many of the once noble temples and shrines have been defiled. In their place are crude altars dedicated to all manner of foul Gods. Apart from the obvious pleasure of killing the invaders of their ancestral homes, and hopefully recovering some of the long-lost treasures, the Dwarf Kings also pay a rich reward for every evil temple destroyed. The Warriors have been charged with locating one of these temples that is reputed to lie deep below the ground in the ruins of Karak Azgal. Kargun Skalfson, deposed Lord of Karak Azgal, has allowed the Warriors into the ruins to search for the temple, and has waived his right to a share of any treasure they discover on the way as long as they bring back evidence of the destruction of the temple. Secretly, Skalfson does not believe there is a temple, and therefore hopes to persuade the Warriors to venture into the most dangerous regions of Karak Azgal in search of it.</flavor>
      <rules>In actual fact, Skalfson is wrong and there is a temple in the ruins, dedicated to Khorne, the blood god. Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the idol chamber contains. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may destroy the temple by overturning the idol and thus desecrating it. They may then cut off its head as proof that they have successfully completed their mission. To overturn the idol, all the Warriors must be standing in squares adjacent to it. Roll 1D6 for each Warrior and add their Strengths. If the total is equal to 24 or over, the idol topples to the ground with a crash and the head rolls free. If the total is less than 24, the idol remains standing. The Warriors may attempt to destroy the idol once per turn, during the Warriors' Phase, as long as they do nothing else. For each turn that the idol remains standing, the Wizard deducts 2 from his Power roll in the Power Phase. If the modified result is 1 or less, an Unexpected Event occurs. The Unexpected Event must be resolved before the Warriors can try to smash the idol again. When the idol is smashed, a hideous scream echoes through the dungeon, causing all the monsters for miles around to flee in terror. This means that the Warriors can find their way back to the surface quite safely. At the end of the adventure, because there really was an idol, Skalfson is obliged to let them keep all the treasure they found.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="Kill the Shaman" generic="false">
      <flavor>A powerful Goblin Shaman is foretelling of a great Waaagh to come soon, when the Goblins and Orcs will sweep out of the Dark Lands and overthrow the Empire. Although not very powerful at the moment, his cult is growing stronger and unrest is beginning to stir. So as not to raise suspicions and warn him of their intentions, the Emperor has decreed that the best way to solve the crisis is to assassinate the Shaman. The Warriors have been chosen to venture into the Shaman's lair below Mount Gunbad, on the far side of the Worlds Edge Mountains, and kill him.</flavor>
      <rules>When the Warriors reach the idol chamber they will find that it contains 11 Goblins plus the Shaman. The Goblins are placed on the board according to the normal rules, while the Shaman starts in a square adjacent to the idol at the far end of the room. The Shaman will avoid combat if possible. He is not subject to the normal rules for pinning, and may move around freely, always trying to stay as far away from the Warriors as he can. Apart from that, his profile is exactly the same as the other Goblins. The Shaman's attack is to try and cast a Hand of Mork spell at the Warriors at the start of each Monsters' Phase. Roll 1D6. On a score of 4, 5 or 6 the spell succeeds. Use the Warrior Counters to determine who is hit. That Warrior takes 1D6 x 2 Wounds, modified for Toughness and armour. Once all the Monsters in the room, including the Shaman, are dead, the Warriors find a concealed entrance behind the idol leading out into the light of day. They may carry the Goblin Shaman's body back through this passage as evidence. If the mission is a success, each Warrior is rewarded with 1D6 x 50 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="Daemon Summoning" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Middle Mountains lie deep within the forests of the Empire, and are a wild and dangerous place. Although the Orcs, Goblins and other evil creatures that live in the mountain caves are a great hazard to travellers, in the past they have not been considered numerous or organised enough to threaten the security of the Empire itself. Now, however, a threat from one of their number has arisen, and must be eradicated quickly, or all manner of disasters will befall the Empire. A Skaven Warlord has discovered an ancient temple deep below the mountains, and within it a lifelike effigy of a mighty daemon that could summon the beast itself. The Skaven Warlord and his minions are doing their utmost to summon the daemon, believing they can bind it to do their will using braziers of burning warpstone. The Empire's Battle Wizards have scried something of this threat, and the Warriors have been dispatched with great haste to prevent the daemon being summoned. To stop the Skaven's evil work, the Wizard has been given a Scroll of Banishment by the head Wizards of the Empire. This ancient parchment must be guarded well, for it is the only thing that can stop the daemon being summoned.</flavor>
      <rules>The idol chamber is guarded by 12 Skaven. All but one of the Skaven are placed according to the normal rules. The final Skaven should be placed on the plinth, next to the brazier. This Skaven will stay on this spot unless attacked by a Warrior, as he is to act as the channel for the daemon's soul and must be near the idol to complete the summoning. The Warriors have 1D6 turns to kill all the Skaven, starting from the turn they enter the room. Once all the Skaven are dead, the Wizard may read aloud the Scroll of Banishment. As he does so, an anguished roar fills the air. The summoning is thwarted and the statue is destroyed in a great fire column that leaps up to the ceiling of the temple. If they do not thwart the summoning in time, in the Monsters' Phase of the final turn the daemon wakes and possesses the Skaven nearest to the statue. In the space of a few seconds the Skaven grows and changes, taking on the form of a mighty bull-headed man, a Minotaur. The Daemon Minotaur is similar to the Minotaur in the Rule Book, except it has 20 Wounds and 3 Attacks. It will attack the Warriors just as if it were a normal Monster. If the Warriors kill the Daemon Minotaur, it bursts into flames and creates a fire column that shoots up to the roof of the cavern. The mighty column of fire, whether created by the statue or the Minotaur exploding, creates a near vertical tunnel to the outside world. Although this takes some climbing, the Warriors eventually emerge into the daylight. Upon their return to the Empire, they are rewarded with 1D6 x 150 gold each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Return the Staff" generic="false">
      <flavor>As a final test of their courage and bravery before being accepted into the official Warriors' Guild of Bretonnia, the Warriors must fulfil a challenging task. They must descend into the labyrinthine tunnels of the Cursed Pit, which lies below Cripple Peak near the Dark Lands, and place a staff in the hand of an idol hidden deep underground. The staff has magical properties, and if left anywhere other than in the hand of the idol, it will eventually return to the throne room of Bretonnia.</flavor>
      <rules>Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the idol chamber contains. In addition, take the next Monster Event Card from the Event Deck and add those Monsters to those rolled. This is a particularly hazardous chamber. Once the Monsters are defeated, the Warriors may place the staff in the hand of the idol, completing their adventure. As they have killed all the Monsters in the vicinity already, they may now escape from the dungeon without danger. Upon their return to Bretonnia, the king rewards them with one item of treasure each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Sword of the Electors" generic="false">
      <flavor>One of the long-lost swords of the Elector Counts of the Empire, missing for centuries, has been found by a band of warriors in the Worlds Edge Mountains, near the Dwarf Hold of Mount Grimfang. Unfortunately, before they could return the blade to safety, all but one of the warriors were killed. The one warrior who survived, although tortured and badly mutilated, managed to escape and get back to the Emperor to tell his story. The Warriors have been requested to seek out this extremely important sword and return it. The sword is being kept in the idol chamber, clasped in the hand of the stone idol.</flavor>
      <rules>Roll on the Objective Room Monster Table to determine what Monsters the idol chamber contains. Once the Monsters have been defeated, the Warriors may try and retrieve the sword. Each Warrior may make one attempt to get the sword each turn. To do so, a Warrior must stand in one of the squares adjacent to the idol. Roll 1D6 and add the Warrior's Strength. If the total is 7 or more, he has succeeded and wrenches the sword free. If the total is less than 7, the idol suddenly animates and strikes the Warrior. The attack automatically hits and does 3D6 Wounds, modified for Toughness and armour. The idol then becomes immobile once more. The same Warrior cannot try again until all the Warriors have attempted the task. If the Warriors retrieve the sword, they are rewarded with 1D6 x 50 gold each.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>
  <objectiveRoom name="GORGUT'S LAIR">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de Gorgut's Lair sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual. No se aplican objetivos especiales ni reglas de salida adicionales si no eliges una aventura concreta.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="Stop the Waaagh!" generic="false">
      <flavor>In Kislev, a seer has foretold the coming of another great Ore horde, one to rival that of Azhag the Slaughterer. The prophecy states that in an Ore lair near Mount Gunbad an Ore Warboss has come to power. Unless he is stopped soon, he may gather the tribes and strike at Kislev, eventually laying waste to all the lands east of the Great Ocean. Although there is some doubt about the accuracy of the prophecy, a reward is being paid for every Ore Warboss head taken to Kislev, and great treasures are promised to those who bring the head the seer saw in her dreams. The Warriors have heard rumours of a fight between two Ore factions that has brought about a new Warboss called Gorgut. They have become convinced that he is the one in the prophecy and they immediately set out to find Gorgut and bring back his head!</flavor>
      <rules>Roll on the Gorgut's Lair Objective Room Monster Table to see what Monsters the Warriors meet when they get to the objective room. After killing all the Monsters in the Lair, one of the Warriors can cut off Gorgut's head so they can take the grisly trophy back to Kislev. At the back of the room the Warriors find a secret door and a passageway back to the surface. Place another doorway at the back of Gorgut's Lair and use a further four Dungeon cards to see what the Warriors meet on their way out of the lair. Take an Event card as normal if the Warriors enter a room or if the Wizard rolls a 1 in the Power Phase. Once out of the lair, the Warriors make their way back to Kislev. Eventually they arrive, and present their prize to the seer. Roll on the table below. On 1, the seer has already identified a head as being the one in her dreams, the rewards for Ore heads have been stopped, and the Warriors get nothing for their efforts. On 2-5, the seer says it is not the head from her dreams but the Warriors get 1D6 x 30 gold each for ridding the world of one more Ore Warboss. On 6, the seer says that Gorgut's head is the one in her dreams and the Warriors get 1D6 x 100 gold each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="Atonement" generic="false">
      <flavor>As the Warriors are returning from a dungeon adventure near Mount Gunbad they are forced to take shelter in a cave during a terrible storm. The cave walls are etched with strange, vaguely familiar symbols and there are signs that a fire has been lit here before. The next morning the storm subsides and the Warriors prepare to continue their journey. A noise of metal on stone alerts them that they have company, but nothing has prepared them for the look of anger on the faces of the Dwarfs now surrounding them. Apparently the cave is a sacred site and the Warriors have defiled it. The Dwarfs are very angry indeed, but there is a possible way for the Warriors to atone for this terrible sacrilege. The Dwarfs know that an Ore lair near Mount Gunbad is the resting place not only of a sacred amulet said to have belonged to Azhag the Slaughterer, but also the actual skull of the Warlord himself. To atone for defiling the Dwarfs' territory, the Warriors must enter the lair and bring back both the amulet and Azhag's skull.</flavor>
      <rules>To play this adventure, you will need to prepare the Dungeon deck slightly differently from normal. You will need 10 Dungeon cards, plus the Collapsed Passage, Shaman's Den and Gorgut's Lair cards from the Lair of the Ore Lord. Put the Gorgut's Lair Objective Room card and the Shaman's Den Dungeon Room card to one side, and shuffle the remaining 11 cards. Deal out six cards face-down, then shuffle in the Gorgut's Lair card. Shuffle the Shaman's Den in with the remaining cards, and put these six cards on top of the other seven cards. This completes the Dungeon deck for this adventure. The Warriors must get the amulet from the Shaman's Den and the skull from Gorgut's Lair. In the Shaman's Den, take an Event card for this room as normal, but also include Skabnoze in the room. Once Skabnoze has been sent packing and the other Monsters have been killed, the Warriors may pick up Azhag's amulet, which is on the keg on the platform in the Den. In Gorgut's Lair, roll on the Gorgut's Lair Objective Room Monster Table to see what Monsters the Warriors encounter. Once all the Monsters in the Lair are dead the Warriors may attempt to retrieve the skull, which is set in a niche in the wall above a pile of bones and skulls. The skull of Azhag has been magically protected by Skabnoze. Any turn that there are no Monsters in the Lair, draw a Warrior counter to see who tries to take the skull. This Warrior must roll a D6 + his Initiative and score 7+; remember that a 1 always fails. If the Warrior fails, a sheet of flame shoots out from the eyes of the skull causing 2D6 Wounds on the Warrior. Each turn continues as normal until a Warrior successfully picks up the skull. Once the Warriors get the skull the warding spell is broken and in the niche they will also find a lever for opening a secret passage to the surface. The Warriors can then take the skull back to Karaz-a-Karak where the Dwarfs will judge that they have atoned for their wrong doing and reward them with a Treasure card each, taken from the original Warhammer Quest cards.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="The Magnificent Four" generic="false">
      <flavor>Just for once the Warriors find that their arrival in a village is a cause for celebration rather than disapproval. They are treated to a feast and entertained in high fashion. Realising that something must be up, the Warriors wait for the villagers to make their request. Eventually, towards the end of the evening, the village leaders tell the Warriors that for years they have been harassed by a tribe of Ores, called the Black Fangs, who live in the mountains nearby. The killing and destruction has been bad enough, but during the last raid the Ores found and stole a gold statue that the village treasured. Rumour now has it that the Ores have recently been attacked by Dwarfs and will not be expecting a small raiding party. The villagers believe that it should now be possible for the Warriors to attack the Ore lair and not only get their statue back but put paid to the nasty Ores forever. The leader, holding his hat in his hands, tells the Warriors that they have managed to gather together some gold and pleads for the Warriors to help them.</flavor>
      <rules>To set the Dungeon deck for this adventure, follow the procedure on page 5 of this rulebook. The Warriors will not know where the Shaman's Den or Gorgut's Lair are. When the Warriors leave the first board section the portcullis drops in the doorway. The Warriors cannot get out of the Ores' lair without the key. The key can be found in the Shaman's Den. If the Warriors find Gorgut's Lair before they find the Shaman's Den, place a door at the back of the Lair. The Warriors must continue with the remaining board sections once they have finished in Gorgut's Lair. Use the Gorgut's Lair Objective Room Monster Table to see what Monsters are in the Lair. Once all the Monsters in the Lair have been killed the Warriors can search for the statue, which they will find in the open chest at the back of the Lair. However, just as they lay their hands on the statue, Bogoff the Snotling appears and runs off with it. Place Bogoff at the far end of the board section immediately before Gorgut's Lair. He will run between Gorgut's Lair and the last board section. As with the lantern, the Warriors must hit Bogoff to make him drop the statue. Note which Warrior hits Bogoff. In the Shaman's Den, draw an Event card as normal. Once all the Monsters are dead the key for the portcullis will be found under one of the stools. On the Warriors' return to the village, the villagers will pay them 1D6 x 50 gold each plus an extra 100 gold to the Warrior who got the statue back from Bogoff.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="Impossible!" generic="false">
      <flavor>The king of Bretonnia claims that his knights have finally rid the Grey Mountains of Ores and Goblins once and for all. His people may now pass safely through the mountains without fear. A banquet is held to celebrate this great day, marred only by the arrival of a deputation from the surrounding villages saying that there seem to be more Ores than ever! The king of course has the villagers whipped soundly and sent away, but just in case there is some truth in the preposterous story he sends the Warriors off to scout around and find out what's going on. In fact, the truth is that a new Warboss called Gorgut had decided to move his tribe, the Black Fangs, from their home near Mount Gunbad. One night he took all his followers and some friendly Night Goblins and went in search of a new lair. After many months of travelling, always by night, they found their new home. Unfortunately Skabnoze, the Shaman who guided them, had a very poor sense of direction. Instead of finding a nice quiet cave complex to the south, say near the Broken Teeth, he headed west, then north and ended up in the Grey Mountains! The Warriors are walking into very dangerous territory, but they have to follow the orders of the king!</flavor>
      <rules>Roll on the Gorgut's Lair Objective Room Monster Table. By the time the Warriors reach Gorgut's Lair they will have realised that there are both Goblins and Ores here. After killing all the Monsters in the lair they will have plenty of proof to take back to the king for their reward, but they cannot leave the lair unless they have found the key to the portcullis. To claim their reward they journey to Couronne to see the king once more. Upon presenting their evidence, the king makes his judgement. Roll a dice and consult the table below. On 1, the proof is ignored and the Warriors are ridiculed as mendacious simpletons, paid nothing, and sent packing. On 2-3, the king and his court refuse to believe that there could be any more Ores and Goblins this far west; however, the Warriors told a jolly tale, and are paid 1D6 x 30 gold each just to go away. On 4-5, the king's advisors see the truth in the Warriors' words and evidence, and the Warriors are paid 1D6 + 6 x 50 gold each as a reward for their heroic quest; knights are once more dispatched to wipe the Ores from the Grey Mountains. On 6, the king deems the Warriors conquering heroes for finding the Monsters and defeating them. They are made honorary knights of the realm, with the right to wear the king's colours. They are also each given an item of treasure from the king's treasure chamber, and each Warrior gets a Treasure card taken from the original Warhammer Quest Treasure deck.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="A Hound for a Hound" generic="false">
      <flavor>During an Ore raid the favourite hunting hound of Duke Harald of Talabheim was killed when his hunting party was ambushed. Now Harald has become consumed with the idea of revenge and has offered the Warriors a rich reward to enter the lair of the Ore Warboss responsible and kill his favourite Squig Hound; it's only fair, after all. Normally, the Warriors would refuse such a foolhardy and pointless quest, but Harald is an extremely wealthy and powerful duke, and they were supposed to be in charge of the hound when it was killed...</flavor>
      <rules>This adventure is played through like any other, with the following special rules. Each Warrior takes one of the Luck tokens from the Warhammer Quest game, to represent his magic amulet. At any time in the adventure, a Warrior may declare that he is using his amulet. This allows him to re-roll a dice roll which has just failed. Once he has re-rolled, he discards the Luck token, the amulet's power is exhausted, and the Warrior must abide by the second dice roll. When the Warriors reach Gorgut's Lair, use the Gorgut's Lair Objective Monster Table to roll for Monsters as normal but also add Growler the Squig Hound and place him on the platform level. When all the Monsters are reduced to 0 Wounds the Warriors can remove a tooth from the Squig Hound as proof that they killed it and return to Talabheim through a secret passage. Roll on the table below. On 1, the Warriors lose the tooth on the way back and get no reward as the duke does not believe their story. Instead, he kicks them off his lands, never to return. On 2-3, they return with the tooth but the fickle duke has forgotten about the arrangement and gives them each 1D6 x 20 gold to go away. On 4-5, the duke seems happy with the result and pays them each 1D6 x 50 gold as a reward. On 6, the duke declares that he can now sleep happy in the knowledge that he has had his revenge, thanks the Warriors and gratefully pays each of them 1D6 x 100 gold.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Stolen Goods" generic="false">
      <flavor>While relaxing in a small tavern between adventures the Warriors are approached by an anonymous Alchemist from Altdorf. The Alchemist wishes to hire the Warriors for a simple job. Rumour has reached him that an evil sorcerer known as Gradluk the Deceiver was recently killed in a wizards' duel in Middenheim. A few years ago Gradluk stole something from the Alchemist and now he wants the Warriors to get it back. Apparently Gradluk had a secret hideaway near Peak Pass, which is where the Alchemist's property is probably hidden. The hideaway will only be lightly guarded and the Warriors should have no trouble in retrieving his property, which will be in a green drawstring bag marked with a skull and crossbones. The mysterious Alchemist tells them the bag contains valuable items that he wants back. However, he says that there are also four healing potions in there, which the Warriors are welcome to if they find the bag. He also gives each Warrior a magical amulet, said to bring luck. The bag is magically trapped to kill anyone who touches it, but the Alchemist provides the Warriors with a counter spell. Only a Wizard can cast the spell. What the Alchemist doesn't know is that soon after the death of Gradluk, a tribe of Ores called the Black Fangs moved into the caves. Retrieving the bag will be by no means easy!</flavor>
      <rules>This adventure is played through like any other, with the following special rules. Each Warrior takes one of the Luck tokens from the Warhammer Quest game, to represent his magic amulet. At any time in the adventure, a Warrior may declare that he is using his amulet. This allows him to re-roll a dice roll which has just failed. Once he has re-rolled, he discards the Luck token, the amulet's power is exhausted, and the Warrior must abide by the second dice roll. In Gorgut's Lair, roll on the Gorgut's Lair Objective Room Monster Table to see what Monsters are in Gorgut's Lair. The Warriors will notice the green bag at the back of the room and will also see a pile of bones and skulls in the corner. Whenever someone upset Gorgut he would make them try and pick up the bag; the skulls are a mute testimony to the power of the protective spell. When all the Monsters have been killed the Wizard can retrieve the bag from the back of the Lair. The Wizard must remember to cast the counter spell before picking up the bag, and he must be standing in the same square as the bag. Roll a D6 and on anything but a score of 1, the Wizard picks up the bag safely; the spell worked. However, if the roll was a 1, black fire consumes him and the flesh is flayed off his bones. His charred skeleton collapses onto the floor. No matter whether the Warriors get the bag or not, the only way out of the lair is back the way they came and there are still likely to be some Monsters around. The Warriors must move back through the rooms and corridors, but there is not an automatic event if they enter a room. If the Wizard rolls a 1 in the Power Phase he must roll again. If the second dice comes up with anything but a 1, take an Event card as normal. However, if the second roll comes up a 1 the Warriors are attacked by Skabnoze and minions. Skabnoze is after the bag now that it is free of its spell and may try to steal it back more than once depending on the Wizard's dice rolls. Once the Warriors get out of the Ores' lair they may go back to see the mysterious Alchemist if they have retrieved the bag. When the Warriors meet up with the Alchemist he checks the bag. Roll a D6: on a roll of 1 Gorgut has thrown out whatever was in the bag and used it to carry his lunch. The bag now contains some well chewed bones and a few lumps of gristle he was saving for a snack. The Alchemist throws the bag down in disgust and refuses to pay the Warriors. On any other roll he is more than happy with the return of his property and gives the Warriors 2D6 x 100 gold each. Note: each healing potion cures 2D6 Wounds.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>
  <objectiveRoom name="TEMPLE OF KHAINE">
    <adventure id="generic" name="Generica" generic="true">
      <flavor>Usa la ambientacion normal de la Temple of Khaine sin una aventura concreta del Adventure Book.</flavor>
      <rules>Resuelve la sala objetivo con el comportamiento habitual. Si usas esta sala sin una aventura concreta, aplica sus reglas especiales normales y la tabla de monstruos correspondiente.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="1" name="The Golden Pillars" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Warriors encounter Stephano Whitewolf, the leader of a newly organised mercenary company in Couronne known as the Golden Pillars, which consists of a motley group of adventurers. The Golden Pillars are virtuous and upright, trying to subtly direct immoral lords and foil the plans of the wicked. To gain admission into the company and prove their worth, it has been decided that the Warriors must eradicate the growing presence of a Cult of Slaanesh. The faction has recently taken up residence in the sea caves north of Couronne and Stephano wants to remove them before they become a nuisance. The Warriors are given a Golden Pillar, a banner emblazoned with the group's gold emblem, and are told to place it inside the cult's temple in order to complete their membership. Each Warrior should roll 1D6, the one with the highest score being selected to carry the banner. Monsters are at -1 To Hit the Warrior who carries the banner due to its fearsome markings and bold colors. If a Warrior carrying the banner dies, the other Warriors may roll off again to see who gets to pick it up. The whole initiation is merely a formality. Stephano expects the Warriors to simply enter the caverns, run off a few cult members, plant the flag, and return to a hero's welcome. As Stephano figures it, the more members that exist, the more influence his mercenary company will possess, so he always assigns a fairly simple task to newcomers. Unbeknownst to the Warriors and Stephano, the caves have already been cleansed of these cult members by the Hag Queen Melusina and her Dark Elf clan. Her Black Ark raids have been instrumental in maintaining a supply of fresh blood for her magical cauldron, which in turn bestows upon her eternal beauty. Presently, the Black Ark has returned to Naggaroth with slaves and sacrifices, but Melusina and a Dark Elf raiding party remain to terrorise the coast.</flavor>
      <rules>For this Adventure, shuffle the Circle of Power card into the top half of the Dungeon Deck. This Adventure uses the special Hall of the Hag Queen counters. There are books of interest located in the Bottomless Pit, the Water Cave, and the Circle of Power. Each book tells a bit of history, legend, and lore about the Dark Elves, Black Arks, the Cauldron of Blood, and the Hag Queens. For each Book that turns out to be important, you may add +1 to the dice roll when rolling on the Objective Room Monster Table. If there are no Monsters on one of those Board Sections and the party leader is standing on a square that contains a Book, they may pick it up to see if it contains anything important. Take the corresponding Book Counter and the three Skull Counters and put all four of them into a cup. Mix them up and have the party leader pick one from the cup without looking. If it is the Book Counter, put it on the Adventure Record Sheet. If the Warriors draw a Skull Counter instead, the book is unimportant and also trapped, so they must immediately draw an Event Card. Repeat this process for each relevant Board Section. Once the Objective Room is clear of Monsters, a secret passage opens on the wall opposite the entrance. The Warriors plant the Golden Pillar and can leave the room by this exit, which leads up to the surface. Stephano Whitewolf welcomes them into the organisation with an honorary gift from the company vaults, one item of Dungeon Room Treasure to distribute as normal. Bretonnia is also glad to have the Dark Elf presence removed and the King rewards the Warriors with 1D6 x 100 gold each.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="2" name="Protest" generic="false">
      <flavor>The town of St. Leu is refusing to pay taxes because they do not feel their monies are at work protecting them after the third Dark Elf raid in a month, the last of which occurred just before the Warriors arrived. The townsfolk are furious and have begun to steer travellers and merchants away from the area in protest. In a desperate effort to quell the fears of the citizens, the Burgermeister hires the Warriors as mercenaries to pursue the Dark Elf raiders. The Warriors track the Dark Elves to a cavern system on the coast which they bravely enter.</flavor>
      <rules>Take the Torture Chamber Dungeon Room card and shuffle it into the top half of the Dungeon Deck. Shuffle the Temple of Khaine card into the bottom half of the Dungeon Deck for a total of 14 cards. Remove the Execution Event Card from the deck for this Adventure. Instead of drawing an Event Card when the Warriors enter the Torture Chamber, they encounter Executioner Husk Bawn. In addition, draw Event Cards until one reveals Monsters, reshuffling any E Events back into the deck, to see who accompanies him. If the Warriors clear the Board of Monsters there, each Warrior receives one item of Dungeon Room Treasure instead of a single item for the group. If the Warriors find the Temple of Khaine Objective Room and defeat all the Monsters, they discover a false panel in the wall that leads out of the Dungeon and back to the surface. They can return to St. Leu where they are paid 1D6 x 100 gold each by the Burgermeister. In addition, the townsfolk are so relieved that the Dark Elf raids have been stopped that some of the houses donate a family heirloom, an item of Dungeon Room Treasure, to each Warrior.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="3" name="Hexed" generic="false">
      <flavor>Strolling about the streets of Hargendorf in-between adventures, the Warriors inadvertently insult an old wretch begging in the streets. She gives them an evil stare and curses them in a foreign tongue before shuffling off. Not soon afterward bad luck follows the Warriors like an animal stalking its prey. The Warriors have no choice but to seek out the old woman, whom they find in a craggy cave overlooking the sea. As if expecting them, she welcomes them into her hovel, declaring that she will remove the hex if the Warriors bring her the blood of a Dark Elf Hag Queen. Following a pointing finger out toward the ocean, the Warriors can see the vague outline of a dark fortress floating on the water. The Hag Queen awaits deep within the cavernous holds of the foreboding vessel.</flavor>
      <rules>Until the hex is removed, any Warrior who rerolls any dice that successfully alters consequences in their favour must make a Hex Roll immediately afterward by rolling 1D6. This includes Luck Points, Faith Points, the Wizard's Staff, and rerolling dice due to Magic Items, Magic Weapons, Skills, and similar effects. If the result of the Hex Roll is a 1 or 2, the old woman's curse negates the roll as if it never happened. This Hex Roll cannot be rerolled by any means. When the Warriors enter the Objective Room, the Hag Queen Melusina and the old wretch that hexed them in Hargendorf are revealed to be one and the same. Because she was expecting the Warriors, subtract 1 when the Warriors roll on the Dark Elves Objective Room Monster Table. If the Warriors manage to clear the Objective Room, a secret recess opens on the cavern wall opposite the entrance. The small chamber contains captured treasure from various Dark Elf raids as well as a passage to the surface. As the Warriors pass through the doorway, they may each take one random item of Objective Room Treasure before making their way back to shore.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="4" name="Bloody Retribution" generic="false">
      <flavor>It had been days since the Warriors had slept and the weary party spent the night in a grove just a few miles from Bordeleaux. They awoke in chains, being whipped and beaten, and forced to march through a dank underground tunnel by their Dark Elf captors. An encounter with trolls allowed them to break their bonds and escape. They have now made tracks back to Bordeleaux where they plan bloody retribution.</flavor>
      <rules>Take the Dungeon Cell Dungeon Room card and shuffle it in with five other cards to make the top half of the Dungeon Deck. Shuffle the Water Cave Dungeon Room and the Temple of Khaine Objective Room in with five other cards to make the bottom half of the Dungeon Deck. The Warriors begin the Adventure stripped of all of their Weapons, Armour, gold and other items, although they have each managed to locate one hand-to-hand weapon of their choice. They may choose a sword, axe, spear, mace, warhammer, flail or halberd to begin this Adventure. If the Warriors defeat the first Monsters they encounter, they find their lost Weapons. If the Warriors find the Dungeon Cell and clear the Board of Monsters, they find their lost Armour. If the Warriors find the Water Cave and clear the Board of Monsters, they find their lost Gold. If the Warriors find the Temple of Khaine Objective Room and defeat all the Monsters inside, they will find the rest of their missing items. If the Warriors discover the Temple of Khaine before the Water Cave, place the second Doorway on the Temple of Khaine so that the Warriors can continue their search for their gold. Place the three Skull Counters and one of the Book Counters into a cup. Each Warrior receives +1 Attack per turn while their wrath endures. Each time they reveal a new Board Section in the Exploration Phase, each Warrior, starting with the Party Leader, must draw a counter from the cup and return it before the next Warrior draws. If a Warrior draws a Skull Counter, their wrath remains at its peak and they continue to receive +1 Attack per turn. If a Warrior draws a Book Counter instead, their wrath has waned and they no longer receive the bonus. The last Board Section in the Dungeon Deck leads out of the Dungeon and up to the surface. The Warriors have completed their quest and can bask in the satisfaction of revenge.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="5" name="Rescue Revolt" generic="false">
      <flavor>The Bretonnian King's nephew was among the latest victims taken away in a Black Ark raid on the coast of Brionne. The King has demanded that the Warriors rescue his nephew. Although there is no conceivable way to penetrate the magical barrier that surrounds the Black Ark as it sails back to Naggaroth, the King's advisors have devised a desperate scheme: after the royal Enchantress renders the Warriors' weapons invisible by way of a magic spell, the Warriors will allow themselves to be captured by a Dark Elf raiding party. Once inside and after the invisibility spell wears off, they are expected to locate the royal nephew and lead him safely back to Bretonnia. The Warriors see that their best chance of surviving the whole ordeal is to ignite a slave revolt.</flavor>
      <rules>Prepare the Dungeon Deck as normal with one exception: shuffle the Fighting Pit Objective Room into the top seven cards and the Temple of Khaine Objective Room into the bottom four cards to form a total of 13 cards for the Dungeon Deck. Put the Demona Ryme Beastmaster Event Card aside for now. The first Board Section is the Warriors' dungeon cell where the invisibility spell wears off. Draw an Event Card until it reveals Monsters, reshuffling any E Event Cards back into the deck. The Warriors receive the equivalent of an Ambush attack on their astonished captors, taking an extra Warriors' Phase in the first round of combat. If the Warriors defeat their captors they receive one item of Dungeon Room Treasure as normal, and there is only one exit in this room. When the Warriors enter the Fighting Pit Objective Room they are attacked by Beastmaster Ryme, Julong the Wardog, 1 Ogre slave, 1D6 + 3 Hobgoblins slaves, and 1D6 Dark Elves with Crossbows of Strength 4. If Demona Ryme is killed before the Ogre, then the Ogre receives the Break ability. If the Warriors clear the Fighting Pit of Monsters, they can attempt to break down the huge wooden door, Toughness 3 and Wounds 7, and free the captives inside who rush out in droves. The royal nephew is not among them and has been taken to the Temple of Khaine where he will be sacrificed. When the Warriors discover the Temple of Khaine Objective Room in the Exploration Phase, roll 2D6. This is how many turns they have to kill the Hag Queen before she finishes her ritual by plunging a wicked-looking dagger into the royal nephew. Once the Warriors clear the Objective Room, they find a passage out of the Black Ark that leads to the outside world. They leap into the ocean where they are soon rescued by a passing ship. If they have saved the royal nephew, return to the King of Bretonnia and roll 1D6. On 1 to 4, the King is shocked that the Warriors actually completed the mission since it was he who had arranged for the nephew's disappearance in the first place; he grudgingly rewards the Warriors with 1D6 x 100 gold each. On 5 or 6, the King is elated and rewards each Warrior with 1D6 x 100 gold and one item of Objective Room Treasure. If they fail to save the nephew, the Warriors decide a long sabbatical is in order, away from vicious monsters, dangerous dungeons, and irrational rulers with guillotines.</rules>
    </adventure>
    <adventure id="6" name="Three Ancient Tomes" generic="false">
      <flavor>It is known that the dark caves dotted along the Old World are numerous and, sometimes, enormous. It is also known that their uncharted underground waterways extend from the coast of Estalia to the coast of Kislev, emerging at hundreds of points along the way. The coastal caverns were used decades ago by pirates, smugglers, and traders to evade and circumvent the authorities. When the ocean levels rose, the caverns became all but useless. But the water levels have receded once again and adventurers know that the caves may be ripe with bandit gold and pirate treasure. The Warriors have set their sights on the Old Coast Road near Marienburg, but have come before the High Elves of Marienburg to ask permission, for the High Elves believe that they are the rightful occupants of Marienburg and the surrounding area. They insist that it is written in the Three Ancient Tomes, ancient historical texts that detail the history of their ancestors, the Sea Elves, during the time when they reigned supreme. Unfortunately for them, the texts have been missing for generations. The High Elves, impressed with the Warriors' respect and courtesy, have granted them permission to search for gold and treasure within their ancestral home, but with a single condition: the books would be very valuable to the High Elves, as they would reveal some of the missing history of their kin and may prove the High Elves' claim to the area.</flavor>
      <rules>There are Ancient Tomes located in the Bottomless Pit, Water Cave and Temple of Khaine Board Sections. When there are no Monsters on one of those Board Sections, the Warriors may read a tome to see if it is one they seek. The first time the Warriors find a Tome, put the corresponding Tome Counter into a cup with three Skull Counters and, without looking, have the leader draw one out. If the Tome Counter drawn matches the one on the Board, then it is one of the Three Ancient Tomes the Elves seek. The second time the Warriors find a Tome, put the corresponding Tome Counter into a cup with only two Skull Counters and draw again. When the Warriors come across the third Tome, put that Tome Counter in a cup with only one Skull Counter and draw again. When the Warriors reach the Temple of Khaine Objective Room, roll on the Dark Elves Objective Room Monster Table to see who attacks them. The last card in the Dungeon Deck contains the exit out of the Dungeon. Use the second Doorway in the Temple of Khaine Objective Room to continue through the rest of the Dungeon Deck if appropriate. The Warriors can then return to Marienburg where they deliver any treasure of Elven origin they found. As promised, the High Elves pay twice the gold value of each such treasure. In addition, for every Tome they bring back that discusses Sea Elf history, the Warriors receive one item of Objective Room Treasure, rerolling any treasure of Elven origin, to distribute as normal.</rules>
    </adventure>
  </objectiveRoom>
</objectiveRoomAdventures>
