<?xml version="1.0"?>

<events xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	      xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='whq-events-schema.xsd'>
        
  <event id="rpb-thrown-out" name="Thrown Out">
    <rules>Your Warrior's wild behaviour attracts the attention of the Settlement
authorities and he is thrown out of town. He must wait outside the Settlement
gates for the other Warriors. While outside, he spends his Living Expenses as
normal.

In addition, roll 1D6. On a score of 1 your Warrior is fleeced by the state guards as he is thrown out and has all his gold stolen.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-12-pickpocket" name="Pickpocket">
    <rules>As your Warrior rushes through the busy streets, his money pouch is stolen.
Your Warrior loses 1D6 x 20 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-13-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-14-good-deed" name="Good Deed">
    <rules>Leaving most of his gold carefully stashed away in his hotel, your Warrior
goes out on the town, taking 1D6 x 20 gold with him. As he crosses the street,
he spots an old crone in an upstairs window shouting that robbers have broken
into her attic room and are stealing her few possessions. Happy to assist the
helpless, he bounds up the rickety stairs to her room three at a time. As he
enters her dimly lit room, a black bag is placed over his head, swiftly
followed by a heavy iron bar. He awakens in the gutter several hours later,
nursing a sore head. Not surprisingly, the gold he was carrying has all gone.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-15-investment" name="Investment">
    <rules>In one of the wharf side bars, your Warrior meets a young entrepreneur with
great ideas for establishing a trading empire to cover the known world. He
talks your warrior into investing 1D6 x 50 gold, giving him a certificate of
partnership.

From now on, at the end of each dungeon, whenever your Warrior reaches
civilisation, he may visit the local Merchants' Guild and show them his deed
of partnership. Consulting their records, they can tell him how the company is
doing. Roll 1D6 on the following table:

1       The company has gone bust, and your Warrior's
investment is worth nothing. In addition, he must pay
the merchants 1D6 x 50 gold in outstanding debts.

2-5     Your Warrior's investment is performing fairly well,
and the merchant forwards him 1D6 x 10 gold as his
share of the profits

6       Business is booming! After consulting the ledger, the
merchant confirms that he can forward your Warrior
1D6 x 50 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-16-steam-bath" name="Steam Bath">
    <rules>Your Warrior spends the rest of his day in the heady atmosphere of a steam
bath, sweating off the after effects of last night's sojourn at the tavern. He
emerges feeling far healthier than he has for a good while, with +1
permanently added to his Starting Wounds score.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-21-fight" name="Fight">
    <rules>Your Warrior argues with a burly street trader who has tried to charge him far
too much for some cheap, shoddy items. The argument escalates to a brawl
very quickly. Roll 1D6 on the following table:

1       Your Warrior is soundly thrashed and loses 200 gold.

2       Your Warrior is bested after a hard struggle against the
trader and his cronies and loses 100 gold.

3       Your Warrior walks away with a bloody nose and 50 gold
worse off, but leaves the trader badly bruised.

4       After a fierce struggle, your Warrior knocks the impudent
trader to the ground, where he stays to collect his teeth.
While he is busy, your Warrior takes 100 gold from his
stall as compensation.

5       Your Warrior quickly disarms the trader. With a sword at
his throat, the lout has no choice but to apologise and offer
your Warrior 200 gold as compensation.

6       A dozen evil-looking thugs - the trader's bodyguards leap
out from the shadows, attacking your Warrior with knives,
coshes and cudgels. Unperturbed, he coolly dispatches
them with a few well placed sword strokes, empties their
purses, and ends up 300 gold better off.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-22-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-23-fooled" name="Fooled">
    <rules>Your Warrior must discard any one purchase he has made in this Settlement,
as it was a fake and is worth nothing!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-24-circus" name="Circus">
    <rules>There is a travelling circus in town, and your Warrior spends the rest of his
day wandering from sideshow to sideshow. Having met the bearded woman
and the two-headed goat, he decides to have his fortune read.

Perhaps the sign above the door to that particular wagon should say 'Have
your fortune stolen', as for a cost of 2D6 x 10 gold, your Warrior is told
nothing more than that his destiny lies with a tall, dark stranger from
Erengrad!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-25-reward" name="Reward">
    <rules>Your Warrior sees a poster warning that a well known murderer is reputed to
be in the area, and offers a reward for his capture. The criminal in question is
described as very tall, wearing a black cloak and hat, and having an Erengrad
accent. Upon reading this, your Warrior realises that the description exactly
fits a character he bumped into earlier, and rushing back, manages to
apprehend the villain just as he drags a gagged merchant into a dark alley.
Roll 1D6 on the following table:

1       The murderer laughs, slits the merchant's
throat, throws the knife at your Warrior's feet
and flees, shouting "Help, murder!".

Soon your Warrior is surrounded by an
angry mob, and only his best efforts (and
1D6 x 50) gold coins persuade them that he
is innocent.

2-5     Your Warrior saves the merchant's life, for
which he gives you 20 gold, but the
murderer slips away into the gloom.

6       Your Warrior frees the merchant and
captures the murderer, for which he is
proclaimed a hero and given 100 gold
reward.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-26-betrothed" name="Betrothed">
    <rules>Due to a mistake in identity, your Warrior finds himself surrounded by a gang
of angry young men who insist that he is betrothed to marry their sister. Your
Warrior agrees, albeit at knife point, and pledges his troth to a farmer's
daughter of ample charms.

The marriage is arranged for tomorrow, so your Warrior must either leave the
Settlement immediately, or get married...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-31-drugged" name="Drugged">
    <rules>Visiting a local hostelry in a rather seedy area, your Warrior partakes of a
curious drink offered him by the bartender. After one swig, he feels the effects
of the liquid take hold he has been drugged! Roll 1D6 on the following table:

1-3     Your Warrior has been poisoned and is at -1
Toughness for the duration of the next
adventure.

4-6     The liquid in question is simply very strong
ale, and your Warrior quickly gets a taste for
it. The only ill effect is a pounding head next
morning.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-32-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-33-an-honest-days-work" name="An Honest Day's Work">
    <rules>Your Warrior is employed by a local merchant to carry bales of cotton to the
riverside area for the day. This task earns him 20 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-34-riotous-living" name="Riotous Living">
    <rules>Taken with the joys of hot food and a comfortable bed after so long out in the
wild, your Warrior overspends on such luxuries by 50 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-35-duel" name="Duel">
    <rules>Your Warrior is challenged to a duel by a professional duellist whom he
insulted in a tavern. The duel is scheduled to take place at dawn tomorrow.
Your Warrior can either leave town immediately or take up the challenge.

If your Warrior takes part in the duel, roll 1D6 on the following table:

1       With a single, well-placed sword thrust your
Warrior's heart is speared and he falls to the
ground, quite dead.

2-4     The two duellists fight for hour after hour,
each inflicting many light wounds on the
other. Eventually the sun goes down and the
fight is declared a draw. The duellist
congratulates your Warrior on his
swordsmanship, and offers him a fine supper
and the best wine at the most expensive hotel
in the Settlement

5-6     After a few minutes, your Warrior realises
that he has the better of the duellist and
despatches him. On his body he finds jewels
worth 2D6 x 50 gold and a single item of
treasure (take a Treasure card).</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-36-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-41-gambling" name="Gambling">
    <rules>Your Warrior visits a local inn and gets involved in a dubious game of dice.
Roll 1D6 on the following table:

1       Your Warrior loses badly, and must forfeit
one piece of treasure of your choice

2       Your Warrior loses 1D6 x 20 gold.

3-4     Your Warrior comes out of the game evens

5       Your Warrior wins 1D6 x 10 gold.

6       Your Warrior wins 3D6 x 10 gold</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-42-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-43-join-the-watch" name="Join The Watch">
    <rules>The Captain of the Watch marks your Warrior as a useful looking recruit and,
as he is short on manpower, press gangs him for a week. Your Warrior can
either try to escape the Watch by making a donation to their funds of 2D6 x
10 gold, or join up.

If your Warrior joins up he does not have to pay Living Expenses for the
week and earns 20 gold in wages. However, while in the Watch he has no
time to visit any traders or Special Locations.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-44-illness" name="Illness">
    <rules>A terrible illness strikes the Settlement, and your Warrior falls prey to it. He
must spend the next two days in bed, paying 10 gold per day for medication
as well as the normal Living Expenses. While your Warrior is in bed, you do
not have to roll on this table for him.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-45-pet-dog" name="Pet Dog">
    <rules>Your Warrior is adopted by a small dog. It follows him around everywhere,
skulking in the shadows while the fighting goes on and then emerging after
the adventure is completed to shower his new master with adoration.
Unfortunately, his appetite is beyond all expectations for his size, and he
doubles your Warrior's Living Expenses. Your Warrior can kill it if you want,
but it would be a cruel and heartless thing to do and it will cost him 1,000
gold to pay for a decent burial for the hound!

If your Warrior already has a pet dog, roll on this table again. If not, name
him and note him down on your Warrior's Adventure Record sheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-46-runaway" name="Runaway">
    <rules>While walking along the main street, your Warrior hears a disturbance just
around the corner. A moment later a huge runaway bull charges down the
street, wrecking market stalls and causing panic. Your Warrior can let it pass
by hiding down a side alley, or try to stop the enraged animal.

If your Warrior hides down the alley and lets the bull pass, roll

1D6 on the following table:
1-3    Your Warrior skulks in the shadows, waiting for the
action to die down. As he peeps round the corner, a
mugger's metal bar hits him over the head. When he
regains consciousness, his purse is 100 gold coins
lighter.

4-6     After waiting nervously in the dark for a few
minutes, your Warrior sees the bull roar past and
career off down a side street. The danger is passed
and your Warrior may carry on about his business.

If your Warrior tries to stop the bull, roll 1D6 on the following table:
1-2     Your Warrior waves the passers-by aside and leaps
out in front of the bull, sword drawn. The bull
hesitates for half a second or so, and then tramples
him into the dirt before carrying on its way. The
crowd then stomp all over him in the rush to follow
the bull, leaving him to nurse his injuries alone in
an empty street.

3-4     A single sword thrust stops the bull dead in its
tracks literally. As its carcass twitches
spasmodically, the crowd roar in approval and
shower your Warrior with 100 gold. Then the bull's
enraged owner arrives, and relieves him of 150 gold
- it was his prize stud, and he wanted it stopped, not
slaughtered!

5-6     Your Warrior gives the bull a hard stare and it skids
to a halt, snorting and pawing the ground. Putting a
rope around its neck, he leads it back to its stall.
The crowd cheer and shower him with 150 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-51-crime" name="Crime">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accused of murder and thrown in jail. The matter is sorted out
eventually, but only after your Warrior's companions have bailed him out.
Each Warrior in the party except the accused must pay 1D6 x 5 gold to the
authorities.

If his companions do not have the money, your Warrior must spend 1D6 days
in jail. While in jail he doesn't have to pay Living Expenses or roll on this
table.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-52-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-53-counterfeit" name="Counterfeit">
    <rules>As your Warrior attempts to buy some equipment, the trader points out his
gold is counterfeit and refuses to take it. Looking through his stash, your
Warrior discovers that 1D6 x 10 of his gold is indeed worthless. Discard it
and cross it off his Adventure Record sheet.

If your Warrior does not have that much gold left, and has already spent some
in the Settlement, he must leave for the next dungeon immediately before
anyone catches on.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-54-beggars" name="Beggars">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accosted by beggars and, overwhelmed by the sadness of
their plight, gives each of the 2D6+2 pitiful wretches 5 gold. If your Warrior
cannot pay he is a beggar himself, and you must roll 1D6 on the following
table:

1       Your Warrior is thrown out of the Settlement - see
Settlement Event 11.

2-6     Your Warrior gains 1D6 x 10 gold by begging.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-55-debt" name="Debt">
    <rules>A debt collector catches up with your Warrior, demanding payment for
money borrowed years ago. The sum your Warrior borrowed was not
substantial, but the interest rates are astronomical. The outstanding balance is
1D6 x 20 gold, and if your Warrior cannot pay in full immediately the debt
collector takes all his gold plus one piece of equipment or treasure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-56-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-61-temple-donation" name="Temple Donation">
    <rules>Much taken with the teachings of the local priest, your Warrior pledges 1D6 x
50 gold to his cause, selling equipment if necessary to meet the cost of the
donation. The next time your Warrior is in a fight and fails to hit his
opponent, the sect's deity shines on him and he may re-roll the attack. He may
only do this once for each donation he makes (i.e., each time he rolls this
result on this table.)</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-62-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-63-hunting" name="Hunting">
    <rules>Your Warrior is invited by a group of locals to go on a nocturnal hunt.
Meeting them just before sunset, he is informed that tonight's prey is the great
Quarg - a beast of fearsome temper and foul disposition. His task in the group
is to take the hunting tools a net, a small pole with a bell on it and a bag full of
garlic - and wait in the middle of the woods while the rest of the hunters
spread out into the forest and drive the Quarg towards him.

As the sun rises the next morning, and the owls return to their nests, there is
still no sign of the Quarg, your Warrior begins to wonder if someone is being
made a fool of...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-64-witchcraft" name="Witchcraft">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accused of witchcraft, and is chased through the streets by an
angry mob. Roll 1D6 on the following table:

1-3     Your Warrior escapes by jumping over the
Settlement wall and into the filthy water of the
moat. Pelted with eggs and rotten fruit, he staggers
out onto the far side, where he has to wait outside
for his companions.

4-5     Your Warrior ducks down a side alley and escapes,
but from now on must wear a disguise when out in
public!

6       Your Warrior turns angrily on the mob, demanding
an explanation. Shouting down the leader of the
mob, he establishes his authority over the crowd,
who sheepishly return to their hovels, pausing only
to give him 100 gold as way of compensation.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-65-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="rpb-settlement-66-accident" name="Accident">
    <rules>As your Warrior helps an old crone to cross the busy main street, a beer wagon unexpectedly crashes into him. She carefully peels him off the heavy,
iron-shod wheel, and takes him to the infirmary to be patched up. Your
Warrior cannot buy anything or visit any Special Locations for 1D6 days
while he recovers. While he is recovering you do not have to roll for him on
this table.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
</events>
