<?xml version="1.0"?>

<events xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="whq-events-schema.xsd">
  <event id="lm-outskirts-11-city-watch" name="City Watch">
    <rules>The City Watch is responding to citizen reports of particularly
aggressive vagrants and brazen pickpockets outside the
Settlement gates. Your Warrior is among those who are
detained by the angry(and extremely corrupt) guards. One
item of Treasure or piece of Equipment is confiscated as a
"stolen" article (determined at random) and your Warrior is
brutally flogged and must deduct 1D3 from their Starting
Wounds permanently.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-12-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-13-bandits" name="Bandits">
    <rules>Inanactofrevengeforthelossofoneof theirleaders,a group
of vicious bandits emerge from the hills on horseback,raiding
and looting the helpless peasants outside the Settlement.Your
Warrior mustroll1D6 on the table below:
1
Your Warrior is soon targeted by the bandits who
overpower them bysheernumbers.Theystealallof
theirgoldand1D3itemsofTreasure (your choice)
before the Settlement soldiers are able to drive them
back into the hills.
2-3
Theattackcatcheseveryonebysurpriseand,despite
the Warrior's best efforts to defend their belongings,
the bandits make off with oneitem ofTreasure(your
choice).
4-5
Your Warrior hides behind the makeshifttents,quietly
slashing bandits astheyrideby.WhentheSettlement
soldiers arrive,theyrewardyour Warrior with 1D6x25
gold for helping to defend the Settlement inhabitants.
6
Withadramaticleapoffathatchedroof,yourWarrior
attacksthelargest,mostpowerfulbanditin thegroup,
killing him outright.Theleaderlessattackersare easily
routed by the Settlementsoldiers.TheSettlement
leaders reward your Warrior with 1D6x50 gold for their
role in the fight and they are allowed entry into the
Settlement.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-14-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-15-argil-s-magic-emporium" name="Argil's Magic Emporium">
    <rules>Argil Fend le petter, a dishevelled travelling purveyor of salves
and unguents,has setup shop here for the day.Your Warrior
m ay purchase Argil's waresby following all of the normal rules
of visiting a Traderin the Settle m ent.
Cost
ITEM
Stock
Description
Buy
5
Heals 1D3 Wounds.
25g
Liniment
Tonic
6
50g
Heals 1D6 Wounds.
100g
Restores1pointtoany
6
Balm
Statistic that has previously
been reduced for anyreason.
150g
Heals Warrior to full.
10
Home Brew
175g
Gives your Warrior double
Quicksilver
Attacks for 1 Turn.
When using any of Argil'sitemsroll1D6.Ifthe scoreis1 your
Warriorloses1 Wound permanently and the item hasnoeffect.
If the score is a 2 or3 your Warrior loses 1 Wound permanently
but the item worksasstated.On a scoreof4,5 or 6theitem
worksas stated with no side effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-16-beggars" name="Beggars">
    <rules>Your Warrior cannot hide their heroic stature and dozens of
peasants soon surround them begging for money andfood.
that half of allthe Provisions they were carrying are gone
(roundeddown)and theyare1D6x20goldlighter!
3</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-21-bard" name="Bard">
    <rules>A colour fully dressed minstrel who is heading toward the
t gates notices your Warrior. with a look of
Settlement
recognition
1 he excitedly approaches your Warrior, loudly
strum ming his instrument and singing a ballad allabout your
Warrior'sexploits.Roll1D6below:
1-2
While the lyrical poet relates all of the interesting
exploits of your Warrior,a sm allcrowd gathers around,
excitedly.Ayoungloutsuddenlylashesout,stabbing
your Warriorwithapoisonousdagger!Hehappensto
be the offspring of a criminal who your Warrior once
broughttojustice.Theyoungscampisquicklysubdued
by the other peasants and your hero is rushed to a wise
man whomanagestoremovemuchof thevenom.Your
Warrior's life is saved but must deduct 1 Wound from
their Starting Wounds score permanently.
3-6
The bard's music focuses on all of your Warrior's good
deedsandheroics!SoonyourWarriorismobbedby the
the rest of the day giving blessings and allowing the
wretched to kiss their boots and touch their sweat
soaked handkerchief.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-22-hay-wagon" name="Hay Wagon">
    <rules>Your Warrior sees a wagon filled with hay enter through the
Settlement gates, presumably to feed the various animals
inside.A second hay wagon canbe seen approaching from a
distance and your Warrior has the crazy idea that they could
possibly steal away inside the wagonin orderto get backinto
theSettlement.IfyourWarriorchoosestodoso,roll1D6onthe
tablebelow:
1
Injured!Asthe wagonreachestheSettlementGate,it
is stopped by the guards who begin stabbing their
swordsrandomlyinto thehaypile.Asoneof thesword
thrusts penetrates your Warrior'sstomach,theyletout
ablood-curdlingcry!Rollanother1D6andifthescoreis
a1,yourWarriorexpiresonthespotandisremoved
from the game.Onany other score they survive
although they mustdeduct1 Wound permanently from
their Starting Woundsscore.YourWarriorspendthe
next 1D6 daysinjail,isfined 100 gold and is thrown
back outof the Settlement.
2-3
Caught!AnobservantgateguardseesyourWarrior's
foot sticking partiallyoutof thehay.Your Warrior is
wrenched from the wagon and thrown into a jail cell for
1D3days.Theyarefined1o0goldbeforebeingthrown
4-5
Unnoticed!Thehaywagonpassesthroughthegates
with your Warrior hidden in the hay and noone is the
wiser!Afew momentsafteritstops,your Warrior hops
outunobserved.YourWarriormaynowfollowallthe
normal rules for staying in aSettlement.
6
Spotted!YourWarriorhidesin thehay wagonand
enters the Settlementunnoticed.Whentheyfeelitis
the wagon is parked in front of thejail!Standingnextto
your Warrior is the captain of the watch who eyes them
suspiciously."Notimefornapping!" he snorts."This
hayneedstogetdeliveredto theanimalpens." The
captain hands your Warrior 1D6x10gold coins and
sends them on their way!Your W arrior m ay now follow
all the normal rules for staying in a Settlement.
4</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-23-outbreak" name="Outbreak">
    <rules>There is an outbreak of Tyrant's Fever and your Warrior quickly
becomes bed-ridden,their face becomes red and painfully
swollen.They mustroll1D6atthebeginning ofeach dayonthe
following table adding +1to the score each subsequent time
(remembering the Rule of1and 6).
1
The fever has taken a turn for the worse and your
Warrior can only moanin pain,unabletoleavetheirbed.
Your Warriorsuffers-1to Strength or Toughness (your
choice)forthenext Adventure.IftheirStrength or
Toughnesseverreacheszero,theyaredead.
2-5
The fever runs high and your Warrior is bedridden in
their makeshift hovel. Whilst laid up,your Warrior does
6
The fever breaks and your Warrior returns to normal by
the end of the day.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-24-horse-thief" name="Horse Thief">
    <rules>While your Warrior is busy relieving himself in a m a ke shift
latrine,ahorsethief makes off with theirmount.Ifyour Warrior
has a horse, markit offyour Adventure Record Sheet along
with anything that was attached it, such as a cart. If your
Warriorhasnomounts,treatitasanUneventfulDayinstead.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-25-riot" name="Riot">
    <rules>Stoked by the words of a few malcontents the lowly inhabitants
who dwell outside of the Settlement have had enough of their
impoverished situation. A small gathering has erupted into a
dangerous riot pitting the peasantsagainstthelocalWatch.Roll
1D6onthetablebelow:
1
Your Warrior is arrested and charged with inciting ariot
They(ortheircompanions) mustpay 1D6x200 goldin
fines and bribes to clear up the matter.Iftheycannot
pay they are hangedin the center of the Settlement in
1D6daysasawarningto theothervagabondsOutside
theGates.
Your Warrior is beaten terribly by the Watch and
2-3
thrownintojail.Theymustpay1D6x100gold.Ifthey
cannotpaytheymustspendthenext1D6 days in jail
4-5
Joiningtherioters,your Warrior strides steadfastly into
the Settlement where the angry mob demand sample
sustenance,clean water and accessto medical
treatment.TheSettlementofficials eventually agreeto
acompromiseandeachpeasant,includingyour Warrior,
isgiven 1D3 Provisions,1D3Bandages and1D6x5gold.
6
Organizingtherioters,your Warrior marches the pack
of peasants into the Settlement demanding to meet
with high officials.Theterrifiedauthorities quickly meet
the demands of your Warrior and the peasants are
given accesstofood,clean waterand medical facilities.
ThepeasantsandyourWarriorareeachgiven1D6
Provisionsand1D6Bandages.YourWarrioralso
receives1D6x50goldinpaymentasanegotiatorand
for keeping the peasants from using violence to solve
the matter.
SE</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-26-the-black-tiger" name="The Black Tiger">
    <rules>A masked criminal,the Black Tiger,sneaksinto your Warrior's
makeshift camp in the middle of the night.Hestealsfrom the
rich and gives to the poor.Ifyour Warrior has more than 1oo
gold,the outlaw steals half. If your Warrior has less than 100
gold,theoutlaw does nothing.Ifyour Warrior has no gold atall,
the Black Tiger slips 1oo gold pieces into your Warrior's purse.
In any case,the outlaw leaves a piece of parchment with a
tiger's paw print on your Warrior's chest which they findin the
morning upon waking.
Note: if the Bounty Hunter rolls this Event,im mediate ly roll up
a new Outlaw following allthe normalrules. This Outlaw also
has the Vanish 5+ Ability in addition to any others. (See the
Bounty Hunter Revision by Littlemonk).</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-31-bad-omen" name="Bad Omen">
    <rules>Your Warrior continually glimpses a black cat prowling about
nearthem. Others in the vicinity also notice and swear it is a
bad omen.Your Warrior is so perturbed by the situation that
Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-32-wizard-s-apprentice" name="Wizard's Apprentice">
    <rules>Late at night your Warrior witnesses a thin, frail man being
assaulted by a group of hoodlums. Rushing to his aid your
Warrior fends off the attackers whoscatterinto thenight.The
man gasps for breath as blood pours from anopen woundon
hishead.Bythelook of his clothes and belongings the young
manappearstobeanapprenticingwizard.Fartooinjuredtobe
healed by bandages,your Warrior can onlysave him ifthey give
themanahealingpotion.
Ifyour Warrior does so,theapprenticerepaysyour Warrior
by casting a powerful spell that permanently increases one of
1 1D6 to see which
Warrior's Characteristics. Roll
your
Characteristic is affected:
Initiative
1
4
Weapon Skill
Willpower
2
5
Strength
3
Luck
Toughness
6
If your Warrior has no healing potion, the young apprentice
expires...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-33-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-34-curse" name="Curse">
    <rules>into a patch of dead weeds and flowers adjacent to a crude
dwelling. An old crone im mediate ly em erges yelling and
screaming that your Warrior has destroyed her perfect lilies.
She levels her finger at your Warrior and curses them
malevolently before returning to her abode. Your Warrior must
im mediatelydeduct1Luckpointpermanently!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-35-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-36-animal-rampage" name="Animal Rampage">
    <rules>attackingthepeasants.Your Warrior mustroll2D6.Thisisthe
number of animals attacking them.Rollanother 1D6and add
your W arrior's Battle-level,the score beingthe amount of wild
animals your Warrior kills. If any animals remain, your Warrior
injures their hand in theskirmishandsuffers-1 WeaponS kill for
the next Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-41-stench" name="Stench">
    <rules>The smell of urine and excrement is particularly overwhelming
second time during their stay atthis Settlement,then they are
so sickened by the smell that they suffer-1 Strength forthe
next Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-42-famished" name="Famished">
    <rules>Your Warrior must eat a provision or other food they are
carrying to maintain their health and strength.Ifthey have no
food,your Warriorsuffers-1Strengthin thenextAdventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-43-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-44-collapse" name="Collapse">
    <rules>In the middle of the night a wall collapses upon your Warrior's
m a ke shift cam p. Your Warrior's legis severely injured and they
areunabletotravelfor1D3daysandmustremain outside the
gates of theSettlement.In addition they suffer-1Movementfor
the next Adventure. Whilstinjured,your Warrior does not have</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-45-spirit" name="Spirit">
    <rules>The spirit of a druid appears in front of your Warrior late at
night and accuses them of destroying sacred foliage during
their recent journey to the Settlement.He demands that your
Warrior make amends by planting atree or bushin a shady
grove.Your Warrior suffers-1 Luck until they do so.Ittakes
1D3 days to make amends and your Warrior must rollfor
5</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-46-noble" name="Noble">
    <rules>An influential noble and his entourage are galloping through
toward the Settlement gates and soon a small crowd has
blocked their way to beg for food and coin. The noble
inexplicably spots your Warrior amongst the crowd and points a
fingeratthem.Roll1D6 one the following table:
1
The noble is extremely irritated that the crowdhas
stoppedhim.Itisobviousto him thatyour Warrior,
beingstoutandstrongcomparedto thefrailbeggars,is
theoneincharge.Hedirectshisguardstosurround
your Warrior aggressively and they drag them in front
of thenobleforaseverebeating.Your Warrior must
deduct1from their Starting Wounds score
permanently.
2
The greedy noble eyes one of your Warrior's it emf
Treasure(determinedatrandom)andsendshislackeys
toobtainit.Uponpain ofdeath,your Warrior reluctantly
hands over the item.
3
The noble is suspicious ofyour Warrior and calls for the
Watch to apprehend and interrogatethem.For1D3
daysyour Warrior is grilled and beaten until eventually
being fined 1D6x10 goldforloitering(your Warrior
m ustsell item sorequipmentifnecessary).Theyare
4
Among all of the wretched beggars the compassionate
noblehaschosenyouastherecipientof1D6x10gold.
5
Thenoble keenly observes that your Warrior may be of
someuseforaparticularlyimportanttask.Heoffersto
hire them for the day,payingthem 1D6x20gold to
watch hishorse while in the Settlement.In addition,
your Warrior m ay visit any Location not previously
visited during this stay in the Settlement and must pay
LivingExpensesasnormal.YourWarriorreturns
6
The noble calls out your name and beckons you over.
Familiar with your recent heroic undertakings he wishes
todonate1D6x100goldtoyourcause.IfyourWarrior
wasnotallowedinto theSettlementforanyreason,he
berates the watchcom m anderand Settlement officials
whoim mediate ly apologize to your Warrior for any
misunderstandingsandallowthemre-entry.Youmay
treat this as a new visit to the Settlement and your
Warrior m ay visit Traders and Special Locations even
they had done so previously in this Settlement.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-51-pests" name="Pests">
    <rules>Mischievous wild animals sneak into your Warrior's camp and
pilfer some of your Warrior'spossessions.Roll1D6to see what
they have taken:
1
Anitem ofTreasure(determined atrandom).
2
A Potion(determined atrandom).
3
ARope.
4
ABandage.
5
A Provision.
Nothing.
6
Ifthe Warrior has such asitem they mustdiscardit.Ifthey
don't have it,they does nothing.In any case,rollagain.Ifyou
roll lower than your first score to see whattheanimalstole,the
animal also stole the second item too,and soon.Assoon as
you roll the same number again orhigher,stoprolling.
6</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-52-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-53-pet-dog" name="Pet Dog">
    <rules>Your Warrior is adopted byasmalldog.Itfollowsthem around
and then emerging after the adventure is completed to shower
itsnew master withadoration.Rollonthe Pet Dog Event Table
(page 24) to see exactly which type of canine has attached
itselftoyou.
Your Warrior can killthe dogif you want,butit would be a
crueland heartless thing to do andit will cost them 1,ooo gold
to pay for a decent burial for the hound!
Ifyour Warrior already hasa pet dog,rollonthistable again.
Ifnot,nameit and noteit down on your Warrior's Adventure
RecordSheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-54-lepers" name="Lepers">
    <rules>Lepers begging for food accost your Warrior. The lepers will
approach your Warrior each day until your Warrior gives them
food,untilyour Warrior departs for the nextAdventure,or until
your Warrior contracts their horrid affliction.
Each day the lepers approachtobegforfood,your Warrior
mustroll2D6.Ifboth dice come up the same number your
Warrior has contracted their foul disease and they suffer-1
Movement from nowuntiltheendof thenextAdventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-55-madman" name="Madman">
    <rules>A deranged lunatic approaches your Warrior and lunges forward
with a knife! Your Warrior deals him a fatal blow in a clear act
of self-defense. Rummaging through the deceased man's
belongings your Warrior realizes that the man's necklace bears
the crest of Duke Hilderwhelm.Monthsago,the Duke's nephew
wasrumouredtobemissingandthismustbehim!Roll1D6to
see the result of your Warrior's actions:
1
The authorities are furious and accuse your Warrior of
murder!Theyarethrownintojailandscheduledtobe
executedin10days.Attheendofeachdaythat
passes,including this one,roll 1D6.If the result is a 6,it
means that a witness to the incident has come forward
to exonerate your Warrior.YourWarrioristhen
immediatelyescortedoutsidetheSettlementgates.If
no witnesscomesforwardby theendof thetenthday,
your Warrior is beheaded in the center of the
Settlementbeforealarge,jeeringcrowd.
2-3
In order to avoid any public embarrassment abouthis
deceased nephew's stateofmind,DukeHilderwhelm
has your Warrior arrested on trumped up charges.He
will only drop the charges if your Warrior agrees to pay
afine and keep quiet about the entireincident.These
negotiationstake1D6daysandcostyourWarrior
1D6x50gold.IfyourWarriordoesnothavetheamount
(after selling any Equipment or Treasure to cover the
cost)thentheDuketakeswhatevergoldtheyhaveand
drops the charges.
4-5
The influential Duke Hil der w helm has your Warrior
arrested claiming that your Warrior killed his nephew
during aduel.Your Warrior spends 3 days in jail while
authoritiesdetermineiftheduelwasproper.
6
DukeHilderwhelm,wellawareofhisnephew's
deterioratedmentalstate,paysyourWarrior1D6x100
goldtokeepsilentabouttheentireincident.
SE</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-56-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-61-mysterious-priest" name="Mysterious Priest">
    <rules>frail looking horseis offering comfort and solace to some of the
more wretched inhabitants - or so it seems. As the wagon
approaches your Warrior,roll1D6onthetablebelow:
1
Uponcom mandfrom the priest a nightmarish creature
bursts from the wagon and assaults your Warrior who
manages to dispatchit,butonly after it claws them
repeatedly.Thepriestvanishesduringthestruggleand
your Warrior im m ediatelybeginstofeelill,thevictim of
a strange disease that the creature carried.They m ust
spendthenext1D3daysinbeddoingnothingand must
deduct1D6 Wounds from their Starting Wounds score
permanently.
The priest convinces your Warrior to trade one of their
2-3
weapons for one the priest claims is a holy artefact that
will protect them from harm.Ifyour Warrior is the
WarriorPriest,theBretonnian Knight,ortheSisterof
Sigmar,theysenseeviland corruption and decline the
offersteadfastly.AnyotherWarriormustroll1D6and
addtheir Willpower.Ifthetotalis 8or more they refuse.
If the total is less than 8theyreadily agree to the trade
and must discard a weapon of theirchoice.The weapon
traded for is the same type as the one given but it
carriesa terrible curse.
Inthe nextAdventure,eachtime anatural1isrolled
in the Power Phase,yourWarrior mustdraw and use
the cursed weapon.The weapononlyhitsonanatural6
anddoesDamageasnormal.However,ifhisToHitisa
natural1,your Warrior uncontrollably lashes outand
attacks the nearest Warrior instead.
AtthenextSettlement,your Warrior may rid himself
of the weapon and the curse by visiting a Temple and
paying 1D6x100 gold.
4
The priest turns out to be a simple clergyman on his
wayto anearbymonastery.
5
The priest is carrying food for the less fortunate and
upon seeing the sorry state ofyour Warrior's tattered
gear and items he offers to trade food in exchange for
anyitem your Warrioriscarrying.Foreachitem of
Equipment or Treasure that they give up,your Warrior
is given 1D6 Provisions.
6
The priest tells your Warrior that he has seen them in a
vision and that they willbecomea'starof theheavens'.
Heplaces something in your Warrior's hand and then
leads his horse and wagon away into the darkness.
Theitem placedin his hand is a polished stone with a
strangerune.OnceperAdventureyourWarriormay
utilise the power within thestone which allows them to
addanextra1D6to theirStrengthforoneCombat.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-62-healer" name="Healer">
    <rules>A healeris passing through the makeshift camps outside the
Settlements offering to cure any maladies at no charge. Roll
1D6 and if the score is a 5 or6,thehealerreallydoes have the
power to heal and restores 1 point to one Characteristic (your
choice)thathasbeen previouslyreducedforanyreason(such
as Poison, etc.). On any other score,the healer blesses your
Warrior by licking his thum b and then rubbing it across your
Warrior's forehead before moving on.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-63-heavy-rains" name="Heavy Rains">
    <rules>A heavy rainfall bombards the Settlement. With no placeto
the constant downpour, your Warrior
seek refuge from
develops a terrible, hacking cough.During the nextDungeon,
your Warrior suffers-1 To Hit until they drink a Healing Potion.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-64-young-whelp" name="Young Whelp">
    <rules>Your Warrior catches ayoung urchin trying to steal their purse.
The boy claims that he's an orphan supporting himself and his
sisterandbegsformercy.IfyourWarriorfreeshim,roll1D6:
1-2
ThecontemptuousyoungladpromisestoNEVER,EVER
steal again and darts away.YourWarrior'sfearsare
confirmed when they reach into their pack and
discoversthatoneitemismissing(determined
randomly).
3-6
Theboyfallstohiskneesinoverwhelmingthanks.
Before departing he gives your Warriora piece of
parchment that he lifted offofa merchant in the
Settlement,explainingthathecan'tread anyway.Onit
is the location of a secret cache of gold worth 1D6x100
gold.Ifthe Warriors defeat all of the Monsters in the
Objective Room duringthenextAdventure,your
Warrior may claim this treasure.
Ifyour Warrior delivers him in to the Watchroll1D6:
1-3
The poor lad cannot withstand the severe beating
receives from the authoritiesanddies,leavinghissister
to careforherself.Accordingtolocallawsand customs
your Warrior is now responsible for the girl's welfare.
From now on,each time your Warrior reaches a
Settlement,they mustsend1D6x50goldforherliving
expenses.
4-6
The impudent child has been a huge menace and the
Watch has been trying to apprehend the young whelp
forthepastmonth.YourWarriorisgiven 1D6x25gold
for catching the troublesome urchin.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-65-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-outskirts-66-admittance" name="Admittance">
    <rules>In order to address the grumbling of the lower classes, the
mayor of the Settlement has declared that a small handful of
peasants willbe allowed to enter.Ifyour Warrior was restricted
from entering the Settlement for any reason,they are one of
the lucky few selected. They may re-enter the Settlement
immediately if they so choose, paying Living Expenses and
7</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-11-thrown-out" name="Thrown Out">
    <rules>Your Warrior's wild behaviour attracts the attention of the
Settlement authorities and there are thrown outoftown.They
must wait outside the Settlement gates for the other Warriors.
In addition,roll1D6.On a score of1 your Warrior is fleeced
by the gate guards asthey are thrown outand have alltheir
gold stolen!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-12-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-13-hunting" name="Hunting">
    <rules>Your Warrior is invited by a group of locals togo on a nocturnal
hunt.
Meeting them just before sunset,they are informed that
tonight's prey is the great Qu arg a beast of fearsome temper
andfouldisposition.Your Warrior's task in the group is to take
the hunting tools- a net,a sm all pole with a bellon it and a bag
full of garlic and wait in the middle of the woods while the rest
of the hunters spread out into the forest and drive theQuarg
towardsthem.Asthesunrisesthenextmorning,and theowls
return to their nests, there is stillno sign of the Quarg,your
Warrior begins to wonder if someone is being madeafoolof...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-14-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-15-witchcraft" name="Witchcraft">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accused of witchcraft,andis chased through
the streets by an angry mob. Roll1D6 on the following table
(the Witch Hunter may add +1tohisscore):
1-3 Your Warrior escapes by jumping over the Settlement
wall and into the filthy water of the moat.Pelted with
eggsandrottenfruit,theystaggeroutonto thefar
rules (page 3).
4-5
Your Warrior ducks down aside alley andescapes,but
from now on must wear a disguise when out in public!
6
Your Warrior turns angrily on the mob,demandingan
explanation.Shoutingdowntheleaderof the m ob,they
establish theirauthorityoverthecrowd,who sheepishly
returnto theirhovels,pausingonlytogive your Warrior
1o0goldas way of compensation.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-16-nightmare" name="Nightmare">
    <rules>As your Warrior retires for the evening they fall into a deep
slumber.Theybeginto dream that they are fighting a terrifying
gorgon;herhaircomposedofvicioussnakesand agaze which
can turn a person to stone. with a horrendous scream the
gorgon attacks! Roll 1D6 to see how the dream ends:
1
No matter how many times or how hardyour Warrior
strikes the creature with their weapon,the beast
seemsinvulnerable.Withaterrifying scream the
gorgon shootsan arrow directly into your Warrior's
heart!
Whenyour Warriorwakes,theyfindthat theyhave
permanently lost 1 Wound!Ifyour Warrior's Starting
Woundsiseverreducedtozerobecauseofthisdream,
theyaredead.
Tomorrow night the nightmare returns and they must
roll on this table again.MakeanoteonyourAdventure
Record Sheet to remind you.
2-5
The battle is brutal and neither your Warrior nor the
creatureseemstogettheupperhand.YourWarrior
wakesin acold sweat.
Tomorrow night the nightmare returns and they must
roll on this table again!MakeanoteonyourAdventure
Record Sheet to remind you.
Your Warrior courageously stands their ground and
6
strikes the wretchedbeastdown!A sense of relief fills
your Warrior and they sleep better than they have in a
long time.
Whenyour Warrior awakens they discover that they
are +1to his Starting Wounds!The nightmare ends
and theydonothavetorollonthistableagain(unless
theyencounterthisSettlementEventagain)!
If your Warrior leaves the Settlement before the dream
concludes, the nightmare temporarily ends. At the next
Settlement, however,it returns to haunt the Warrior again.
MakeanoteonyourAdventureRecordSheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-21-well" name="Well">
    <rules>Strolling alongside a dilapidated oldhouse your Warrior spies an
old,stone well.Your Warrior casually tosses in 1 gold coin.Roll
1D6 on the table below:
1
Acreepy,gutturalmoanechoesupwardinanunknown
tongue.A terrible sense of dread overwhelms your
Warriorand theysuffer-1LuckforthenextAdventure.
2-5
Nothing happens and your Warrior is now carrying one
less gold piece.
6
A high pitched squeal and soft giggling can be heard at
the bottom of the well.Your Warrior gains +1Luck for
next Adventure!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-22-festival" name="Festival">
    <rules>Asyour Warriors trolls through the village centre it is abuzz with
thepreparationsfortomorrow'sfestival.Roll1D6tosee what
festival is being celebrated and another 1D6tosee what effect
ithason ALL ofyour Warriors.
1D6
Festival
A Beer festival
1
2
A Food festival
A festival for the Deceased
3
4
A Religious festival
A Music festival
5
6
A Cultural festival
1D6
Effect
1
In recognition of thefestival,alllocations willbe closed
forthenext1D6 days.Warriorswhoaretrainingwill
find their instruction interrupted during the period and
they mustadd on those extra days to their training
time.
2
In recognition of the festival, all traders will close up
shopforthenext1D3days.
3
The population of the Village will double as it welcomes
visitors from thesurroundingregion.Forthenext1D3
days all Warriors must roll on the Town Events Table
instead of the Village Events Table.In addition,
Warriors may make all stock rolls as if in a Town
(2D6).
4
Vendors,merchantsandtraders will make their wayto
the Village tomorrow and any Warrior may visitthe
Peddler, who is treated exactly asthe Peddler from the
Role play Book (page 15)orthenew,expanded
Travelling Hazards by Little monk (page 8).Visitingthe
Peddler takes an entire day during which a Warrior
5
In celebration (but mostly to lure in new customers)all
locations will offer one item in stock at5o%.Thissale
is offered tomorrow only.
6
In celebration (but m ostly tolurein customers)all
locations willoffer1o% of fall items in stock.Thissale
is offered tomorrow only!
If any Warrior rolls this Settlement Event again during this
stay,re-rollthis result.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-23-family-heirloom" name="Family Heirloom">
    <rules>An item of Treasure that your Warrior is carrying (determined
randomly)isidentifiedbya wealthy,influentialmemberof the
local citizenry ashisfamilyheirloom,stolenlastyearby wanton
burglars.The local Watch confiscates theitem and you must
discarditimmediately.If your Warrior has no Treasure items,
the wealthy local accuses your Warrior of hiding it and demands
1D6x50 goldin restitutioninstead.Ifthey cannotpay,then your</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-24-runaway" name="Runaway">
    <rules>While walking along the main street, your Warrior hears a
disturbance just around the corner.A moment later a huge
runaway bull charges down thestreet, wrecking market stalls
andcausingpanic.YourWarriorcanletitpassbyhidingdowna
side alley, or try to stop the enraged animal.If your Warrior
hides down the alley and lets the bullpass, roll 1D6 on the
following table:
1-3
YourWarriorskulksin theshadows,waitingforthe
actiontodiedown.Astheypeep roundthecorner,a
mugger's metal bar hits them overthe head.Whenthey
regain consciousness,your Warrior's purse is 1oo gold
coins lighter.
4-6
After waiting nervously in the dark forafew minutes,
your Warrior sees the bull roar past and career off
downasidestreet.Thedangerispassedandyour
Warrior may carry on about their business.
Ifyour Warrior tries to stopthe bull,roll1D6 on the following
table:
1-2
Your Warrior waves the passers by aside and leaps out
infrontof thebull,sword drawn.The bull hesitates for
halfa secondorso,and thentramplesthem into the
dirt before carrying on its way.The crowd then stomps
all over your Warrior in the rush to follow the bull,
leaving them to nurse their injuries alonein an empty
street.
3-4
A single sword thrust stops the bull dead in its tracks
literally.Asitscarcasstwitchesspasmodically,the
crowd roars in approval and showers your Warrior with
100 gold.Thenthebull'senragedownerarrives,and
relieves them of150gold-it washisprizestud,and he
wanteditstopped,notslaughtered!
5-6
Your Warrior gives the bulla hard stare and its kids to a
halt,snortingandpawingtheground.Puttingarope
arounditsneck,theyleaditbacktoitsstall.Thecrowd
cheers and showers them with150gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-25-illness" name="Illness">
    <rules>A terrible illness strikes the Settlem ent, and your W arrior falls
preytoit.Theymustspend thenexttwodaysinbed,paying10
gold per day for medication as well as the normal Living
Expenses.Whileyour Warrior is in bed,youdonothavetoroll</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-26-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-31-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-32-temple-donation" name="Temple Donation">
    <rules>Much taken with the teachings of thelocalpriest,your Warrior
pledges 1D6x50 gold to his cause, selling equipment if
necessary to meetthecostof thedonation.Thenexttime your
Warrior is in a fight and fails to hit their opponent,the sect's
only do this once foreach donation they make (i.e.,each time
they roll this result on this table).</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-33-river-monster" name="River Monster">
    <rules>Your Warrior overhears that the local fisherman are com plaining
ofa giant aquatic monster that has been terror ising them down
by the river. Upon investigation your Warrior discovers a
massive creature thathas somehow managed to findits way
inland.Aftera few patient hours your Warrior spots the beast
anda smallbattleforwaterrightsensues.Roll1D6onthetable
below:
1
ThestrangecreatureistoomuchforyourWarrior.
Razor sharp teeth and a piercing snout tear at your
Warrior and soonthey are running from the river at top
speed,muchto thechagrin of thelocals.Yourbested
Warriorsuffers-1ToughnessforthenextAdventure.
2-3
The mighty fish tosses your Warrior about and leaves
them on the bank in a heap.Theirhandis badly injured
in the struggle and they suffer-1 Weapon Skill for the
next Adventure.
4-5
Your Warrior thrashes about in the water as the
creature snaps and stabs at them with its long duck
likebill.Eventually your Warrior drives the creature
away and returns to the applauding fishermen who
thank them with1D6x25 gold.
6
As the giant fish leaps outof the water,yourWarrior
fellsit withone swift and accurate blow.The fishermen
are ecstatic as they haul the beast out of the water.
They regard your Warrior as a hero and givethem
1D6x50 gold.Inaddition,theyusethecreatureto
prepare1D6 ProvisionsforyourWarrior.Treatthem
like normal Provisions from the General Store.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-34-snake" name="Snake">
    <rules>As your Warrior passes bya potter'sstore,a woman comes
running out hollering about a poisonous snake that has slipped
in. She immediately hires your Warrior to rid hershop of the
snake,butshe warns them notto break any of her pottery
which is on display throughout the shop.Roll1D6below:
1
The snake is much harder to catch or kill than
anticipated and your Warrior practically tears the shop
apart before finally corralling thereptile.Angrily,the
shopownerdemands1D6x50goldforherloses.
2-3
Justas your Warriors lips the snag into a burlap sack,
they stumble backward into a rare and expensive pot
which falls to the ground withaloudcrash.After
deducting their pay for catching the snake,your Warrior
owesthepotter1D6x10goldforthedamage.
4-5
Stepping into the potter's shop your Warrior spies the
cold blooded creature coiled upin therafters.They
manageto bring it down along with afew cups hanging
onthe wall.Thepotteris elated and,afterdeductingfor
damage,paysyour Warrior1D6x10gold.
6
No sooner than your Warrior enters the shop do they
pounce upon the terrifying reptile,snatchingit with
their bare hands.Whenthey bringthe beastie back out,
the potter is elated that nothing wasdamaged.She
paysyour Warrior1D6x25goldfor theirservices.
10</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-35-accident" name="Accident">
    <rules>As your Warrior helps an old crone to cross the busy main
street,a beer wagon unexpectedly crashes into them. She
carefully peels them offthe heavy,iron-shed wheel,andtakes
them to the infirmary to be patched up. Your Warrior cannot
buy anything or visit any Special Locations for 1D6 days while
they recover. While they are recovering you do not have to roll</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-36-pacifist" name="Pacifist">
    <rules>Seeing them armed andbattle-hardened,apacifistapproaches
your Warrior,attemptingtoconvertthem to the ways ofnon-
violence.Theyounglady is passionate and convincing and you
mustroll1D6 and add your Warrior's Willpower.Look upthe
result on the table below to see what effect her words have on
your W arrior.
2-4
Your Warrior takes the words of the woman to heart
and they vow to relinquish one of their weapons(your
choice).Discarditim mediately.
5-6
Your Warrior is thoroughly convinced by the wordsof
theyoung woman and in the next Adventure they
promisethat,asidefrom theirregularAttacks,they
will not use any special skills or abilities that cause
Damage.
7-8
Your Warrior deeply considers the words of the young
woman and in the next Dungeon they refuse to make
an Attack in the first Warriors ' Phase ofeach combat.
Your Warrior is unaffected by the words of the young
9or
lady.
more</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-41-pickpocket" name="Pickpocket">
    <rules>As your Warrior rushes through the busy streets,theirmoney
pouch is stolen.
YourWarriorloses1D6x20 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-42-betrothed" name="Betrothed">
    <rules>Due to a mistake in identity, your Warrior finds himself
are betrothed to marrytheirsister.Your Warrior agrees,albeit
at knifepoint,andpledgestheirtroth to a farmer's daughter of
a m ple charm s.
The marriage is arranged fortomorrow,so your Warrior
must either leave the Settlement im mediately,orget married...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-43-friendly-villager" name="Friendly Villager">
    <rules>As your Warrior heads back to the inn for a bit of relaxation,
they encounter a villager who welcomes them to the Settlement
heartily and insists on taking them to the nearest tavern for a
drink.Roll1D6 on the following tables:
1D6
ThepersonistheVillage...
1
Idiot
Drunk
2
3
Loudmouth
4
Bard
Gate Guard
5
Elder
6
Nowrollanother1D6andaddthenumberrolledabove.Look
uptheresultonthetablebelow:
Result
Total
2-3
Upon entering thetavern,yourWarrioris
im mediate ly surrounded byruffians.Theyfind out
that the villager owes a huge debt to the owner of
the establishment and he was told not to return until
hisdebt waspaidinfull.Beforebeingthrown out
with theirnew friend,your Warrior is relieved of
1D6x50gold.Iftheydonothavethatamount,the
owner takes one item ofTreasure(determinedat
random)ascompensation.
4-5
As your Warrior struts into the tavern with the
villageritisapparentthat theyarenotwelcomehere.
Afterbeingroughedupandthrownout,yourWarrior
finds outthat one of the enforcers made off with one
item of Equipment(determined atrandom).Discard
itim mediately.
6-8
Your Warrior spends the next few hours politely
listening to the boring history of the settlement after
whichthe villager leaves them to foot the bill, which
amountsto1D6x10gold.
As your Warrior and the villager walk through the
9-10
door,theotherpatronscheerfully greet them (the
villager is apparently a bit of a celebrity).Your
Warriorand thevillageraregivenfreefoodanddrink.
Your Warrior does not need to pay for living
expenses today.
11-12
The villager is well known and wellrespected.Seeing
your Warrior with him,thevillagersin thetavernpay
allof the Living Expenses for the rest of their stay in
theSettlementanddonate1D6x25goldtowardtheir
next Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-44-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-45-circus" name="Circus">
    <rules>Thereis a travelling circusintown,and your Warrior spends the
rest of their day wanderingfromsideshowtosideshow.Having
metthebeardedwomanand thetwo-headedgoat,theydecide
tohavetheirfortuneread.Perhapsthe sign above the door to
that particular wagon should say Have your fortune stolen',as
for a cost of 1D6x10 gold,your Warrior is told nothing more
than that their destiny lies with a tall, dark stranger from
Erengrad!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-46-gambling" name="Gambling">
    <rules>Your Warrior visits a localinn and gets involved in a dubious
gameofdice.Roll1D6onthefollowingtable:
Your Warriorlosesbadly,and must forfeit one item of
1
Treasure of your choice.
2
YourWarriorloses1D6x20gold.
3-4
YourWarriorcomesoutof thegameeven.
Your Warriorwins1D6x10gold.
5
Your Warrior wins3D6x10gold.
6</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-51-beggars" name="Beggars">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accosted by beggars and,overwhelmed by the
sadness of theirplight,gives each of the1D6 pitiful wretches5
gold.Ifyour Warriorcannotpaytheyareabeggarthemselves,
and you m ustroll1D6 on the following table:
1
Your Warrior is thrown out of the Settlement see
VillageEvent11.
Your Warriorgains1D6x5goldbybegging.
2-6</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-52-pugilist" name="Pugilist">
    <rules>As you wander through the Village your Warrior comes upon
some bare knuckle pugilists competing with one another.
Catching sight of your Warrior's garb and equipment they
im mediate ly hailyou tojoin them in a friendly bout,albeit with
much public jeering and taunting.Your Warrior has no choice
buttoupholdtheirreputationbyacceptingthelocals'challenge.
Stepping up to meet your Warrior is Bam wig,localchampion
and prize fighter. The protocols for such a bout here are
unfamiliar to your Warrior so they are given alist of rules and
regulations that they must adhere to.
Add your Warrior's Strength and Toughness together and
then factor in their Alehouse modifier (see your Warrior's
Rulebook). This is your Warrior's Fight Total. The local
champion's Fight Tota/is8.
Eachroundyoumustrolla1D6foryour Warrior and another
1D6forBamwig.Deduct your Warrior's score from their Fight
Totaland then deduct Bam wig's roll from his. Keep a running
total on a piece of paperand the first contender whose Fight
Total reaches zero (orbelow)is theloser.Ifboth contestants '
score reach zero or below atthe same time the higher score
prevails.In case ofa tie, continue another round until one of
them is the winner.
If your Warrior wins the match they receive one item of
Dungeon Room Treasure. If they are defeated, the local
champion and his cohorts relieve them of half their gold!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-53-inheritance" name="Inheritance">
    <rules>A head villager approaches your Warrior and in forms them that
a distant relative hasjust passed away and has left them an
inheritance.Roll1D6 tosee what the inheritance is:
1
The inheritance is a debt and the head villager has come
tocollect!Your Warrior mustforfeit1D6x25 gold selling
Equipment and Treasure if necessary!
2-3
The inheritance is actually apet dog(seeEvent63).If
your W arrior already has a pet dog,treat this as a roll
of 1 above.
4
The inheritance is a small sum of money to the amount
of 1D6x25 gold!
The inheritance is a small sum of money to the amount
5
of1D6x50 gold!
6
The inheritance is anitem of Dungeon Room Treasure!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-54-fooled" name="Fooled">
    <rules>Your Warrior must discard anyone purchase they have madein
this Settlement,as it was a fake and is worth nothing!Ifyour
Warrior has not yet made any purchases in this Settlement,
treat this as an Uneventful Day.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-55-riotous-living" name="Riotous Living">
    <rules>Taken with the joys of hot food and a comfortable bed afterso
long outin the wild,your Warrior overspends on such luxuries
by30 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-56-an-honest-day-s-work" name="An Honest Day's Work">
    <rules>Your Warrior is employed by a local farmer to carry bales of
cotton to the riverside area forthe day.This task earns them
20 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-61-fire" name="Fire">
    <rules>As your Warrior passes by a small house they see smoke
seeping out from underthefrontdoor.Rushinginsidetheydrag
outthe unconsciousinhabitants.Almostthe entire village turns
outto fight the blaze and the house is saved with no casualties.
Your Warrior is being congratulated as a hero,especially from
the surviving family who makea giftof 1D6x20 gold in thanks.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-62-troubadour" name="Troubadour">
    <rules>A colour fully dressed minstrel notices your Warrior as they pass
by. With an exasperated laugh he follows your Warrior,loudly
strum ming hislute and singing aballad allabout your Warrior's
exploits.Roll1D6:
1-2
The raucous tune is an insulting account of all of your
Warrior'sfollies;from their missteps in combatto
spilling their drink atthetavern.Thebard also singsof
the unfortunate encounter with the miller's daughter
down by the river which angers some of her close male
relatives.They waitfor your Warrior around acorner,
throw a sack over their head and beat them severely.
Your Warriorsuffers-1 Strength forthe next
Adventure.
3-4
The ballad is all about your Warrior's exploits but no one
seemsto even notice orcare.
5-6
The bard embellishes all of your Warrior's good deeds
and heroics to such degree that even your Warrior is
impressed with himself.Alargegroup quickly gathers
and givesthreecheers!Your Warrior's inner spirit is
bolsteredand theyare+1Strengthforthenext
Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-63-pet-dog" name="Pet Dog">
    <rules>YourWarriorisadoptedbyasmalldog.Itfollowsthem around
everywhere,skulkingin theshadows while the fighting goes on
and then emerging after the adventure is completed to shower
its new master withadoration.RollonthePetDog Event Table
(page 24) to see exactly which type of canine has attached
itselftoyou.
Your Warrior can killthe dogif you want,butit wouldbea
cruel and heartless thingto doandit will cost them 1,ooo gold
to pay for a decent burial for the hound!
Ifyour Warrior already has a pet dog,ignorethis result and
roll again on the Village Events table.Ifnot,nameitand noteit
downonyourWarrior'sAdventureRecordSheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-64-crime" name="Crime">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accused of murder and thrown in jail. The
matter is sorted out eventually, but only after your Warrior's
companions have bailed them out.Each Warrior in the party
except the accused mustpay 1D6x5 gold to the authorities.
Iftheir companions do not have the money,your Warrior
mustspend1D6 daysinjail.Whileinjail they don't have to pay</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-65-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-village-66-fearful-villagers" name="Fearful Villagers">
    <rules>Your Warrior is carrying an item of magical Treasure
(determined randomly) that the villagers perceive as unlucky,
unholy ortaboo.ThelocalWatchisim mediate ly summoned and
your Warrior must either leave the Settlement im mediate ly or
surrender the item to the authorities (after which it is properly
destroyed in a cerem ony involving a bonfire,a catapult,a ten
poundhammerandalargesquash).</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-11-thrown-out" name="Thrown Out">
    <rules>Your Warrior's wild behaviour attracts the attention of the
Settlement authorities and there are thrown out oftown.They
must wait outside the Settlement gates for the other Warriors.
In addition,roll1D6.On ascore of 1 your Warrior is fleeced
goldstolen!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-12-well" name="Well">
    <rules>Strolling alongside a dilapidated old house your Warrior spies an
old,stone well.Your Warrior casually tosses in 1 gold coin. Roll
1D6onthetablebelow:
1
Acreepy,guttural moan echoes upward in an unknown
tongue.Aterriblesenseofdreadoverwhelmsyour
Warrior and they suffer-1 Luck for the next Adventure.
2-5
Nothing happens and your Warrior is now carrying one
less gold piece.
6
A high pitched squeal and soft giggling can be heard at
the bottom of the well.Your Warrior is +1Luckforthe
next Adventure!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-13-debt" name="Debt">
    <rules>A debt collector catches up with your Warrior, demanding
payment for money borrowed yearsago.Thesum your Warrior
borrowed was not substantial, but the interest rates are
astronomical. The outstanding balance is 1D6x20 gold,andif
your Warrior cannot pay in fullim mediate ly the debt collector
takes alltheir gold plus one piece of Equipment or Treasure
(determinedrandomly).</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-14-investment" name="Investment">
    <rules>In one of the wharf side bars,your Warrior meets a young
to cover the known world.Hetalksyour Warrior into investing
1D6x50 gold, giving them a certificate of partnership. From
now on,at the end of each Dungeon, whenever your Warrior
reaches civilisation,they may visitthe local Merchants ' Guild
and show them their deed of partnership. Consulting their
records,they can tell your Warrior how the company is doing.
Roll1D6 on the following table:
1
Thecompanyhasgonebust,andyourWarrior's
investment is worthnothing.Inaddition,they mustpay
themerchants1D6x50 goldin outstanding debts.
2-5
Your Warrior's investment is performing fairly well,and
the merchant forwards them 1D6x10 gold as their
share of the profits.
6
Businessisbooming!Afterconsultingtheledger,the
merchant confirms that he can forward your Warrior
1D6x50gold.
artisans,traders and such.Unfortunately,that also means
and more spread out than villages, many more things can
ead ofevents and encounters. However,townsfolk can still
heir step and not upsetthelocals...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-15-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-16-fire" name="Fire">
    <rules>seeping out from underthefrontdoor.Rushinginsidetheydrag
outthe unconsciousinhabitants.Almostthe entire village turns</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-21-fight" name="Fight">
    <rules>Your Warrior is being congratulated as ahero,especiallyfrom
the surviving family who makea giftof 1D6x50 gold in thanks.
FIGHT
Your W arrior argues with a burly street trader who has tried to
charge them fartoo muchforsomecheap,shoddyitems.The
argument escalates to a brawl very quickly as the trader calls in
hisguards.Roll1D6 on the following table:
Your Warriorissoundlythrashedandloses2oogold.
1
2
Your Warrior is bested after a hard struggle against the
traderandhiscroniesandloses1oogold.
Your Warrior walks away withabloodynoseand50
3
gold worse off,butleavesthetraderbadlybruised.
4
Afterafiercestruggle,your Warrior knocks the
impudent trader to theground,wherehestays to
collecthisteeth.Whileheisbusy,yourWarriortakes
100 goldfrom his stall as compensation.
YourWarriorquicklydisarmsthetrader.Withasword
5
athisthroat,thelouthasno choice but to apologise
and offer your Warrior2oo gold as compensation.
6
A dozen evil looking thugs the trader's bodyguards
leapoutfrom theshadows,attackingyour Warrior with
knives,coshes and cudgels.Unperturbed,they coolly
dispatch them with afew well placed sword strokes,
emptiestheirpurses,andendsup3o0 gold better off.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-22-nightmare" name="Nightmare">
    <rules>As your Warrior retires for the evening they fallinto a deep
slumber.They beginto dream that they are fighting a terrifying
gorgon;herhaircomposedofvicioussnakesand agaze which
can turn a person to stone. with a horrendous scream the
gorgon attacks! Roll 1D6 to see how the dream ends:
1
No matter how many times or how hard your Warrior
strikes the creature with their weapon,the beast
seems invulnerable. With a terrifying scream the
gorgonshootsanarrowdirectlyinto theirheart!
WhenyourWarriorwakes,theyfindthat theyhave
permanentlylost1 Wound!Ifyour Warrior's Starting
Woundsiseverreducedtozerobecauseofthisdream,
theyare dead.
Tomorrow night the nightmare returns and they must
roll on this table again.Makeanote on your Adventure
Record Sheet to remind you.
2-5
The battle is brutal and neither your Warrior nor the
creature seems to gettheupperhand.Your Warrior
wakesina coldsweat.
Tomorrow night the nightmare returns and they must
rollonthistableagain!MakeanoteonyourAdventure
Record Sheet to remind you.
6
Your Warrior courageously stands their ground and
strikes the wretchedbeastdown!A sense of relief fills
your Warrior and they sleep better than they have in a
long time.
When your Warrior awakens they discover that they
are +1tohisStarting Wounds!Thenightmareends
and they do not have to roll on this table again (unless
theyencounterthisSettlementEventagain)!
If your Warrior leaves the Settlement before the dream
concludes, the nightmare temporarily ends. At the next
Settlement,however,it returns to haunt the Warrior again.
MakeanoteonyourAdventureRecordSheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-23-drugged" name="Drugged">
    <rules>Visiting a local hostelry in a rather seedy area, your W arrior
partakes of a curious drink offered them by the bartender.
Afterone swig,theyfeelthe effects of the liquid take hold-
they have been drugged! Roll1D6 on the following table:
Your Warriorhasbeenpoisonedandsuffers-1
1-3
Toughness for the duration of the next Adventure.
4-6
The liquid in question is simply very strong ale,and your
Warrior quickly getsatasteforit. The only ill effect is a
pounding head next morning.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-24-family-heirloom" name="Family Heirloom">
    <rules>An item of Treasure that your Warrior is carrying (determined
randomly)is identified by a wealthy,influential member of the
local citizenry ashisfamilyheirloom,stolenlastyearby wanton
burglars. The local Watch confiscates the item and you m ust
discard itim mediately.If your Warrior has no Treasure items,
the wealthy local accuses your Warrior of hiding it and demands
1D6x50 goldin restitutioninstead.Ifthey cannotpay,then your</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-25-accident" name="Accident">
    <rules>As your Warrior helps an old crone to cross the busy m ain
street,a beer wagon unexpectedly crashes into them. She
carefully peels them offtheheavy,iron-shed wheel,and takes
them to the infirmary to be patched up. Your Warrior cannot
buy anything or visit any Special Locations for 1D6 days while
theyrecover.Whiletheyarerecovering you do not have to roll</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-26-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-31-riotous-living" name="Riotous Living">
    <rules>Taken with the joys of hot food and a comfortable bed after so
long out in the wild,your Warrior overspends on such luxuries
by50gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-32-circus" name="Circus">
    <rules>Thereis a travelling circusintown,and your Warrior spends the
rest of their day wandering from sideshowtosideshow.Having
metthebeardedwomanand thetwo-headedgoat,theydecide
tohavetheirfortuneread.Perhapsthe sign above the doorto
that particular wagon should say Have your fortune stolen',as
for a costof2D6x10 gold,your Warrior is told nothing more
than that their destiny lies with a tall, dark stranger from
Erengrad!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-33-crime" name="Crime">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accused of murder and thrown in jail. The
matter is sorted out eventually, but only after your Warrior's
companions have bailed them out.Each Warrior in the party
except the accused m ustpay 1D6x10 gold to the authorities.
Iftheir companions do not have the money,your Warrior
m ust spend1D6 daysinjail. While in jail they don't have to pay</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-34-snake" name="Snake">
    <rules>As your warrior passes bya potter's store,a woman comes
running out hollering abouta poisonous snake that has slipped
in. She immediately hires your Warrior to rid hershop of the
snake,butshe warns them not to break any ofher pottery
which is on display throughout the shop.Roll1D6 below:
1
The snake is much harder to catch or kill than
anticipated and your Warrior practically tears the shop
apart before finallycorrallingthereptile.Angrily,the
shopownerdemands1D6x50goldforherloses.
2-3
JustasyourWarriorslipsthesnagintoaburlapsack,
they stumble backward into a rare and expensive pot
which falls to the ground with aloud crash.After
deducting theirpayforcatchingthesnake,yourWarrior
owesthepotter1D6x10goldforthedamage.
4-5
Stepping into the potter's shop your Warrior spies the
cold blooded creature coiled upin therafters.They
manageto bring it down along with afew cups hanging
onthe wall.Thepotteris elated and,afterdeductingfor
damage,paysyour Warrior1D6x10gold.
6
No sooner than your Warrior enters the shop do they
pounce upon the terrifying reptile,snatching it with
their bare hands.Whentheybringthe beastie back out,
the potter is elated that nothing wasdamaged.She
paysyour Warrior1D6x25 gold for their services.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-35-witchcraft" name="Witchcraft">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accused of witchcraft, and is chased through
the streets by an angry mob.Roll1D6 on the following table
(the Witch Hunter may add +1to theirscore):
1-3
Your Warrior escapes by jumping over the Settlement
wall and into the filthy water of the moat.Pelted with
eggsandrottenfruit,they stagger out onto thefar
rules (page 3).
4-5
Your Warriorducksdownasidealleyandescapes,but
from now on must wear a disguise when out in public!
Your Warrior turns angrily on the mob,demandingan
6
explanation.Shoutingdowntheleaderof the mob,they
establish their authority overthe crowd, who sheepishly
returnto theirhovels,pausingonlyto give your Warrior
1o0 gold as way of compensation.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-36-pet-dog" name="Pet Dog">
    <rules>Your Warrior is adopted by a smalldog.Itfollowsthem around
everywhere,skulkingin theshadows while the fighting goes on
and then emerging after the adventure is completed to shower
its new master with adoration.RollonthePetDogEventTable
(page 24) to see exactly which type of canine has attached
itselftoyou.
Your Warrior can kill the dog if you want,butit would bea
crueland heartless thing to doandit will cost them 1,ooo gold
to pay for a decent burial for thehound!
Ifyour Warrior already has a petdog,ignorethiseventand
roll on the Town Events table again.Ifnot,name it and note it
down on your Warrior's Adventure Record Sheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-41-fooled" name="Fooled">
    <rules>this Settlement,asit was a fake andis worth nothing!Ifyour
Warrior has not yet made any purchases in this Settlement,
treat this as an Uneventful Day.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-42-inheritance" name="Inheritance">
    <rules>Ahead villager approaches your Warrior and in forms them that
a distant relative has just passed away and has left them an
inheritance.Roll1D6toseewhattheinheritanceis:
1
The inheritance is a debt and the head villager has come
tocollect!Your Warrior mustforfeit1D6x50gold selling
Equipment and Treasure if necessary!
2-3
The inheritance is actuallyapetdog(seeEvent36).If
your Warrior already has apetdog,treatthisasa 1.
4
The inheritance is a small sum of money to the amount
of1D6x50 gold!
5
The inheritance is an item of Dungeon Room Treasure!
6
The inheritance is an item of Objective Room Treasure!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-43-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-44-steam-bath" name="Steam Bath">
    <rules>Your Warrior spends the rest of their day in the heady
atmosphere of a steam bath,sweating offthe aftereffects of
last night's sojourn at the tavern. They emerge feeling far
healthierthantheyhaveforagoodwhile,and theymayadd+1
Wound to their Starting Wounds score permanently.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-45-overturned-cart" name="Overturned Cart">
    <rules>Your Warrior hears a loud cry from for help from around the
cart has turned over andis crushingalocalboy.Your Warrior
runs overto try and push the cart off the young lad.Roll1D6
and add your Warrior's Strength then look up the result below:
6 or
Asyour Warriorliftsthecartuptheylosetheirgrip!
less
Thecartfallsbackonto theboy,maiminghim!The
boy's family demands restitution for the accident and
your Warrior m ust give up half their gold or besentto
prisonfor1D6 weeks!IfyourWarriorhasnogold,they
must give the family 1D3 TreasureItems(yourchoice)
instead.
7
Your Warrior manages to movethecart,buttheboyis
injuredin theprocess.YourWarriorfeelssoterrible
aboutthe situation that theygive1D6x50 goldto cover
thecost of medical treatment.
8-9
Your Warrior shifts the heavy cart enough for someone
to pull the boy out,thussaving hislife.Hisfather,a
localmerchant,isso grateful that he gives your Warrior
1D6x50gold.
10+
In aheroicfeat,your Warrior hauls the massive cartoff
theboyandheescapesunscathed.Theonlookers
cheer buoyantly and theboy'sfamily,who arerich
nobles,givesyourWarrior1D6x100goldandanItem
of Dungeon Room Treasure ingratitude!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-46-sword-for-sale" name="Sword For Sale">
    <rules>Strolling passed a bazaar your Warrior notices a young woman
who is selling agrandlookingsword.The woman claims that
theswordisafamilytreasure,handeddownfrom generation to
generation.Sheexplainsthatsheisimpoverishedand mustsell
it.Aninterested buyer is hovering overyour Warrior's shoulder
andhe tellsthe young woman that he will purchase it if your
Warrior doesn't.
The price the woman is asking is 1D6x1o0 gold and your
Warrior may buythe weapon if they wish bypaying the gold
and then rolling on the table below:
1
The sword functions as a regular sword from the
Weaponsmith,butitissopoorlyconstructedthat the
first time the Warriorrollsa1 To Hitin combat,the
blade shatters and must be discarded.
2
The sword functions as a regular sword from the
Weaponsmith,butisabitheavierandnotas well
balanced.Thus,the wieldersuffers-1Initiative when
wielding this sword in combat.
3
The sword is actually the Bronze Sigil Sword and gives
the wielder +2Initiative.
4
The sword is actually the Sword of Might and givesthe
wielder+1Strength.
5
The sword is actually the Blade of Leaping Copper and
givesthe wielder+1Attacks.
6
The sword is actually the Heart seekerS word and once
per Turn your Warrior may re roll anyone of their
Attacks that misses.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-51-beggars" name="Beggars">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accostedbybeggarsand,overwhelmed by the
sadnessof theirplight,giveseachof the1D6+4pitifulwretches
5
5 gold. If your Warrior cannot pay they are a beggar
themselves,andyou mustroll1D6 on the following table:
1
Your Warrior is thrown out of the Settlement see
TownEvent11.
2-6
YourWarriorgains1D6x10goldbybegging.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-52-troubadour" name="Troubadour">
    <rules>A colourfully-dressedbardnoticesyourWarriorastheypassby.
With an exasperated laugh he follows your Warrior,loudly
strum ming hislute and singing a ballad all about your Warrior's
exploits.Roll1D6:
1-2
The raucous tune is an insulting account of all of your
Warrior'sfollies;from their missteps in combatto
spilling their drink atthetavern.Thebardalso singsof
the unfortunate encounter with the miller's daughter
down by the river which angers some of her close male
relatives.They wait for your Warrior around a corner,
throw a sack over their head and beat them severely.
Your Warrior suffers-1Strengthforthe next
Adventure.
3-4
The ballad is all about your Warrior's exploits but noone
seemsto even notice or care.
5-6
The bard embellishes all of your Warrior's good deeds
and heroics to such degree that even your Warrior is
impressed with themselves.Alarge group quickly
gathersandgivesthreecheers!YourWarrior'sinner
spirit is bolstered and they are +1Strengthforthenext
Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-53-an-honest-day-s-work" name="An Honest Day's Work">
    <rules>Your Warrior is employed by a local apothecary to unload
suppliesathisshopfortheday.Thistask earns them 35 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-54-robbery" name="Robbery">
    <rules>Your Warrior bumps into a thief who hasjust robbed the
jeweller'sstore.Roll1D6 on the table below:
1
The culprit escapes as the shop owner emerges and
accuses your Warrior of thetheft!Heim mediate ly
summons the Watch who throw your Warrior in jail for
1D3daysandfinethem 1D6x100gold!
2-3
TherobberthrowssomejewelsatyourWarrior,yelling
Townsfolk come running out of the surroundings
buildings and surround yourWarrior,screamingforthe
Watch.Afterrepeatedpleasofinnocence,yourWarrior
isfined 1D6x50 goldforfailingtostopthecrime.
4-5
Your Warrior instinctively knocks the culprit down,
forcing him to drop allofhisloot.The nimble thief
manages to regain his feet and climb over a wall and
outofsight.Alocalwhowitnessedeverything
corroborates your story to the shopkeeper and the
Watch whentheyarrive.Theownerrewardsyour
Warrior with 1D6x25 gold for saving his merchandise.
6
Your Warriorgrabsthethief,slamshim to the floor and
sitson him untilthe Watch arrive.Theshopkeeperlauds
your Warrior as a hero and rewards them with1D6x50
gold!Inaddition,theyare given a bronze pendant with
an ancient rune offortuneinscribeduponit.Eachtime
your Warrior visitsa Settlement the pendant allows you
tore roll one SettlementEvent.You must accept the
result of the secondroll.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-55-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-56-hunting" name="Hunting">
    <rules>Your Warrior is invited by a group of locals togo on a nocturnal
hunt.
Meeting them just before sunset,they are informed that
tonight's prey is the great Qu arg a beast of fearsome temper
andfouldisposition.Your Warrior's task in the group is to take
thehuntingtools-anet,asmallpolewithabellonitandabag
fullof garlic and waitin the middle of the woods while the rest
of the hunters spread out into the forest and drive the Quarg
towardsthem.Asthesunrisesthenextmorning,and theowls
return to their nests, there is still no sign of the Quarg,your
Warrior begins to wonder if someone is being made afoolof...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-61-pickpocket" name="Pickpocket">
    <rules>As your Warrior rushes through the busystreets,theirmoney
pouch is stolen.
YourWarriorloses1D6x30gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-62-runaway" name="Runaway">
    <rules>While walking along the main street, your Warrior hears a
disturbance just around the corner.A moment later a huge
runaway bull charges down thestreet,wrecking market stalls
andcausingpanic.Your Warrior can let it pass by hiding down a
side alley, or try to stop the enraged animal.If your Warrior
hides down the alley and lets the bullpass,roll1D6 onthe
following table:
1-3
Your Warriorskulksin theshadows,waitingforthe
action todiedown.Astheypeep roundthecorner,a
mugger's metal bar hits them overthe head. Whenthey
regain consciousness,your Warrior's purse is 1oo gold
coins lighter.
After waiting nervously in the dark forafew minutes,
4-6
your Warrior sees the bull roar past and career off
downasidestreet.Thedangerispassedandyour
Warriormaycarryonabouttheirbusiness.
Ifyour Warrior tries to stop the bull,roll1D6 on the following
table:
1-2
Your Warrior waves the passers by aside and leaps out
infrontof thebull,sword drawn.Thebullhesitatesfor
half a second orso,and thentramplesthem into the
dirtbeforecarryingonitsway.Thecrowdthenstomps
all over your Warrior in the rush to follow thebull,
leaving them to nurse their injuries alonein an empty
street.
3-4
A single sword thrust stops the bull dead in its tracks
literally.Asits carcasstwitchesspasmodically,the
crowd roars in approval and showers your Warrior with
100gold.Thenthebull'senragedownerarrives,and
relieves them of150 gold-itwashisprizestud,and he
wanteditstopped,notslaughtered!
5-6
Your Warrior gives the bulla hard stare and its kids to a
halt,snorting andpawingtheground.Putting arope
arounditsneck,theyleaditback toitsstall.The crowd
cheers and showers them with150gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-63-jealous-adventurer" name="Jealous Adventurer">
    <rules>Unbeknownst to them, your Warrior is being watched and
followed bya young man. The stranger is a failed adventurer
and he longs for the fame and glory that your Warrior seems to
haveobtained.Hejealously decides to sabotage your Warrior's
achievements.
In the next Dungeon it becomes clear that someone has
alerted the denizens to the Warriors ' coming. Each time an
Unexpected Event occurs that reveals Monsters,you mustroll
1D6.On a score of 1-3 you must roll twice on the Monster Table
with the minimum amountof Monstersarriving.On ascoreof
4-6you rollonly once onthe Monster Table as normal,butthe
maximum numberof Monsters arrive.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-64-join-the-watch" name="Join The Watch">
    <rules>The Captain of the Watch marks your Warrior as a useful
looking recruit and,ashe is short on manpower,press gangs
them fora week.Your Warrior can either try to escape the
Watch by making a donation to their funds of 2D6x10 gold,or
join up.
If your Warrior joins up they do not have to pay Living
Expenses for the weekandearns2ogoldin wages.However,
while in the Watch they have no time to visit any traders or
Special Locations.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-65-salesman" name="Salesman">
    <rules>A salesman has set up shop just outside an inn selling Holy
Water.He offers it to your Warrior claiming thatit will protect
themfrom evilspiritsandcanevendestroytheundead.
You m ay buy up to 1D6 Holy Water vials at the cost of
1D6x50 gold each. After purchasing the vials,the salesman
takes downhis wares and disappears into theinn.Nowrollfor
each holy watervialpurchased.Onascore of1 or2,the vialis
filled with simple drinking water and is useless.
On any other score,the vial actually does contain a magical
holy water, purified and blessed by a priest.If drunk, the
imbibe r is protected by a magical aura which lasts for one Turn
and all attacks against the drinker made by Undead Monsters
do half the normalDamage(rounded down).If thrown atan
Undead Monster rollon your Ballistic Skill,each successful hit
causing1D6 Wounds with no deductions for anything.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-town-66-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-11-thrown-out" name="Thrown Out">
    <rules>Your Warrior's wild behaviour attracts the attention of the
Settlement authorities and there are thrown outoftown.They
must wait outside the Settlement gates for the other Warriors.
In addition,roll1D6.On a score of1 your Warrior is fleeced
by the gate guards asthey are thrown outand have alltheir
gold stolen!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-12-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-13-investment" name="Investment">
    <rules>In one of the wharf side bars, your Warrior meets a young
entrepreneur with great ideas for establishing a trading empire
tocover the Known World.Hetalksyour Warrior into investing
1D6x5o gold per Battle-level, giving them a certificate of
purchase.
From now on,atthe end of the Dungeon,wheneveryour
Warrior reaches civilisation,they may visit the local Merchant's
Guild andshow them theirdeedofpartnership(thistakesone
day). Consulting their records,they can tellyour Warrior how
the companyisdoing.Roll1D6 on the following table:
1
Thecompanyhasgonebust,andyourWarrior's
investment is worthnothing.In addition,they mustpay
the merchants1D6x50goldperBattle-levelin
outstanding debts.
2-5
Your Warrior's investment is performing fairly well and
the merchant forward them 1D6x10goldperBattle-
level as their share of the profits.
Businessisbooming!Afterconsultingtheledger,the
6
merchant confirms that he can forward your Warrior
1D6x50 goldperBattle-level.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-14-pet-dog" name="Pet Dog">
    <rules>Your Warriorisadoptedbyasmalldog.Itfollowsthem around
everywhere,skulkingin theshadows while the fighting goes on
and then emerging after the adventure is completed to shower
its new master with adoration.Rollonthe Pet Dog Event Table
(page 24) to see exactly which type of canine has attached
itself to you.
Your Warrior can killthe dogifyou want,butitwouldbe a
cruel and heartless thing to doandit will cost them 1,ooo gold
topayforadecentburialforthehound!
Ifyour Warrior already hasapetdog,ignore this event and
roll again on the City Events table.Ifnot, name it and noteit
downon your Warrior's Adventure Record Sheet.
18
llfind a whole array ofthings to do! There willbe more
more chances of something great happening butalso more
a in ment and more people to meet.A crow dedcity willalso
t m ore...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-15-cutpurse" name="Cutpurse">
    <rules>As your Warrior rushes through the busy streets, their money
pouch is stolen.
YourWarriorloses1D6x50gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-16-bathhouse" name="Bathhouse">
    <rules>Your Warrior spends the rest of their day in the heady
atm o sphere of a steam bath,sweating off the aftereffects of
last night's sojourn at the tavern. They emerge feeling far
healthierthantheyhaveforagoodwhile,and theymayadd+1
Wound to their Starting Wounds scorepermanently.Inaddition,
they are +1Initiativeforthe next Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-21-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-22-an-honest-day-s-work" name="An Honest Day's Work?">
    <rules>Your Warrior encounters a nervous looking merchant who is in a
bitofa bind and asksforhelp.Someofhis workers have failed
toshow up for work and he has a lot of crates that need to be
transported to the warehouse district. Roll 1D6 on the table
below:
1
The crates contain stolen goods and the Watch has had
themerchantundersuspicionforsometime.Theentire
group, including your Warrior, is arrested. Your Warrior
mustspendthenext2 days in jail during which they are
cleared of any wrong doing.Unfortunately,they fail to
getpaid.
2-3
Your Warrior does not realise that the crates are filled
with illegal substances and is surprised when the Watch
arrives to arrest the merchant.Obviously,your Warrior
receives no pay.
4-5
Your Warrior works diligently andis paid 50 goldfor a
hard day's work.
6
Your Warrior's efforts are exemplary and the task
earns them 1oo gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-23-riotous-living" name="Riotous Living">
    <rules>Taken with the joys of hot food and a comfortable bed after so
long outin the wild,your Warrior overspends on such luxuries
by 50 gold.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-24-hunting" name="Hunting">
    <rules>Your Warrior is invited by a group of locals to goon a nocturnal
hunt.
Meeting them just before sunset,they are informed that
tonight's prey is the great Qu arg a beast of fearsome temper
andfouldisposition.Your Warrior's task in the group is to take
thehuntingtools-anet,asmallpolewithabellonitandabag
full of garlic and wait in the middle of the woods while the rest
of the hunters spread out into the forest and drivethe Quarg
towardsthem.Asthesunrisesthenextmorning,and theowls
return to their nests, there is stillno sign of the Quarg,your
Warrior begins to wonder if someone is being made afoolof...</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-25-street-artists" name="Street Artists">
    <rules>Your Warrior is captivated by a particular brilliant team of
street artists, who are performing their own rendition of a
popular and contemporary play.
The play your Warrior is watching iscalled (rollonce on each
of thetablesbelow):
1D6
Result
1
Death of...
The Lost Love of...
2
A Return To...
3
4
No Solace For...
Cursed Be...
5
6
Drunken As...
1D6
Result
1
...theEmperor.
...aLove Struck Wastrel!
2
3
...Solitude.
...the Creeping Dead.
4
5
...the Sylvan ian Counts.
...the Ever hungry Halfling!
6
Rollanother1D6toseehow good the actors were:
1
Appalling! Your Warrior has never seen such rubbish in
their life and pelts the unfortunate actors with rotten
vegetables!
2-5
Entertaining! Your Warrior gives the actors 10 gold x
the total of the numbers rolled on the tables above.
6
Splendid! Your Warrior is captivated and showers the
actors with well-earnedpraiseandalotofgoldtoo!
Your Warrior gives the actors5o gold xthe numbers
rolled on the tables above.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-26-counterfeit" name="Counterfeit">
    <rules>As your Warrior attempts to buy someequipment,the trader
points out their gold is counterfeit and refuses to take it.
Looking through their stash, your Warrior discovers that
1D6x10 of their gold is indeed worthless. Discard it and crossit
off your Adventure Record Sheet.
Ifyour Warrior does nothavethatmuchgoldleft,andhas
already spent some in theSettlement,they must leave forthe
nextDungeonimmediatelybeforeanyonecatcheson.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-31-false-accusation" name="False Accusation">
    <rules>Studying the weapons on display in the local smithy, your
Warrior feels a steel gauntlet ed hand upon their shoulder.Itis
the Marshal of the Watch and your Warrior is accused ofacrime
they did not com mit!
Your Warrior is arrested and thrown uponthe mercy of the
courts. Your Warrior must roll once on each table below to see
what crime they are accused ofand what their sentence is.
1D6
Crime
1
Trouble making
2
Robbery
3
Forgery
4
Arson
Treachery
5
6
Murder
Sentence
1D6
1
Innocent
A stern warning!
2
3
1000 gold fine
Lose a limb*
4
10 years in jail**
5
Deathby(rollontheExecution MethodTable)
6
1D6
Execution Method
1
Burning
2
Beheading
3
Impalement
Drowning
4
5
Torture
6
Firing Squad
*Lose a Limb
The authorities decide to chop offone ofyour Warrior's limbs as
punishment. You may choose which.If theylose aleg,your
Warrior's Movement is halved and their Escape from Pinning roll
is always a 6+.Ifthey everlose another leg they maynot move
atall. If they lose a hand,thentheyare-2 onallTo Hit rolls and
they may neveruse missile weaponsorcastspells.Iftheyever
lose another hand they may not fight at all.
**10YearsinJail
This effectively means your Warrior is out of the game (as
indeed does ' sentenced to death by...'.However,atthe start
of every Adventure from now on,roll1D6.Onascoreof5or6
your Warrior escapes,together with all their gear, and may
rejoin their fellow Warriors.
Buying Your Freedom
Ifthe sentence is a 4,5 or 6,the arrested Warrior(and other
Warriors) can bribe the guards and the court officials in orderto
avoidharm.Thecostofthis will be found by adding together all
of the dice rolls from the Crime/Sentence/Execution Method
tablesandmultiplyingtheresultby1oo.Thatishow muchgold
it will cost for your Warrior to w alkfree,unharmed.
19</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-32-wrestler" name="Wrestler">
    <rules>"The Slammer" has come to town and he is taking on all
challengers in a 'friendly' wrestling match! Boasting a perfect
record,theNorseman wagers5oogoldpiecestoanyonein the
crowd who defeats him in unarmed combat. At the urgingof
the crowd your Warrior accepts the challenge,roll2D6 and
apply their Alehouse modifier (see your Warrior's Rulebook).
Look uptheresultonthetablebelow:
2-3
In the first few seconds,TheSlammerpicksyour
Warrior up and promptly smashes them to the ground.
The sickening thud ofyour Warrior hitting the ground
sendsashudderthroughthecrowd.Momentslater
your Warrioriscartedoffonawoodenplank.Notonly
isyour Warrior5o0gold pieceslighter,butThe
Slam mer helps himself to oneitem of Treasure
(determined atrandom)your Warrior was carrying.
4-5
Aftera nifty maneuver,The Slam mergrabs your
Warrior in a bear hug that feels like they're being
squeezed by...well,abear. With eyes bulging your
Warrior gives up just prior to slipping into
unconsciousness. With terribly bruised ribs and an even
more bruised ego yourWarriorforfeits5o0gold.
6-8
After a grueling 15 minutes of dirt eating exchanges
between The Slam mer and your Warrior,the matchis
calleda draw.Your Warrior gains nothing butthe
knowledge that they lasted longer than most and has
lost nothing morethan afew teeth...
+6
With all the focused fury of a hungry Half ling in apie
shop your Warrior meets The Slam merheadon.After
several minutes of intense combat your Warrior takes
the measure of his foe and slams the Norseman to the
ground!Standingtriumphantamidstacheeringcrowd,
your Warrior dusts off their clothing before marching off
with 5o0 moregold pieces in their pocket.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-33-uneventful-day" name="Uneventful Day">
    <rules>Uneventful day. No special effects.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-34-robbery" name="Robbery">
    <rules>Your Warrior bumps into a thief who hasjust robbed the
jeweller's store.Roll1D6 on the table below:
1
The culprit escapes as the shop owner emerges and
accuses your Warrior of the theft!Heim mediate ly
summons the Watch who throw your Warrior in jail for
1D3 days and fine them 1D6x100 gold!
2-3
The robber throws some jewels at your Warrior,yelling
"Thief!Thief!" and then escapes down a dark alley.
Townsfolk come running out of the surroundings
buildings and surround your Warrior,screamingforthe
Watch.Afterrepeated pleasofinnocence,yourWarrior
isfined 1D6x50 gold for failing to stop the crime.
4-5
Your Warrior instinctively knocks the culprit down,
forcing him to drop allofhisloot.Theynimblethief
manages to regain his feet and climb over a walland
outofsight.Alocalwho witnessed everything
corroborates your story to the shopkeeper and the
Watch whenthey arrive.The owner rewards your
Warrior with 1D6x25 gold for saving his merchandise.
6
YourWarriorgrabsthethief,slamminghimto thefloor
and sitson him until the Watch arrive.Theshopkeeper
lauds your Warrior as a hero and rewards them with
1D6x50gold!Inaddition,theyare given abronze
pendant with an ancient rune of fortune inscribed upon
it.Eachtimeyour Warrior visits a Settlement the
pendantallowsyoutore-rolloneSettlementEvent.You
m ust accept the result of the second roll.
20</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-35-troubadour" name="Troubadour">
    <rules>A colourfully-dressedbardnoticesyourWarriorastheypassby.
With an exasperated laugh he follows your Warrior,loudly
s
exploits.Roll 1D6:
1-2
The raucous tune is an insulting account of all of your
Warrior'sfollies;from their missteps in combatto
spilling their drink atthetavern.The bard also sings of
the unfortunate encounter with the miller's daughter
down by the river which angers some of her close male
relatives.They waitfor your Warrior around a corner,
throw a sack over their head and beat them severely.
Your Warriorsuffers-1 Strength forthe next
Adventure.
3-4
The ballad is all about your Warrior's exploits but noone
seemsto even notice or care.
5-6
Thebard embellishes all of your Warrior's good deeds
and heroics to such degree that even your Warrior is
impressed with themselves.Alarge group quickly
gathers and gives three cheers!Your Warrior's spirit is
bolstered and gains +1Strengthforthenext
Adventure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-36-tax-collector" name="Tax Collector">
    <rules>As your Warrior strolls about the civic district they are
approached by a city employee who demands payment for the
new ' Adventurer's Tax ' which amountsto10goldperTreasure
item that they arecarrying.Your Warrior must either pay orthe
local Watch will remove them from the City im m ediately (see</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-41-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-42-con-artist" name="Con Artist">
    <rules>Mungo and his Amazing Monkeys are performing in the street
and your Warrior laughs heartily as the creatures leap on to their
back and scurry around theirlegs.Flipping a gold coin to the
trainer your Warrior leaves the area.Aboutanhourlateryour
Warrior realizes that they are missing one item of Treasure
(determinedatrandom)!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-43-old-friend" name="Old Friend">
    <rules>Someone across the street shouts out your Warrior'sname.Itis
along lost friend and fellow Warrior who insists on taking your
Warriortoeveryinnandalehouseheknowsin thevicinity.
Your Warrior must roll on the Alehouse Events Table (ifusing
theNew AlehouseEventsTable,the SophisticationValueisa2)
1D6 times,deducting a cumulative -1 from the score each
successivevisit,astheybecome moreand more inebriated.
At the end of the merry-making, your Warrior goes their
separate way, leaving their old friend unconscious in a
wharf sidebar of ill repute.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-44-good-deed" name="Good Deed">
    <rules>your Warriorgoesoutonthetown,taking 1D6x20 gold with
them.As they cross the street,they spotan old cronein an
upstairs window shouting that robbers have broken into her
attic room and are stealing her few possessions.Happy to
assist the helpless,your Warrior bounds up the rickety stairsto
herroom three at atime.As they enter herdimlylitroom,a
blackbagisplacedovertheirhead,swiftlyfollowedbyaheavy
ironbar.Theyawakenin thegutterseveralhourslater,nursing
a sore head.Not surprisingly,the gold they wer carrying is all
gone.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-45-beggars" name="Beggars">
    <rules>Your Warriorisaccostedbybeggarsand,overwhelmed by the
sadness of theirplight,gives eachof the2D6+2 pitiful wretches
5 gold. If your Warrior cannot pay they are a beggar
themselves,andyou mustroll1D6 on the following table:
Your Warrior is thro wn outof the Settlem ent-see City
1
Event11.
2-6
YourWarriorgains1D6x15goldbybegging.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-46-relative" name="Relative">
    <rules>An old woman bumps into your Warrior on the city street.She
explodes in excitement at the sight of their face and claims they
areherdistantrelative.Beforetheycansaya word,theexcited
lady drags your Warrior home with her where they are
welcomed by allthe family members and fed to their heart's
content.Your Warrior graciouslyacceptstheirhospitality,which
includesapackageoffoodupontheirdeparture.
Your Warrior does not have to pay living expenses for this
Sheet.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-51-criminal" name="Criminal">
    <rules>Your Warrior is minding theirown business when a criminal in
custody of the Watchpassesby.Theprisonergivesanodanda
smileto your Warrior and the captain of the guards notices.
Roll1D6 on the table below:
1-3
Youarearrestedforcomplicity.Your Warrior spends
thenext1D3 days in the local jail during which they are
interrogated by the authorities. They are finally
released with afine of1D6x5 gold for loitering.
4-6
One of the guards stops your Warrior for questioning as
theother guardslookon.Thecriminaltakesthe
opportunitytotryandbreakfree.Rollanother1D6.
1-3
The criminal manages to eludethe
authorities and they are convinced that you
werepurposelytryingtodistracttheguards.
Youspendthenext1D3daysinjailuntil
you're finally released due to lack of
evidence.
4-6
As the prisoner makes a break forit,your
Warrior frees him selffrom the bewildered
guard,leapsoveravegetablestand,and
apprehendsthecriminal.Dragginghim back
to the Watch commander your Warrior
collects1D6x25goldasareward.The
prisoner glares at your Warrior as they are
marched away.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-52-parade" name="Parade">
    <rules>Alarge procession of citizens is marching down the avenue
encouragingallonlookerstojoin them.Feelingin ajovialmood,
your Warriordecidestojoin theparade.Roll1D6 on the table
below:
1-2
The procession is a political activist group that is
protestingthelocalauthorities.Allof the
demonstrators,including your Warrior,are arrested by
the Watch.Theyspendthenext1D3daysinjailand
mustpay 1D6x20 goldinfines.
3-4
The procession is a victory march celebrating the most
recentdefeatofOrcs&amp; Goblinsin thearea.Thegroup
marches to the city centre where a decorated
commandergivesatriumphantspeech.YourWarrior
mayadd+1to theirWillpowerforthenextAdventure!
5-6
The citizens are worshippers of the new temple whoare
trying to recruit members. The procession makesits
way to the temple where all of the worshippers,
including your Warrior,are blessed by the head priest.
Your Warrior is +1Luck for the next Adventure!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-53-accident" name="Accident">
    <rules>As your Warrior helps an old crone to cross the busy main
street,a beer wagon unexpectedly crashes into them. She
carefully peels them offthe heavy,iron-shed wheel,andtakes
them to the infirmary to be patched up.Your Warrior cannot
buy anything or visit any Special Locations for 1D6 days while</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-54-city-watch" name="City Watch">
    <rules>Your Warrior is accosted by the City Watch who has been
warned that a Warrior bearing powerful and destructive magic
items is on the prowl.
Your Warrior mustroll1D6foreachitem of Treasure they
arecarrying.Onascore 1 the Watch confiscate and it must be
discarded im mediately.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-55-street-urchin" name="Street Urchin">
    <rules>Your Warrior is approached by a street urchin who offers to
guard their mountfor 10 gold pieces a day.If your Warrior pays
the urchin, you may rolltwo dice instead of one when
determining if your Warrior's horse has been stolen and may
choose the higher one. If your Warrior does not have that
amount or decides not to pay the urchin,then treat this as an
Uneventful Day.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-56-salesman" name="Salesman">
    <rules>An extremely persuasive salesman is making a pitch toalarge
crowd.Roll1D6andaddyourWarrior's Willpower:
2-4
YourWarriorpays1D6x1o0 gold for a pair of boots
yourfeetsmell..."
5-7
Your Warrior purchases a one year subscription to
Adventurer's Monthlyfor1D6x50gold.This manuscript
contains everything one needs to know about slaying
monsters and keeping their gear in pristine condition!
The manuscript willbe deliveredevery3o days directly
toyour Warrior's doorstep!
8+
Your Warrior resists the great temptation to buy Super
Belt,the all purpose survival kit that will hold the most
important items one should carry in the wild including
coins,abeermug,arope,rations,aknife,alargesack
and aQua rg horn.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-61-duel" name="Duel">
    <rules>Your Warrior is challenged to a duelby a professional duelist
whom they insulted in atavern.The duelis scheduled to take
place atdawn tomorrow.
Your Warrior can either leave town im mediate ly or take up
the challenge.
If your Warrior takes part in the duel,roll 1D6 on the
following table:
1
With asingle, well placed sword thrust your Warrior's
heartisspearedand theyfallto theground,quitedead.
2-4
Thetwo duelistsfightforhourafterhour,eachinflicting
manylightwoundsontheother.Eventuallythe sun
goesdownand thefightisdeclaredadraw.The duelist
congratulates your Warrior on their swordsman ship,
and offers them a fines upper and the best wine at the
most expensive hotel in the Settlement.
5-6
After a few minutes,your Warrior realizes that they
have the better of the duellistanddespatcheshim.On
his body they find jewels worth2D6x50 gold anda
single item of Dungeon Room Treasure.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-62-an-adventure" name="An Adventure!">
    <rules>See The Ultimate Adventure Book to determine what exploit the Warriors might participate in next!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-63-riot" name="Riot">
    <rules>The lowly inhabitants outside the Settlement are fed up with
their impoverished situation.A small gathering has erupted into
a dangerous riot pitting the peasants against the local Watch.
Your Warrior chooses to help restrain the peasants and must
roll2D6onthetable below:
2
An angry horde of peasants overpowers your Warrior
and theybeatthemintoabloodypulp.Theyaredead
and must be removed from game.
3-5
Your Warrior is overrun by vagabonds who beat them
senseless.They spendthenext1D6daysin the
infirmary and mustpay1D6x50goldfortreatment.
6-9
Your Warrior helps the Watch beat back the miscreants
and is paid 1D6x25 gold in wages.
10+
Your Warrior helps crush the riot quickly and efficiently.
A high official is extremely impressed and pleased by
your Warrior'sactions.Hepaysthem 1D6x50 goldand
gives them oneitem of Dungeon Room Treasure!</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-64-trader" name="Trader">
    <rules>A shrewd trader convinces your Warrior to swap anitem of
Treasure(determinedatrandom)foroneofhis. Make one roll
onthe Dungeon Room Treasure Tableto see whatitem the
traderis giving youin exchange.Ifthe gold value of the trader's
item is m ore than the gold value of the Warrior's item,the
Traderisnothappy.Rollanother1D6 andif the result is a 1,
the Trader declares that you were being deceptive in the trade
and summons the Watch who declare that both items must be
returned to their original owners.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-65-reward" name="Reward">
    <rules>Your Warrior sees a poster warning that a well known murderer
isreputedtobein thearea,andoffersarewardforhiscapture.
The criminal in question is described as very tall, wearing a
black cloak and hat,and having an Erengrad accent. Upon
reading this, your Warrior realises that the description exactly
fits a character they bumped into earlier,and rushing back,
manages to apprehend the villain just as he dragsa gagged
merchant into a dark alley.Roll1D6 on the following table:
1
The murdererlaughs,slitsthemerchant'sthroat,
throws the knife at your Warrior's feet andflees,
shouting"Help,murder! Soonyour Warrior is</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
  <event id="lm-city-66-assassin" name="Assassin">
    <rules>(and1D6x50)goldcoinspersuadethem that they are
innocent.
Your Warrior savesthe m erchant'slife,for which he
2-5
gives them 20gold,butthemurdererslipsawayinto
thegloom.
Your Warrior frees the merchant and captures the
6
murderer,forwhichtheyareproclaimedaheroand
given1o0 goldreward.
ASSASSIN
As your Warrior passes byan alleyway they catch sightofa
figure lurking in the darkness. They instinctively draw their
weaponjustasthefigurepouncesonthem!Roll1D6 andadd
your Warrior's Initiative:
2-4
Your Warrior is severely wounded!Roll1D6 andifthe
resultisa1,yourWarriorcannotbesavedand
perishes.OnanyotherscoreyourWarriorisfoundby
a passerby who rushes them to the infirmary where
they are treated for their grievous wounds.They
spendthenext1D6daysinbedand mustdeduct1
Wound permanently from their Starting Woundsscore.
Your Warrior suffers a serious wound as they fend off
5-7
theattacker,whoquicklydisappearsdownthe
alleyway.Your Warriormustspendthenext1D3days
in theinfirmary,paying 1D6x20 gold for treatm ent as
well as Living Expenses.
8-10
Your Warrior defends himself against the assailant but
the attacker manages to escape.
11+
Your Warrior deals a prompt and fatal blow to the
villain.Upon searching the Assassin's body your
Warrior finds oneItem of Dungeon Room Treasure on
hisperson,butnoclueastowhohewasorwhyhe
was trying to killyour Warrior.</rules>
    <treasure>false</treasure>
  </event>
</events>
